All right, welcome to 2025. I was going
to say happy Monday, but it's obviously a
Thursday, even though it may feel like a
weekend. Hope everybody had a really nice
New Year's Eve celebration. And again,
obviously, as Brandon said, he's glad to
be back. So thanks for everybody. Yes,
and well wishes there as well.
We're going to just do some
Q&A and 1st question is asking
about PST G and looking at
the base comparing to Shacks base.
Let's see, want to get better
at under at. Identifying quality bases, I
feel Shack was more tight throughout the
formation versus PSG, which seemed too
wide and loose. Am I getting more or
less, I guess just asking if they're
seeing that correctly. The first thing
you know, listen, I don't even look at
the base generally until I look at the
right side. So if my eye just if we're
talking about screening and looking at
bases. And that that kind of stuff, I
just look at this right side. So if I've
never seen this chart before, this is
where my eye goes right here, just kind
of right in here. And if if it doesn't
look even imminently purchasable or
viable, generally I just on to the next
one. And you know, this is it looks
relatively interesting. So I might and,
and you're right, you got a decent size.
Place here then I look left for supply
and other things you know from there and
see what is the overall chart look like
I'll look down at the fundamentals I'm
just you know giving you a very sort of
what's the first thing and then where we
go from there so looking at this base and
I'll look at the weekly as well you know
this is a decent sized correction here
and then. As you come back up the right
hand side, you've got good volume coming
in. Obviously this is a response to
earnings. Now. I just want to see can we
get some type of a tightening over here?
It's it's trying, it's a little bit short
and a little bit, you know, you know,
leaking off a little. I don't know much
about this one particularly
fundamentally, I think we traded this
maybe you know, a year ago or so Brandon,
when it was set up. Memory serves me
correct had this on focus. You know, well
in the past, you know our the RSRP are a
little bit low. So you know, All in all,
it's just not ready. That's that would be
my short take now comparing it to
something like Shaq. Yeah,
this was, we were starting to watch this,
you know, right as this was putting in
this area here using a little bit of an
iMac, you know, of our imagination
saying, you know, if this is coming in on
schedule. I think we were sort of looking
at it, you know, this day right here and
then it gapped and even, you know, on
this right hand side we were expecting it
poked its head out. We kind of got, you
know, chopped around a little bit in
shack if you were too tight and same
happened with the MSP tried again here
and then, you know, really got going
after the earnings. This even here, you
know, it's on focus for reason. This is
acceptable and potentially, you know, a
follow up by point here today. But you
know, I think your overall analysis is
you know. Correct. This, this is this
might be where you could say in, in a
situation like this, this is exactly
maybe where we are on the PSG, it's just
a little sloppier where you, you stick it
on a secondary watch list. I'd love to
see this if this could tighten up, you
know, into this level or even into this
level, you know, you could be really
aggressive in a better market. Might try
and pick it coming off this low, but it's
just not necessary in my opinion. So and
because it's a little bit in a lower Rs,
that's where I I want to see it look a
little bit better in terms of the radiant
side. Um, Suleiman's
asking opinion on Pam.
Yeah, I don't know. This is an ADR, don't
know much about this one is what's sort
of in that. Yeah, that electric power
group that's continuing to stay strong.
Look, it's just short. This is really
short here. You know, could you, could
you have tried this coming right through
here? Well, I like that it's tight at
least. And if you're going to play a high
Rs name that just extended and really
short, I want to do it. We're really
tight area. But yeah, I mean given
where we are and the action subsequently
that we've been seeing, this is just
a little too aggressive right now.
Similar with, you know, BRBROS is in
one small, I have a really small
position in this. Bought right
here and this is a good example of that
power play esque kind of theme that we're
seeing. And this is a name that I know a
decent amount fundamentally that I
wouldn't mind owning. So was willing to
take a small position. I'd love to see we
could get just a couple day tightening
over here rather than just blasting off.
That's what I'd be looking for. To really
get heavy or add, you know, more of the
potential name again, environments, not
the best, but if you're going to try a
name, you know, these power play ask
names are are definitely the the place to
be trafficking in my opinion, say versus
that something like PSG and much prefer,
you know, go out that you know, high
alpha, low standard deviations where I
want to be. I just can't.
I can market too. Like if you look at
the volume on Bros, there's like no
selling. So it's had this big nice move
on volume coming in as it's rallying, but
look very little selling even as the
markets come under pressure. So like
that's kind of like stands out to us.
Yeah. The other thing that. Just to, you
know, keep in mind because somebody would
say, well, why do you buy this one or why
would you even put on a position here not
another name. Well, I do. We do know a
little bit about the fundamentals. They
have decent fundamentals on the table. I
know something about this company. It's
this is really looking and if you might
be easier to see on the monthly this is.
Something Mark taught me a long time ago,
whenever you see a stock goes public late
in the prior cycle, the stock went public
late in 2021, right near the peak. And
then and then if it's able to come back,
we never really had a viable base over
here. So you could make a pretty decent
argument if this sets up and tightens up,
this is really the first viable. Base of
you know, what's a, what's a newer within
the last few years IPO issue and that's
where sometimes your biggest winners come
from. These are, you know, those primary
bases are that, that magnitude type play
and it's in an area that again, I
know a little bit about consumer retail
again somewhere that you're bigger
winners. Come from so it's it's worth
having on the radar so that that would at
least get, you know, me to say I'm
willing to at least put on a little in
that way if it just blasts off, at least
you have a small position rather than
none at all. The other one he was asking
about was Brinker.
You know, again, just.
Really strong we we were highlighting
this this was your buy point you know you
had one here and here I can't remember
exactly what day in terms of the platform
he recommended this obviously we sold
into this move and this would have been a
great one to potentially play a portion
of for a bigger move and using that you
know 50 day break even or better now it's
just. It's just gotten really extended in
the short run and there's really no pivot
here.
Mode asking about LRN.
Took a half position today. Thoughts.
If you're buying today, my question would
have been why didn't you at least start?
Maybe this day. Which
is I think we highlighted this Mark and I
did in real time on Monday saying, you
know, it's a little short and maybe you
gave it another day or two and use this
subsequent you're trading through this
high similar scenario in terms of the
action on focus. This is this acceptable?
Absolutely. Is it tradable? Sure. And
this is 1 even in my own. Mind saying
OK, I'm a good example for me of a pitch
I'm willing to take right now and a good
in? In a good market or good environment,
I'd be all over a name like this.
We just haven't seen a ton of follow
through. So this is where if you trade a
name like this, you start with a smaller
position and then see maybe do we get
another pivot?Or do
we get the cheat you're you're really
just trading through the low cheat here.
It's a little sloppy, but again, it's
tight enough. Now if it could set up and
show a little more symmetry or maybe we
get even. I do like obviously some of
this is holidays, but to Brandon's point
from Bros, you see that similar action
here. Power play ask really. Strong move,
very little selling. So that that's
that's constructive action. And if this
can get going, let's say this is where
too. OK, maybe you missed this name
blasts off, but this it really gets
going. That's where I'm willing to take a
pitch or to in a in an acceptable setup
to give me, you know, confidence that
things are starting to work or you start
with the smaller positions. You get some
traction and that's when you look to, you
know, start getting a little bit more
aggressive. So I think I think it's not a
bad, bad spot. If you're gonna be trading
off focus, this is where you want to be,
you know, looking as it's tight, it's
mid, it's mid, single digit and
acceptable.
Chris is saying he was reviewing trade
he did in doc you.
Coming off the 12th 2020 lows, OK, do
you think 3 let's let's go back here.
I was going to say this is not really met
the criteria for quite a while.
Change this to maybe something
like that.
3/3/2020 was too early to buy. Let's go
back just a little bit more. Sorry here,
but adjust the chart.
I think he's looking at 3:30, right?
3:30, I'm sorry. Yeah.
Right here.
Well, you had a little pullback by um, I
had a tiny position, sold half the next
day, got stopped out of the rest and
four, three didn't get back in and 4/13,
which was probably the correct buy was
jumpy at the time. In hindsight, it was a
big missed opportunity. Well, your first
comment there in hindsight, there's
always going to be big missed
opportunities. So you want to be careful
that you don't just Monday morning
quarterback. Looking at this in a vacuum,
and I remember this very well because
this is a name I wanted to get on as well
and wasn't actually able to. It was just
a little sloppy. Keep in mind too, we had
a market that was insanely volatile.
Following that, for those who weren't
familiar, this, this was the up here. You
can see it. Here's your COVID decline.
Now this stock. And when the rest
of the names were getting absolutely
killed, was really able to quickly
recover it's 50, which is pretty
remarkable now given the fact that we
stay at home and DocuSign names like docu
and Zoom, they were really the first ones
sort of back out of the gate. But did we
really get a crisp right hand side even
here to your point?Undercut here. You
know this this pullback 98 down to I'm
always measuring, I'm always looking even
in even if I am going to play Monday
morning quarterback to go well. Would
this have been too big to for me to
hang on? The answer is absolutely. This
is just too much volatility. There's
there's almost no world where if I'd even
bought this through this little pullback.
And even derisked into here where I, I
likely would have held the entire, well,
certainly not the entire position,
probably any of the position because I
just, I'm always asking myself, is this
too much? And this is a huge pullback. So
then you know, what was your next spot or
you know, really right here. And I know
there were a number of folks who wanted
to own. If you're really disciplined,
this is where you just gotta be willing
to let certain pitches go, and this is an
example of that.
So yeah, OK, Yep. Thanks for the well
wishes into the new year.
Suleiman is saying I marked my stop
is always 2.8% but I always get
stopped out. Should I widen my stop
and cut position size back up?
There's a good one for you to to jump
in on as well, Brandon, But first
question I would ask is where are you
getting why 2.8%?I don't
know where that there's, there's nowhere
in any of marks materials are teaching or
anything we say here where you say you
need to have a 2.80% stop. And in
fact, that's going to be often too tight
for a lot of setups. This is where
you want, you want that your stop.
To get you out when either the stock
isn't doing what you expected and that
would be the tightest case scenario for
me. So I'm going to use a tight stop.
It's because I have a very good feel or
expectation based upon experience, how my
trading is going or how much risk I'm
willing to take, and that usually would
coincide. Maybe with the low of the last
few days could even be intraday low.
Listen to stop anywhere less than 3%,
it's tight. So you want to know that your
timing is that the tighter you go, the
better your timing's got to be. Well, so
I would never just blankly say
everything's too 2.8% to any number
because I want. I
want the the stop to be hit when the
trade starts to sour and you know 2 or
3% is often not enough. Again, unless
your timing is really good or a yearly
short term trader Brandon, you want to
add was just going to say like listen, we
need we need more information than just
this. Your stop is. 2.8% you always get
stopped out when you say always, that
means that me that you're getting tagged
on everything. To Mark's point, like, you
know, we, we tend to be very incremental.
That's how we were able to keep our
average stops so low because we have
multiple stops. So as the position is
not. Going our way or going against us,
we're cutting. So yeah, I would, I would
just ask that, you know, if you want to
ask a follow-up question, it's like,
well, yeah, where did you come up with
that 2.8%?Well, and I'll
just add, if you're going to use that
mechanical of a stop. To say,
listen, I just want to be tight
on everything. You're you're going to get
stopped out a decent amount even if
you're selection criteria is very, very
good because to Brandon's point, you have
to give trades a little bit of
room to fluctuate fluctuations. Normal
2.8% is very, very tight. So and that's
where you know, you can use staggered
stops and if I was going to use some type
of a just blanket stop, it would be more
5 to 8% on average somewhere in that
range because it's just going to allow
names to fluctuate a little bit in that
normally. Right,
Garry's asking about
DOCS.
Where did you buy? Well, we didn't. Ohh.
I think he's talking because we had a
position in this name. This is this would
be an example of a situation.
Actually of that again, high alpha,
low standard deviation power, power play
esque if you will. But the
way I think about power play
esque is that same principle. So
this rally something just doing some
quick math 80.
Bring on my calculator.
Ish percent but but you know begrudging
only pulled in about 10. We took a
small position. I want it was right here
right Brandon and just shooting you know
shooting at this little low cheat here
and this same exact same exact idea we're
just talking about with some of those
other ideas see how the volume. And this
pullback, yeah, that really nice run all
in. This pullback was very low. I would
love to see it tighten up even a little
bit more. And sadly, we had to. I think
we dumped half the position. No idea the
earnings are going to be this
spectacular. Dumped a decent chunk of the
position because we didn't have quite
enough cushion to be comfortable with and
then of course had. Sold into this
earnings, but it's the same every time
you notice how we're looking for a tight
area and we're looking for that low risk
entry. Where can we be proven right or
wrong in very short order. So you're
never going to see, you know, Brandon and
I going ohh yeah, we, we bought it right
here and there's our buy point. Stock
wedged up four days. We just decided,
well, we'll just bite the bullet and
never like we, we're always looking for
where those tight little areas where we
can know in relatively short order if the
trains coming in on schedule.
Tamron saying bought EXPE.
It's Expedia.
As it was forming a flat base. In a
previous Q&A, Mark mentioned Coco. He
described it as just a pull back to the
50 day after a breakup from a larger
base, which he said didn't meet his
criteria. Is Exp also just a pullback?
You didn't say when. Uh ohh sorry I'm
sorry. He's saying he thought he XP was
forming a flat base. Well,
this is forming a base. It's a little
short. It's looking.
But if it was tight, you know, if this
continues to tighten here, is it
acceptable? This is relatively tight so
we can get some more tightening. Could
you play this? I think so. The bigger
base was down here. I don't remember if
we were looking at this one or not on
this right hand side because you could
have tried this and then of course it
gapped it just. Again, it never gave you
a really crisp right hand side, but it
broke out of this base over here.
In terms of, you know, I would just be
watching right here, the Coco example,
take a look at that.
Now similarly, just it's a shorter base
and this was after coming out of, you
know, this pivot over here was a little
bit sloppy. Then once it got going, this
is sort of one of the themes. You know,
we've had some of these stocks have run,
they've got shorter consolidations that
are, you know, maybe forming bases, but
we just don't have a lot of crispness on
the right hand side yet. In a lot of
these examples. Making sure I
answered the question but.
Yeah, I wouldn't. I wouldn't, couldn't.
He was asking. I said this is a pullback
by. If you want to call, you know this
would have been your pullback by. Right
here, sort of within the base where you
find support. Could you have tried it the
next day there? Yeah, again, a little
sloppy. There's there's just very little
tightening. But this pullback by is
coinciding now this is where again, if
you wanted to start with a portion of the
position, then you see can it tighten up
and this is where you could see how. Even
in a couple of days. You
know, we, we start to see action like
this proliferating or and, and more
importantly, do we get consistent or any
type of follow through on balance from
these type of setups? That's what I'd be
looking for. Can we get a proliferation
of pivots and then what's the subsequent
action? So, and this is where we always
say. They don't in in a market, things
can and do often change faster than you
think. And there's no doubt when it comes
to setups, there can be very few. And
then all of a sudden, like where did all
these ideas come from? So this is, you
know, a good example of what would be
looking for.
Casas is asking his Shaq is buyable now.
If you wanted to get aggressive on Shaq,
you should have been buying. Really could
have been buying earlier through calling
this your first sort of.
Viable spot.
And then I would be looking at this spot
and measuring to two days, it goes low
and looking at the measurement, it's
relatively tight. So you want to get back
in shape or maybe you bought here or if
you're trading around the position. And
this is again, if you, if you were able
to, you know, de risk here.
This pullback is a you know, a little bit
a little bit excessive, but if you were
using some type of 50 to break even or
better or playing a a smaller piece. If
you had a huge line, this move down
probably knocked you out of a decent bit,
if not the whole trade because the
volatility just got a little wide. Now
it's tightening back up. This is where
you add. Years back or if you wanna, if
you trade it out of the whole thing, you
just add the position back. I, I again be
a little bit smaller with the first buys
because we're just not seeing a lot of
traction yet. Joe saying rereading Mark's
books and then he says rarely does it
correct pivot point coming out of a sound
consolidation fail. But I've been here
for years and it seems they fail about
half the time. Give me the exact quote of
where of of where he says rarely does it
correct pivot point coming out of his
sound consolidation. Male because pivot
points do fail. So yeah, I'm, I'm, I
don't recall Mark ever saying that I've
read his books number of times. So yeah,
give me, give me that as an example, or
maybe save that one for the following
Monday. Because, you know, context, of
course, is everything where you read
something even in terms of O'Neill's book
where he talks about. In
non favorable periods nothing's going to
work. So Mark would never say things like
if you do your work properly that a
good pivot won't fail. Good pivots do
fail.
But as a as an aside, I will say
I think rereading the books is something
I am definitely in the habit of doing.
Brandon. I've even said over the last few
years we'd rather we'd rather reread.
Books like Marks, O'Neill's, a few of the
absolute classics, Livermore reread those
every year. Rather than continuing to
look for books either written by folks
that you know are trying to come up
with new ideas and timeless principles
and continuing to take those ideas and
just solidify them in your own mind and
found this. Be much more helpful and I
feel like you find these little bits of
wisdom that maybe you just kind of either
forgot or or, you know, missed because
you didn't have the wisdom that you carry
now. So yeah, the the best, the best
books and materials are ones that really
need to be read multiple times so that
you can internalize those things and sort
of that that famous Bruce Lee. You
know, idea, you know, I'd rather fear,
fear the man who studied one kick 1000
times than a man who knows 1000 different
kicks. And that's, that's really the key
to mastering anything.
Salinger's asking about SEIU as a
potential power play, yet this, this is a
one that probably could be added to
focus. And yes, I'd love to see now,
now, can we get even a day or
two?Right here if
you could just get a tight day or
two.
It'd be aggressive to trade through
today's high. Maybe tomorrow. Could you?
Yeah, you could. Again. You see how I'm.
I'm often a stickler for.
Really wanting things to look good and
proper because I've just found that the
sloppier you get the sloppy the results.
But yes, and this is 1 I have on a
polls list.
Navita saying can you go over my trade in
Ralph Lauren?Bought
it on 12/26.
12/20 right here.
Place my first stop loss just below the
low of 12/23 and the rest on 12/18.
So you're trading?
So you've staggered between.
Here and here.
Just looking at a couple of things really
quick. All things being equal, yeah, I
would not give this a very high grade one
because this is short. It's also pretty
jagged here, you know, and you get this
big of a pullback. There's a price to pay
for this now. I like that. You're using
this low and sort of some imagination
saying hey, I'm expecting this to tighten
up. Problem of course was buying through
230. Even through 233 this is acceptable
at 5%. This is normal this type of a
pullback as it's tightening back up now
you want it to be tight on half. I
can't really fault you for that, but
given. How short this is? This is why I
would expect a day like this. Because it
just hasn't had the time. Now it's
building out and again, if I was to.
I wouldn't trade a pivot like this for
starters, but if I did I would take it
very small and then expect that there's
more tightening needed and look to add if
it can grow into that.
Casey saying, how do you use ants in your
work if you use them at all? Brandon, you
want to.
Sorry, I was on mute there. Yeah, So for
us, answer is just something we use after
we buy a stock and we're in it and we
get a confirmation like that, then we're
going to try to use that Anna's
confirmation to hold a piece of it for a
larger move. And and I'll, I'll just
comment too. Even the answer was a
concept, I didn't even know what it was,
never heard of it. And have been
trading for several years within this
style of course. And I was at I think
it was 2015 Master Trader program and
Mark had asked me to share a few
examples. And then, you know, sort of
similar to what we doing in the gala,
except this was at the Master Trader
program where there were a few. Few of
us that shared some examples of some
good, good and bad trades, wins and
losses. And I shared one and David Ryan
said, hey, Mark, did you, why didn't you
hold a piece of that for a bigger move?
Because it had clear ants. Of course, I'd
sold something way too early. And then it
went on to just have a gargantuan move.
And I said, David, I don't know. I don't
know what that he didn't even know what
that was. I said, teach me the rules. And
show me so I, you know, I can identify
that in the future. And then he sort of
went over the 12:15 up days. And then of
course, now years later, Marks put that
into monologue. So we just sort of use
that money alert when we see those, those
ants confirmation if we own a name we're
looking to potentially hold, those are
the names that are telling you they're
under institutional accumulation. So
you're only know that after the fact and
usually for us, we've already de risked
or potent, it's possible we may have even
sold the trade. So then we're just
looking to say, OK, this can give us
another consolidation. We're just those
are names we want to potentially add
back. But it isn't, it's not just because
something triggers ants. First of all, we
would never buy it because by definition
when it's triggering, it's short term,
very extended. But if we hold
it, that's that's what's giving us and
that was sort of what I'd used even
in terms of Ibit earlier, earlier in the
last year that those early
characteristics pretty much just looked
just like ants, which is it had a
large move greater than 25% in you know,
3 weeks and the volume. There's a 25%
higher say than above average and up 12
of 15 days.
Uh, let's see a lot of happy New Year's
wishes from you guys. So thanks for all
that. Just looked over ET. We already
covered that. Uh,
Khalid's asking about Twilio.
I bought it on on Christmas
Eve. What you what? What stop
do you recommend? Well.
That is something. First of all, this
five point is not good.
There's no pivot here at all and it's
even short-term extended in terms of like
we talked about examples, you know, that
are really high Rs. If you just want to
try and pick them as they turn back up,
if you're going to try that, you should
have bought a day earlier coming, you
know, through this day.
That would have been really the only
acceptable. I think it's, this is not
acceptable. Even in my view, it's it's a
five day pullback that just turns back
up. There's no pivot here. I understand
that has been really strong, but if
you're going to do something like at any
time, you should know where you're
getting out before you get in. Always
so. And if you're asking us where you
should put your stop, you've got bigger
problems because it just tells me you're
buying something with no concept of.
Low risk entries pivots. You
know, and, and what's normal versus
abnormal action? Anything to add there,
Brandon? Yeah. Listen, this thing has has
had a 60% move since that gap and has
now pulled back 11%. I mean, this thing
could pull back 2030% and still be in an
uptrend. So yeah, to Mark's point, like
this, it's too short and this we don't
know is this. To start, you know of a
bigger, larger pullback. That's why we
wouldn't play anything like this.
So it needs time to kind of tell us that
there's, you know, institutions aren't
selling this after such a big move. So
that's why we wanted to wait and build
out before we're buying a name like this.
Another one sort of in the power play
esque theme because it doesn't meet the
classic rules in terms of the double, but
it it's very strong, it's holding up
well. It's holding up very well. This is
where I have it on the radar, you know,
to say, OK, can you can we get a pivot
to form this pullback is acceptable now
can this fill out?In here.
In terms of a pivot. I mean, you
can just see even how a day or two now we
got to pivot.
And we've gone through the time as well,
right? So, you know, it's even given the
stock an opportunity, right, to go
through that. Where it rinses out some of
the weak hands.
Devon's asking thoughts on end tab as a
competitor to PTSG. Yeah, I don't think
about that at all. Look again, I'm
looking at the right hand side. I bring
this stock up, I can tell you I
haven't even seen it. It's got a 65
Rs. This is total no fly zone, and
I see it. Right side again. It looks like
that it's just on to the next one.
And within Mrs. Low, we won't even see
it. Um Judge is
saying Mark has discussed the 50 day or
better rule for staying in the long term.
In a long. Must must be making
long term trade in chop beer markets or
you're not getting as much traction.
Would you recommend using a 21 day or
shorter term moving averages to hand a
trade which is in theory would give you a
tighter stop loss?For
example ONON.
Right now it's above the 50, but
if it goes above the 21 day
and stays there, would that be a
good trade management moving average? I I
don't even understand really the question
and but I think some of this
stems from the idea of improper context
or the the, the lack of understanding. In
terms of what the 50 day break even or
better rule is for? So what's the one we
were looking at earlier brand, I think it
was 8. As an
example, so and looking at this at a
pretty pretty decent size base here
decent right side. This is the weekly and
see how you know even This is why
we're looking at this name. This entire
basing. Stock is going through it nice
accumulation off the lows. This is this
even looks like. Accumulation to me
because you have this big volume spike on
the earnings, got a decent close and came
up, tightened up, volume dried up.
As I pointed out before, you had a pivot
here. Follow up 1 here.
And even down here, this is again a good
example where you sort of had.
You had three low risk spots to get
on board, so if you want to play
this game for a bigger move, the 50
day break even or better rule is when
where you can switch over to that 50
day acid trail because some of your best
names will have the bulk of their move
or even double. Before closing below the
50 but. Of
course there's there's a price to pay for
that and that is the pullback to the 50
as the stock gets extended can be large.
Well, so, yeah, in hindsight, you could
say, well, what about the 20? What about
the 10? What about the five? The those
aren't going to keep you in for the
bigger move. And the 50 is sort of that
blend where the pullback we had somebody
asked something, why not use the 200?
Well, you can pick any average you want.
The the point though is your better
names are going to hold the 50
for a good chunk of that initial
move, that initial alpha. The tighter
you go. Yeah, you'll be able
to crimp off that downside and that's
fine. If that's how you, you're more
likely I didn't honor the 20. You know, a
name like this, you'll probably wind up
getting stopped out here. Or if you're in
the 50, you're still in it and you're and
you're pulled back to that level will be
less. Now this is for those
again who want to play portions of a
bigger move or this is the back to the
backstop. Big move uses this in
combination with under pressure.
I don't have any of the 21 days and
something I even have on my screen, so I
can't comment in terms of saying I just
know for a fact you're going to be not in
you. You will be stopped out a lot
sooner. There's a price to pay for that.
Then you'll look and go, well, if I use
the 50, I'd still be in the name, you
know, in a name like this or in some of
these other names. So you can use any
trailing stop you want in my so long as
you've derisked the trade, it opens up
your options. And this is just one option
because the 50 again, 50 or 10 week blend
is going to keep you in the bulk of
the move. I don't know, Brandon, am I
explaining this right? Yeah, absolutely.
And I think you know, listen. The point
is, is, you know, yeah, you can use the
21 day, but you're going to, you know,
sacrifice because that the 21 day would
have knocked you out marking on that,
that that mark you have there. So again,
understanding why you're using one of
these tools is important. You know, I
think we understand the limitations, of
course. Trailing moving average is not
sophisticated. It's a crude trailing
backstop, a way of playing a move. But
the idea being this is again where if
you did your work properly. And
bought in any of these low risk entries.
You're at a multiple of your risk. And if
you, if you were aggressive in size, you,
you derisked and paid for the right to
hold whatever you want to hold. And this
is where I'm always saying just measure,
measure from here to here. Measure any of
these pullbacks. Ask yourself what you'd
be comfortable with and how much you've
made and then. Position size accordingly
from there. That's exactly how we do it
whenever we're playing anything for
bigger move right. And if you're going to
use the 58 that means you're willing to
give up, you know, just a decent amount
of open trade profits off the highs if it
gets stopped out. So if you know to your
question in the choppier markets, could
you use a 2021 day if you're not?
Comfortable with the wrist then sure, but
then you got to know that you can't be
upset if you get stopped on the 21 day
and it continued to go higher and never
take the 50 because you wanted to be in
the name. Jay's
asking about NVIDIA.
Oops, sorry about that.
Would you like to see it tighten up
more around the 14141 pivot or what A
position taken today as it passed through
138 be acceptable I would not have taken.
I would not have taken this today
through. Through Tuesday's high, you're
asking about that. It's just not
necessary to be that aggressive,
especially again, given we didn't even
get a good close. The most aggressive I
would be in a situation like this is
through this high. I would I would
incrementally start a position there if I
knew I wanted to own this and then bump
it as it comes through here. And is this
pivot acceptable in terms of risk? Yeah.
And to your answer, your question or
would I like to see it come back up here,
maybe even tighten for a few more days?
Sure. Now with a name like NVIDIA, we may
not get that. This is on
everyone's radar, followed by tons of
eyes. So if this if this got really,
really perfect, it might even be more I
could argue it might even be more failure
prone just because so many people are
watching it. But if you want to get on
board NVIDIA, I just showed you how I
potentially do it and it's it is mid
single digit, which you pointed out. So
it it's. Acceptable in that regard.
Frank is asking about ACLO.
Can I buy it at 2450?
Well, I don't see where maybe you're
getting 2450 and this again.
You know this one. This is
too much to be a power play, and this
is too much even to be a viable pivot
in regards to what's acting normal now.
They had this enormous move this in the
uranium space if I'm not mistaken.
There's no, there's no pivot I would
shoot at here. It is going
through, you know, this VCP process, but
we need a little more tightening because
it's still, yeah, it looks tight, but
then you measure it, it's pretty wide.
Yeah, it's OK almost 19% if you want to
buy or 25 area. Yeah, to Brandon's point.
This would be acting normal. You know,
all OK, you, you buy this as it comes out
here, you know, and then it does this.
That'll put you under 1015% of pressure
right there. That's just too much. That
would be normal. Even if we're to tighten
up, it would be normal for a stock to
come all the way over here and do
something like this. And then this is
where. Always just be measuring.
I don't, we don't want to, we don't want
to play the volatility game. We want to
saw the volatility off and we do that by
waiting for tighter pivots. Rather
than expanding and going on, I'll just
get wider because this pivots wider.
Think of it, OK, if you want to play that
game that that tells me, then I need OK,
if you want to play a 20% wide pivot just
to make a 2 to one, I need a 40% move.
Well, I mean, how many 40% movers are you
going to have in a year? And if I grab a
40% move, I don't want that to be a 2 to
one. I want it to be a 12:50.
What should on Geo with you today? At
first took out the prior day's low,
didn't take out the pivot low, then
started to break above the reach
consolidation creating an outside day. Is
this scenario you avoid taking due to
widening volatility?All things being
equal, yes. Now if this was really,
really tight. And I, I
almost put out a little note on this when
it poked its head out and I, I reset the
alarm because I saw it just popped its
head out here and I had an alarm there.
It went off and then it went right back
into the range. So I reset an alarm and I
was going to say, here's a name that's
trying to emerge on an outside day. Now
this it just took out the. Go and to your
point didn't take out the low of the
pivot and that's where you just measure
it was up about 3% on the day. Is
that acceptable? Yeah. Is it a little
sloppy? Yeah, No, it's a 98 hours. This
is a power play because you've got it's
gone through the right period of time,
it's trying to tighten here now.
This is still acceptable even if you
would again take it on the outside day to
to today's low and combination, you know,
3 1/2, four, 5%. Those are all
acceptable. But this is where again, I'd
like to see now that it's come off, I
just I'm going to stick to yesterday's
alarm. Could could you play this coming
through here with a stop right down in
here?Absolutely that that's still
acceptable. So it's always measuring. I
do like to you got some volume drying up
again with the holidays normal, but you
know after this big move stock hasn't
given up much ground that's telling you a
potentially wants higher. So now we're
just looking can we get this pivot to
tighten up even more. But the way
you're thinking about it is exactly how
I'm thinking about it.
John saying, would you critique an entry
today and Warby?
I think critique, I guess today is just
it's a little sloppy, so. This just, you
know, looks to me. Where's the pivot
again? You're just trying to buy it as it
turns up. And
this isn't even one that's, you know,
95 Rs. I see again in that
similar theme where it's held up really
well. Just measuring here to see based
on the rules, it's not a power
play. It has not had the percentage
move quite strong enough, but it's
rallied and held up pretty well.
But not nearly it's just sloppier than
even some of the other power play esque
situations. So I think there's better
ideas and fundamentals don't look very
good. So I I wouldn't play it. I don't
know brand anything to add there? Not
really. Yeah, I was going to say.
And even that pivot, if you look, you
know, the big reversal day on 12/18, then
you know, on 12/20, it took out the low
and then came right back. And it just
looks, you know, back and forth and
sloppy. And given the way, you know,
stocks have been acting lately, I just to
your point, there's just better
merchandise to even try like a, you know,
a Geo. Alex is asking why we
sold ARSARIS just didn't didn't follow
through, didn't come in on schedule. You
didn't have to sell it. Of course, it
didn't hit the stop, but it you know,
it's leaking off as it sort of bounced
back. Just stepping aside, but with the
idea that you can always get back in the
name. So this can retighten here or give
you a better pivot. And you just
you get right back on board. What was the
other 1TB RG?
There's no pivot again, where's the
pivot? If you were, if you're gonna, you
know, even this really short and same
theme, no power, not the power play. It
just had a, you know, strong move, a
little bit lower price, no earnings.
So if I was going to try and play this, I
would have played it, you know, maybe
this even that was sort of outside day
would maybe tried it here. And I'm only
going to make a play like this in the
best of environments. This is not that
environment. So I'm, you know, staying
away.
Ohh sorry I got the name wrong. That was
Harpreet asking that Alex is asking about
WGS. Making the move
today so far. Been on my radar for weeks.
What do you guys think?I think
the last time I talked about this I was
saying given the reversal. You know
the reversals at these level let this
level I'd like to see it come up
and tighten up into that. Well, we came
poked the head out now it's reversing.
But again, measuring even to here you've
got this is more.
This is more than double digits Yeah,
it's about yeah, 1213% so and now now
look, this is that stock. It's had a
really nice move and now it's come into
the 50. It's been a little bit longer to
technically be a power play Yeah, more
than 8 weeks now, maybe 4 or 5-6 yeah.
Now you just see can this base. Workout.
Can it continue to tighten? Do we get
some type of tighter right hand side?You
know you could. Could you have tried it
here? Even this?You
know, this is, you know, 8%.
I'm I'm always measuring going. I don't,
I don't love, I don't like this pivot
enough to go yellow and maybe take a
really small position and see if it can
tighten up. It's just it needs more
tightening. But obviously 99 Rs. This is
these are the situations you want to be
looking at and given the benefit of the
doubt potentially and you know, some
fundamentals on the table. So obviously
some exciting things going on. Just not
tight enough for me.
Uh, right? Not sure if I'm
getting that name right. Dragoon or
Dragons? Asking about Uber.
No. Huh.
An upgrade and tight price action on
the daily but below SMA's this is.
This is another one I would just never
see. Obviously you're new and that's OK,
but a 19 Rs or anything even below 70
is generally no fly zone. You've got this
is running into huge overhead supply.
There's just no right side we're ever
going to trade it looks like this and
we're not even going to see it. So,
and if if you're referring to this as
tightness, this is the worst kind of
this. This is more of a short. This looks
like it's potentially forming a ledge.
The worst thing a stock can do is break
hard and not rally hard break very little
rally. Another hard break,
very little rally.
In fact, I'm just moving over to the
weekly saying and even here you've got.
You know, this is where you start to see
this is looking, you know, staying like,
like we're going from this is this is
this like Stage 3 to me? And now we're
potentially, you know, moving into Stage
4. I'd
be, I'd be, I'd have that on. I'm going
to put that on a potential short watch
list.
TPMG saying seems China has decoupled
from U.S. market. If you agree, will you
consider China ADR's if they set up I let
Power play and KC go given the US market
environment. Your thoughts and I I saw
that's king soft. I saw this one too, but
it's just sloppy. Where's the where's the
pivot?And to your point about
you and chase this gap or this gap to
play this one, I don't. Not for a sub $10
stock Chinese ADR, Absolutely not. They
answer the question though. Listen, if
they set up I'm interested. That's the
short term answer. It doesn't matter what
country you show me a good pivot in
prices. I'm interested to trade it. I
don't even. Can be a different asset,
can be. People started asking me about
crypto. How did you get into crypto or
whatever The reality is I started seeing
bases and low risk entries years ago in
crypto. And so started trading a few,
making money, started trading a few more.
It's just that simple. So it doesn't
matter what the. What what
it is. If it sets up, I'm potentially
interested. Again, meets
my criteria.
Wilfred saying new member, happy to be
here. Welcome. Thanks for your great
service. Could you comment on GE V? Yeah,
this is one I'm I'm watching. It's sort
of on the. High on deck
list if you will. You had this
short little. Pivot right here and and
a little follow up 1 here we were we were
looking for this to tighten up more
didn't do it. This was viable though and
turned into a really nice winner. Now
you're looking for another another pivot
and this is only a second stage base. So
look, can we get some tightening here?
Can we tighten up in here? You know get
this. Would love to see it come
up into this area again telling you that
and where we get that, you know, maybe a
small little last ringing out of the
towel and even something like that. See
how much more symmetrical that looks.
Love to see it get off the 50 a little
bit too tight and then go.
Um.
Joey saying Margaret G often says that
something is too short. About how many
days of pausing do you require for it
to be to your liking? Also, what
constitutes a crisp entry? Well, the
first thing is it we I used to
hear Mark and and David say, well this
doesn't have the look a lot. And
didn't necessarily know what that meant.
And you didn't give me, you know, any
type of an example, but I don't know
Brandon even from just looking at focus
saying, OK, what's. Geo would
be an example. I drew in a number of
examples even right here. See how see how
much better this CRISPR, this looks with
a couple of tight days in here. That's
the theme as a general what we're looking
for all the time. And then where I know
relatively quickly, OK, in a situation
like this, see how I got 1 tightening.
Then I'd have two. Then I'd have a third
little mini 1. This tells me right
here, we've had a couple of rings out of
the towel for those who bend to the
Master Trader program. So I can know with
relative certainty if this train's coming
in on schedule and now I can take a
position with a stop here versus having
to be down here to know whether I'm right
or wrong. And the difference between
those to some of you thinking, oh, it's
small. It's it's not that big a deal.
It's everything. Think
about that and why? Because I
am automatically. To quote Larry
Height and Mark Minervini, increasing my
asymmetric leverage when I use a pivot
like this versus that, which is why I'm
saying I'm much more willing to just wait
for pivots like this to proliferate than
to place sloppy or wider ones.
Yeah, I think that's a, yeah, I think
Fortune in that statement, absolutely who
don't understand it. And that's a really
good point, Markey. And the only thing
I'll add is like, listen, if it's six
weeks or less, typically I want a base to
be 6 weeks. If it's less than that, it's
got I want context of where it's come
from and then to what Mark you just
described as the tightening from left to
right. So, and, and you know, we've been
seeing short, too short recently because
a lot of the names that you know, you've
got, you guys have been asking for dust
to give opinions on. They were just short
right sides. Well, they weren't, you
know, we have no problem looking at those
pivots, but they got to start proving
that the short pivots are working. You
know, the stocks are breaking out and
rallying above them, you know, and and
giving us a good, you know, couple R's
from the buy point. Well, we haven't seen
that in Pooler for, you know,
proliferating enough to want to play
these and get more involved. And as you
can see now as time has gone by, that's
been the right approach is to not
necessarily play those. Because you
didn't make, you know, you didn't get
ahead if you took the majority of those
names. So that's typically what I want to
do. If it's six weeks or less, then I
mean, I want it to look really good. And
to Margie's point, like you want a tight
pivot to get that asymmetry in yourfavor.
Uh, let's see.
Paul's asking about CRNT.
Bought on Tuesday at 471.
OK, so here's another. You know,
this is an example of, you know, someone
again using that sort of creative as it
turns back up and presumably you're using
now and this is your stop. I don't, I
don't hate this. Because I
see what you're doing, I think saying,
OK, I'm using my imagination expecting
this to maybe tighten more, but if it
doesn't at least have a position if I was
going to play this well, one, you got $5
stock, so they're on that has to be
discounted massively. And that would that
would be a pretty major negative even in
terms of being creative because the
cheaper they are, the better I want them
to look because you're just. They're
going down the quality bin. And it
took me a while to even understand this.
I used to trade more lower priced stocks,
one, because liquidity wasn't nearly an
issue in the early days. And if you did
your work right, you know, they they
weren't as widely followed. But you also
have to understand there's a price to pay
for that because a lot of institutions
the the cheaper it is, the less potential
buyers you even have because a lot of.
Ones that won't even own a stock like
this, only low end funds. Can't even
buy it was this acceptable yeah it's it's
again it's still sloppy and just, you
know measuring but this isn't this is a
cheap little power play trying to form
here and that that or this was really
your only sort of you know viable. I like
this better because you had at least
you've had one you know and using your.
Imagination, you're sort of drawing in
two tightening here, but even in terms of
tightness, you know you're looking at a
25. I guess it's seven 8%, you
know, for for a $5 stock, I just think
there's better, there's better
merchandise. If you're going to play a
really low price stock, though, I like
that it's on the high Rs list at least
and you're using, you know, a stop that's
acceptable. Franco
saying brand, Mark and Brandon, would you
share 24 performance? What was your
biggest drawdown last year? Best wishes
for 25. We haven't gotten this all the
stuff back in terms of accounts, but I
think we did. Just over 35%
worse peak to through, I want to say
Brandon was 8% or something like that.
You can fill in any, any color there. But
yeah, it was look, it was it was a
solid year, not, not an absolute barn
burner, but in terms of, you know, risk
to a return to overall risk, I think
we're pleased. That is
about right. Umm, I did see another
question along those lines asking about
our average gain, an average loss in
percent. We were yeah. You wanna let me
let me just let me just pull that
up real quick. So yeah, our average win
rate was 38% and average gain was 8.35,
average loss of 2.9.
And that's right in line to and for us
that there if it would have been a better
year if we'd had more, more
opportunities, that's really sort of what
it boiled down to. Yeah, we didn't do too
many trades. So I think that somebody it
was a question that before I made you
panelists was in there from. George, I
believe, because he was saying his total
trades were 77, batting average 32.47,
average gain 6.12, average loss of 2.77.
So you know, yeah, you're in the ballpark
of what we did. I think. Let me
see total trades. I haven't logged
everything we did about yeah, a little
maybe like 100 and 2040 trades, so.
Um, yeah, I would, I would say,
you know, pretty, pretty standard, you
know, in terms of and.
All in all, yeah, solid, but, you know,
not a home run. Gary
was asking about YPF. Is this an
oil name? Is an oil name enough
for you to not try a position
today or yesterday? No, but it's this
is just sloppy. So
if this was.
You know, this isn't that great of a
pivot. I see what you're looking at and
look, it's it's this is this is where
again, let's see, we got 12345. This is
more at least more than a few days. If
you want to play a name like this, this
is exactly how you do it.
I don't know anything about this
situation in particular. And if it's a
power play, I'm not really even looking
at the group as much. So in terms of
clearly this is this is telling me
something's going on. I would look into
the news, you know, to to at least be
wondering why is this had such a big
move? And if you want to own the name,
you're looking at it exactly right. But
I'm going to look more at the pivot and
in terms of the oils and cyclicals, this
is where we just talked about, you know,
because the cycles are inverse and our
historical record just isn't as good in
that area. I don't know that I've ever
looked at it in terms of cyclicals that
are power place. That's not those aren't
as common all things being equal. So I
can't. We can't say with any certainty
there, but I would not not trade a really
crisp power play regardless of the group.
I'm looking because the market is telling
me, wow, look at, look at the strength
I'm going to default to to the setup
itself, not to the group. And and
and that's the general rule. If if the
pivots are really crisp and tight, I'm
interested, like I said before.
Um, Harpreet Singh, I'm a lot of
questions and why don't our wanting to
learn from others? Why don't we have a
chat room? Not a good idea. You know,
that's a, that's a good follow up for
Mark I, you know, I don't believe we have
any plans to do a chat room for exactly,
you know what you potentially mentioned,
but I, I have to get more of his
specifics in terms of the. Color of that.
Already talked about GV.
And what would you evaluate my body
talked about Geo Michael, like I said, at
least it's tight enough. Is it
acceptable? Yes. Did it come out on
inside day? Yeah. This is where again,
I'd love to see just even another day or
two of tightening. This would be an
example of.
Even one day like this, you know, or
let's say, let's say you get 11.
One type inside day and then the stock
follows through. I'd be willing to, I'd
be willing to potentially entertain the
name. So someone was saying what's too
short versus short? Well, this looks
short, but then again, an inside day in
context of this, that's where I'm
interested. And then and then I might
even do something where you buy the name
and you stagger a stop here and here
between the two again, giving me a little
more asymmetry because that's what I'm
always looking for. How can I torque
that risk reward ratio in my favor?
Um BT E Brian, OK saying first
time attending. Well, welcome Brian.
Please post location tutorials and forums
to calculate percentages for ratios for
stopping OK.
Cumulative compounding to get the whole
year percent gain manually. I'm not
really sure what that question is.
Brandon, are you reading that one? Yeah,
no, I I read that too and I didn't
necessarily didn't totally understand
what he was asking.
But real simple, there's not going to be
a calculator to get your yearly gain
percentage return manually. That's just a
simple calculation of wherever you're at,
you know, minus the starting point
divided by the starting point. So you
know, you start, you start the year with
10 grand in the account and you know
you're at 11. Brand you just take, you
know, your gains, minus losses divided by
your starting principle. And that's your,
you know, obviously you can also do plus
or minus withdrawals. Any of your, your
brokers, though, should have that, you
know, pretty simple, you know, run for
you or you can, they'll often have where
you can do a year to date, you know,
percent gain loss, that kind of thing. So
that's, that's pretty standard. Again,
not sure I'm understanding your question,
right. So and look, Brian, if you're new,
we're anyone who's newer or starting, you
know, the new year off with us. We're
going to get to a lot of, you know, these
topics over time and through the Q&A and
the different study sessions. So just be
patient. There's always a learning curve,
but you know, everything's explained in
time. I see we've gone. Just over an
hour, we'll do maybe 1-1 or two more
already talked about WGS.
Greg's asking about NARMS looking also
guys at a few see folks have
put in, you know repeat questions. So
try and get somebody new here to
close out again, it's just short.
It does on another. Chart.
I don't know. Much about
this name. And this is
just a name, you know, came up the right
hand side really strong. It's trying to
tighten here and and come out of this
this bigger base so that I don't mind the
RSI is acceptable. Look, could you play
this right here? It's definitely tight.
So I like it in that regard.
And you're looking at, you know, 2, you
know, three and a half, 4% to this little
low right there, but it's a little bit
short. Now the context is it's sitting on
the right side of a much larger base. So
I'm a little bit more interested because
again, context saying, OK, I've got, I've
got a stock that's potentially coming out
of this larger base. I don't know what
this news was. I'd look into that too.
Volumes drying up here. Look if this can.
Stay tight or you knew a lot about the
the company really want to own it. I
might start a position today. You're also
running into, you know, these reversals.
That's where I, you know, if you wanted
to start it, you'd start it and then see
do we get more tightening into, you know,
something like this? This is where you
can see in all these examples and number
of these. I've drawn some things in how
in just a series of, you know, a few
days. A week or two we could see a
proliferation of a lot of new ideas and
pivots, low risk entries. That's where
you always, you know, don't again, we
always say, especially in a market where
the long term trend still intact, you
know, don't go away for weeks. You know,
maybe you take a day off, but then, you
know, be quick to, you know, do the work.
Look, look through the the focus. Listen,
the names you have on your watch list,
you know, for a changing character.
Uh, we'll, we'll end with this one from.
Let's do this one from Dan on. Can you
please explain more incremental stops? Do
you have any hard and fast rules on when
to begin selling a portion of your
holdings and when do you start selling a
portion of the positions Brandon you want
to?So as far
as the stops are, we don't have any
hard rules. It's more or less just, you
know, again, looking at the chart and
technically seeing where can we place
multiple stops as the trade is souring
And then as far as selling a portion
of our holdings in the strength, you
know, again that's. There's
no harder fast rules on that as well.
Typically, you know, we want to sell at a
multiple of our risk and you know if
that's the first move out of a base, say
we get up, you know, 10/12/14 percent or
more in a short amount of time, we're
going to probably derisk into that just
because it's short term. Extended but
also we want to you know, again, we have
a couple things and I'm actually going to
cover this in the stock analysis that
I've been trying to work on here um, you
know as we enter a trade, we want to
expand try to expand our average gain
that's one of our goals right, but we
also want to hold through one or two
natural reactions so. It all depends on
how, you know that the trade unfolds as
far as when we're going to be selling
into strength. Now if we want to derisk
because we have a lot of risk and we got
a quick 89%, then you know, yeah,
sometimes we'll take that. But the
majority of the time we're looking at it
in a vacuum. And again, we're trying to
sell at multiple. Bars of our risk and we
want to try to give the stock the benefit
of the doubt if it's acting well. Yeah, I
think Brandon pretty much covered it all,
but I'll just add the idea of a hard and
fast rule when to begin selling a portion
of the holdings. The first is when it
doesn't do what you think or or the
minute if something is not come from a
trading family. One of the first things,
you know, my dad taught me is, you know,
when do you get out of a bad trade? And
his answer was the second, you know, it's
a bad trade. The key, of course, is, you
know, learning how to win when and how to
know that. And that's really what this
entire methodology is designed to do. So
the hard and fast rule more so than
anything else is when. Volatility is
starting to widen. So even if we're using
something now, there are times volatility
widens a little bit and it's not abnormal
and maybe it's just a pivot failure or,
or some pivot leakage, not an overall,
you know, base failure or pivot failure.
And that's where you got to look at, at
the setup. But I, you know, I drew in a
number of examples where I'm saying, OK,
what, what was the one brand I just drew
in a little bit. So showing how well if
we could get a pivot like this, I'm a
lot more believe yeah, GV, I'm a lot more
interested now I drew, I drew this
example or I'll use the one.
Bros. Saying
if we could get, you know,
even just a mini little tightening
here. Let me get a couple
of days like this.
And you trade it through here. Well, if
it's really crisp. You know,
could you start?With the low
of the day, yeah, that's the most
aggressive. And you can use some type of
staggering as volatility is widening
because the more this stock is is starts
doing this, it's just telling you the
train's not coming in on schedule and
you're either going to have to give it a
lot more time, which is we don't want to
do. The whole idea is to get efficiency.
In your capital. So the more time I have
to sit and wait in the name, you know,
that's time I'm wasting another have my
money in cash or in something else that's
that's potentially with the train is
coming in on schedule. So really the the
hard and fast rule is as volatility
starts to widen and there's evidence that
the training isn't, you know, moving in
our direction as we had expected. That's
when we potentially want to start
incrementally reducing. And look, the
more you do this, the, the you just
develop more of a keen eye in a sense
for, you know how to do that. Yeah. You
just gotta see this stuff over and over
again. Yeah. And every look, every cycle,
every period, that's where your eye
improves and and your ability as a trader
improves. So if you're new, that's OK.
That's all. That's all. Part of the
process. All right, guys, we're going
just over an hour good, good places any
to stop. We'll be back here Monday for
Q&A. Obviously look for the weekend study
session and you know, like I said, don't
keep, keep, keep the powder dry. We, we
may have a better environment here in
short order. Yeah. And
also, yeah, stock analysis, I'm going to
have out hopefully today or tomorrow and
then I'll have another larger one out
this weekend. I'm basically reviewing all
the large gains we had from the platform
in 2024. So definitely look for that. I'm
putting trying to put as much time into
that as I can. And it's it
should be almost like a small model book
for 2024. So perfect. Alright, guys, take
care. We'll see you next week. All right,
bye now.