Good morning and welcome to the Minervini
Private Access Training Room.
I'm Bob Weissman.
If you can do a quick
raising of your hand to let
me know that everybody is
hearing me loud and clear.
Hope everybody enjoyed your weekend.
If you're watching the
football game, some really
exciting ones, including
my Eagles victory.
With that said, let's also welcome Mark
Ritchie to the room.
Good morning, Mark.
Morning, Bob.
Morning, everybody.
And if you can just
raise your hand to let us
know you're hearing
Mark Ritchie loud and clear.
And for everybody who is
coming to the gala this weekend,
I look forward to seeing all
of you, meeting all of you.
And let's get started with today's question
and answer session with Mark Minervini.
Take it away, Mark.
Okay.
Hello, everyone.
Good morning.
Sorry that I was a bit late here today.
Just had trouble getting online on Zoom.
Taking a look at the market here.
We're undercutting these lows,
rolling over a little bit.
This is exactly what I expected.
The real question is whether it's going to
get worse or not.
And whether we shake out
the lows here and maybe
start base building and
seeing some setups.
You can see the NASDAQ
also... Just kidding here.
NASDAQ also coming off, taking out those
lows.
Russell's all the way down to the 200-day
right now.
New York Stock Exchange, NYSE,
is also closing in on that 200-day.
So depending on where you look,
the damage isn't huge.
And it hasn't been... the
market hasn't even pulled
back enough to have the
long-term models raise cash.
So I wouldn't be surprised if you do get
more downside, the models raise cash.
And if this is a correction
within an ongoing bull market,
you'll raise cash like right
around the lows probably.
But you still got to raise cash.
So don't think... I'm saying
don't listen to the model.
If you're in your
401ks, the models start
going into 75%, 50%,
you need to raise cash.
Because we don't know.
We never know if it's going to get worse
or not.
But again, if we're going to have a garden
variety correction here and pull back,
that's generally what happens is you'll
raise cash.
And then you're getting right back in
shortly after.
Not many ideas here.
Mark, we really haven't found much,
right?
I mean, even the ideas
that we are finding, I see
today there's a lot of
stocks down 3%, 4%, 5%.
So there is some volatility around those
pivots, even of the few that are setting up.
Yeah.
I mean, it's been the same really since we
started the distribution dominant tape
about, I don't know, three, four weeks ago
now.
And it's just, you know, until we see some
signs of, you know, character change,
I think it's best to be really nimble and
keep a lot of dry powder.
Yeah.
Just be patient here.
And, you know, we'll probably get a better
market in the not so distant future here.
I'd like to see, personally, I'd like to
see a pretty good correction here.
Because now, you know, we're short.
We don't have any stocks to speak of.
So when you're in a lot of cash,
you know, yeah, you want to see that
market wash out correct and then set up
for, you know, a much larger advance.
The bigger that you get that decline and
the more you wash things out, the more you
can set up for a sustained move going
forward.
Let's see what you guys are coming up with
here for questions and we'll answer them.
All right.
Uh, first question in, uh, Pratesh is
asking in the MTP workbook, there is an
example of travel zoo,
uh, from, you know, I don't
think they're around
anymore, but from July of 2011.
Yeah.
I guess you can go back there.
One way.
Can Mark explain what makes this wedging?
I see there are a few down days as stock
is moving up on the right side.
I know it doesn't have VCP, but my question
is more regarding the wedging comment.
I think he's talking about right here.
If my memory serves me, um, that's a spot
mark.
Yeah.
You know, so, I mean, this is definitely
classic, classic wedging.
And first of all, when you see this
correction of, uh, again, hold on one second.
Cause I, uh, it's a very small here,
kind of blurry.
Um, you know, you've got a very,
very big decline here.
Um, and when you get those big declines,
you want to have, and the point I was
making, um, uh, in the workbook,
uh, is that these are faulty.
These are faulty setups because you just
don't have that right side building and
giving enough time, uh,
and, and pullbacks to digest
all that decline and all
that overhead supply.
Those trap buyers, um, and those profit
takers converge as the stock comes back up
that right side, you've got a big gain for
the people who bottom fished, and you've
got a lot of trap buyers
that got caught in this stock
and are now looking to get
out and break, at break even.
Um, and that would, that's what overwhelms
the stock.
So this is the wedging right here.
You really never had much.
You had this one day
where it pulled back, but you
never really had any right
side building and shakeouts.
Um, and, and that's, you know,
very classic.
I mean, very classic.
This is the same thing that you would hear
if you read O'Neill's books, you know,
about the, of that symmetry on the right
side and having shakeouts.
Okay.
He's also asking, uh, the ticker symbol
F-T-A-I.
Would you call the base, the right-hand
side wedging?
Absolutely.
We would call this compressed.
This is a compressed right side.
So this is a compressed
right side with no right
side development with,
with pivot development.
So this is sort of the, you know,
the worst of all worlds here.
Or now it's obviously it's very strong
coming off the lows.
Maybe this was earnings and, and maybe it
can go higher, but this is where the
volatility, you know,
is, there's a much higher
chance that you're
going to have volatility.
So we'd want to see that right side build
it out.
So it's very V-shaped, um, and it ran
straight up that right side.
So that's what we call time compression.
Yes, the, the, the time is very
compressed.
You're not having much time on the right
side and it's running straight up.
So that needs some type of right side
development.
Okay.
Um, but good eye.
That's a good eye.
With the change in the administration,
uh, uh, presidential administration,
what sectors do you see becoming in focus
for the next four years?
I have no idea.
Your guess is as good as mine.
And I, all I can do is give you some very
valuable advice.
Don't, don't try to predict that because
it's, it'll be frueless.
Um, so I have no idea what sectors and,
and the beautiful thing is I don't have to
know because they'll show up in the
individual stocks and the charts and the
earnings and we'll be in those,
in those sectors.
Actually, sometimes well before the
sectors are even hot and anybody even
realizes that those sectors are the
sectors that are getting, uh, you know,
the, uh, the, the, the institutional,
uh, love.
So a lot of, and the reason I say that is
because when I first started, I started as
a quant, I'd form an opinion
of the market, look for the
best sectors and then the
best stocks in those sectors.
And I was constantly missing the leaders.
So I flipped it around and went stock
sector market.
And that's when everything changed for me.
And I made all my money, um, was when I
went bottoms up because, and the reason
why is because those, those really great
companies, the ones that are the leaders
are going to lead and they're going to
bottom first.
And by the time you find out what sectors
are, you're going to have some of these
low rogue stocks that
have already doubled and
tripled and you, and you
missed their best buy points.
All right.
Chris is asking regarding the SPY models.
I believe Mark says that given they are
pure mechanical models, if we are
following them, then
we should stick to
following the model and
not trade around them.
Uh, however, uh, recently
Mark has suggested raising 25 to
50%, even though the models
haven't signaled anything yet.
I know you just kind of addressed that
Mark, but how should you interpret that if
we are following his logic of sticking to
a mechanical model?
Well, that's your decision.
You know, I mean, I'm telling you, giving
you my gut feel and read of the market.
And if you want to trade around them,
that's fine.
If you're really long-term oriented and
you want to have less trading,
I would stick with them,
but there's a price, there's a
price to pay for everything
that you do in the market.
And so if you stick with those models,
you're going to give up some of the,
uh, you know, maybe, you know,
we get it right sometime and we sell early
and other times we
don't, you know, and, and
we, we sell early
and we try to get cute.
And the next thing, you know, the market's
moving higher and we've lost some chips.
Well, we're, we're also going to lose some
chips when we have to let the market come
off a bit before we get a long-term
signal.
So either way, you know,
if, I mean, personally,
I, if I were you, I would
stick to the model.
I mean, if it, you know, me, I,
I have a certain degree of expertise where
even if I get it wrong
and I trade around them,
you know, I can usually
self-correct very quickly.
It's almost like cooking, you know,
baking is very scientific and,
and the measurements, you don't,
you don't correct much, but when you're
cooking like a dish, like a chicken
franchise or something, you know,
you, you put some salt in there and you
taste it and you, and you correct along
the way that takes, that takes a more
skilled chef, if you will, you know,
to, to do those corrections, um,
as opposed to just sticking to a recipe.
So, but it's really a decision you have to
make, you know, whether you want,
I'm teaching everything and I,
I'm not going to, you know, not tell you
what I see, if I see danger coming and,
but, and that's my, you know, that's my
read of the market, but that read of the
market is a whole different type of
trading than a mechanical system that
you're committing to and sticking to.
You've got to make that decision.
And, and, and more or less, or,
you know, most of the time when I'm
talking about the market and saying,
Hey, here, sell, raise cash short,
I'm more pertaining to stock trading.
Now, those, those models, I don't trade
off of those models.
Um, they're great.
And they were designed for, to give us,
um, a read of the long-term environment
and to provide something for the 401k type
investors that are not going to trade
stocks like we're trading here,
especially very quickly.
Um, but you know, I'm going to be,
I'm going to be keying in on the
individual stocks
and I'm not even really
interested in trading
the SPY to begin with.
Um, I want to trade individual stocks.
All right.
Um, Hytham is asking, could you comment on
Walmart that he bought on January 10th?
Can this be considered a low cheat or is
it just bottom fishing?
Yeah, right.
10th right here.
Um, it is a low cheat.
You know, it's not much of a base.
Um, you know, if this is fine.
I mean, if you're interested
in being in the market right
now, um, you know, it was,
it was out of gap, obviously.
So you chased the gap up a little bit and
now you're getting underwater.
So obviously you may be a little concerned
here.
It's acting fine so far, you know,
be fine until it's not.
And by the time you find out it's not,
you know, maybe you're going to be down,
you know, uh, I don't know.
What is this?
Yeah, it's very tight.
So one thing I do like is come all the way
down to here and it's like 3%.
So you've, you've certainly backed into a
very low risk entry.
So because of that, I would say,
you know, it's, it's fine.
It's, you know, it's a pretty good entry.
Yeah.
That's what he commented, having a very
tight stop inside day, the prior day.
Yeah.
If you're going to do something
like this in this market, and
I like low cheats and bottom
fishing on the bigger cap names.
I do, I do prefer to try to get those
coming off the bottoms, um, because
they're more widely followed by the time
you get to new highs.
Uh, they're more, you know, they're more
efficiently priced.
So, um, if you're going to, you know,
trade in this type of environment where
you're got a tape that's distribution
dominant and the wind's in your face,
you definitely want to
be coming from, you
know, tight pivots and
very tight risk points.
And I think you've achieved that.
Question, uh, from Chris on TSM.
On January 2nd, there was a pullback buy
triggered.
Isn't it a poor pullback buy due to the
close in the very bottom of the range?
Close in the very bottom of the range.
We're talking about the day before,
maybe?
Yeah.
On the 31st.
I would, you know, the outside day,
I mean, you know, is it perfect?
No, but it's a completely viable pullback
buy.
Um, is it my favorite?
No.
Um, but again, you know, with a bigger cap
name, especially I would have liked it.
You know, maybe go inside a couple of days
and then maybe by taking out that high.
Um, so it's, it's, it's a pullback buy,
you know, and again, you can assess the
quality of the pullback buy and,
you know, where the pivot is and so forth.
And that's where the art comes in and the,
and the decision-making comes in of how
much of a stickler you want to be on
certain things.
But, you know, if I really wanted to own
this and, you know, then, you know,
I would, I would definitely take that
pullback buy.
You know, if it was
a stock that I didn't, I
was like, no, I don't
really care if I own this.
It's not, let's just say it was a really
thin stock and, you know, and I just
didn't, wasn't going to get a big position
on.
I was like, ah, this isn't going to mean
much to my portfolio.
I'd probably wait.
You know, if it was one that I could get a
big position on and I really loved the
company and loved the fundamentals were
great.
And I really wanted this in my portfolio,
then I wouldn't let this go by.
And I would probably take that buy.
Excuse me.
David M., who is, I believe, new,
Mark, so might need a quick refresh here.
But he's asking for stocks on the focus
list.
What price level do they need to break and
or volume to start at least a pilot buy?
Well, first of all, the focus list are not
set up as buys just yet.
So once they're set up as buys,
we would put out some type of buy alert
where you would have
a buy price or it would
say buy now as it's
moving through those pivots.
So these are just stocks that are either
set up or close to being set up.
Like something like Wix here, I still would
like to see this tighten up a bit here.
So if this were to tighten up,
maybe for a few days and then came out,
then that pivot would be right here.
So it depends on the stock.
You know, every stock, I put RVRK on here
simply because this undercut the low.
And maybe you might get some
type of little low, cheap bottom
fishing pivot here around
the shakeout close to the low.
If it can set up really
close to that danger
point, I really feel this
is the danger point now.
You don't want to take out this low.
Now that you undercut those
lows in this power play type
situation, this low is becoming
very important, this 110.
So if we were to set up here maybe and
tighten up, especially we can get a few
days and maybe turn up
from there, you know, that
would be a good buy point
close to the danger point.
So again, it's not there yet, but it's
close.
And it could be, it could be by the end of
the week, this could be set up and viable.
So that's how we look at the focus list.
Yeah.
And David, I would
just share to click on the
resources tab, which will
bring you to the user guide.
And the user guide does have a whole
glossary of definitions, including what
the distinction is, a focus
list versus actual... Yeah.
And if you're new, you'll see how things
flow and how we handle things along the way.
You'll get the swing of things after a
while.
And a quick follow-up is
asking is what makes you
consider buying a name for
the Minervi Select Portfolio?
Well, you know, we're looking for some of
the... I mean, the main thing is risk,
you know, always, always risk.
But we're looking for
the most crisp buy points
and, you know, some
of the better setups.
Sometimes we get that right.
Sometimes we don't.
But we're being much more selective and
trading that much more how we would trade,
you know, our own portfolios.
Open positions, we're putting,
you know, a lot of stocks on there.
If they're breaking out,
we're going to put it
on there as long as
they're meeting the criteria.
But with the select, we have to be selective
because we only have so many slots.
There's only so much money.
And so their position sizing is important.
So we're really, you know, it always comes
down to the risk, finding the tightest,
most crisp buy points coming from what we
think are, you know, the better setups.
And again, sometimes we
get that right and sometimes we
don't because we're making
that decision, you know, manually.
All right.
Lou is asking, is ERJ close to making
focus list?
Yeah, it's on my watch list.
It is close to making focus list,
but it's come a long way here.
It is set up.
If it stayed tight here, I'd probably put
it on.
But it was on the list that Mark and
Brandon actually gave me this morning.
Alex is asking if you can go over... well,
Mark Ritchie, can you go over why you
thought YPF buy, I think on January 2nd,
was not that great of a pivot?
Why didn't you consider that trade?
I'm trying to remember.
It's a little short, but that's probably
what I would have said.
I mean, in hindsight, it looks like it's
worked.
It's also in the oil, you know,
gas area.
So not my favorite.
But in terms of the strength, it's held up
really well.
Well, yeah, I mean, I wouldn't say it's a
bad pivot.
I mean, I think you got to put it into
perspective.
I think Mark was probably putting it more
into perspective.
I mean, the pivot is obviously tight.
I'm not sure.
Let's see here what kind of distance it is
to get to those lows.
Yeah, I mean, you know,
again, I think on the 1231 is
the day if you're interested
in, you know, you'd buy it.
But certainly, you know,
one, two was also... I don't
remember if I talked about
this at any time or not.
You had a big base here, too.
Take a look at this.
This is a really, you know, really good
VCP.
And this is, you know, just going into...
I'm going to a different segueing here.
But this is going back to the comment that
we had before about time compression.
You see right here, up here, this is a bit
compressed up this right side.
So you ran right up the right side and you
didn't really... you paused here a little
bit, but you didn't really build out that
right side.
And then now you build here.
Now, this is actually getting to where
this is buyable if it comes out.
But it comes in, you get another shakeout,
runs up a bit.
And now you see you're setting up at a
higher price, but you've gone through all
that price action and
you really built a good size
base with a number of
iterations of tightening.
And that's where you see you have this
first one here, come down here about 35%.
And it's just... it's always classic.
Here, you're around, what, 14%,
14% or so.
And then finally, you tighten up here and
then you get a little bit tighter here.
And now you're looking at, you know,
I can't even see this.
It's... 6%, 7%.
Yeah, yeah, yeah.
Yeah, now you're getting into the,
you know, what I call the kill zone,
you know, where you're getting into the
single digit pivot.
Yeah, and just measuring again,
you know, where I was looking at it,
I think it was probably asked on one of
the Thursdays on January 2nd.
If you look, it's... the stock hadn't
quite doubled.
So it was in that power play S category,
only corrected for nine or 10 days.
So... and we're in a
period where trades
aren't... well, you're
going off that other low.
Yeah, yeah, I'm just looking from
different spots.
Yeah, last eight weeks now.
And I'm saying, if I'm going to trade an
eight, nine day, I want it to be really
perfect, and in an environment where
things are really working, you know,
so that's where, that's probably why I
downgraded a little bit.
Yeah, yeah.
The only way I would, the reason I would
downgrade it is because, you know,
this is not one that really came from a
period of dormancy.
It's already made a very big move,
and then it had this acceleration.
So, you know, it's likely to shake out.
But so far, you know, and again,
like NVIDIA, you could say, okay,
well, so far it's good, but it just didn't
really make much of a gain.
This could still fail.
Well, you know, I'm not, I'm looking at
these stocks that break out here and quote
unquote work as just, you know,
maybe short-term trades.
And for a short-term trade, you know,
this is fine.
Or was fine.
Question on ETR.
Joseph, this weekend looks like a decent
pivot, but it didn't make the focus list.
No, it's an energy name.
You've got this accelerated advanced here.
I don't like when you, when you
accelerated advanced like this on an
extended name, especially in a,
especially in any kind of cyclical,
deep cyclical, or, you know, even energy
name.
So, yes, it's got a pivot for a trade,
maybe.
Now, I'm not sure what this news was.
If this news was really,
really great and this pullback
was shallow, you know, I
might get interested in it.
But in this type of market,
I got to be careful with
those stocks that accelerate
and then have shorter bases.
The key is the acceleration and then the
short base.
They're just more failure prone to break
out and then experience more volatility,
especially in an energy type name.
But it could work.
I mean, this is certainly, you know,
setting up a pivot.
And it's, you know, there's definitely,
you know, VCP action here and it's viable.
Okay.
Roberto bought R-E-V-G, R-E-V-G,
on November 21st.
Yep.
Sold half on November 25th, a quarter on
December 16th.
And today he bought back a quarter and
moved the stop up to yesterday's low.
Can you evaluate his trade?
Today?
Yeah.
So, it seems like you love the pullback
buy.
You know, you bought the pullback buy.
You de-risked.
I mean, it's really, I think it's,
you know, you can, you know, we can always
go back and look and critique things and
see things we maybe could have done
differently on the, usually on the sell
side.
You know, we very seldom sell perfect.
But, you know, buy points are really good
coming off the pullback buys and you
de-risked it and took profits off the
table, sold into strength.
I mean, I think it's been managed very
well.
I mean, you clearly, you know,
get the shorter term trading.
Suleman is asking, I'm confused how to
analyze my year numbers.
His average gain was 5%.
His average stop is 2.8.
And he has a 20% batting average.
Can you explain how I should be using
these numbers?
Does the average loss mean that's the most
loss I should take on my trade?
Well, the average loss is what you are
taking.
So that doesn't mean what you should take.
That is what you are taking.
So... On average, not the max.
That's the average.
Right.
And then he's asking,
does the average gain
mean that's the amount
I should take profits at?
Well, no.
I mean, your average is looking backwards.
It's what you produce.
So if you were selling and
you had an average gain to
2%, it doesn't mean you
should be taking profits at 2%.
I think you're a little
confused about that, or at
least certainly I've confused
me about your question.
But the 20% batting average is the real
problem, obviously.
That's exceptionally, exceptionally low.
This question is, if
that batting average is
low, does it mean I have
to hold stocks longer?
I don't know.
We have to look at your trades and see
what you're doing.
I could never know that answer by you
telling me a batting average.
But it certainly means that your stock
selection is off, or the way you're
handling them is off, or
the market's really bad, and
you're trading in a market
that you shouldn't be trading in.
So that's what I can ascertain from a low
batting average.
But as far as how you're
handling the trades,
you have to look at
each individual chart.
And that's why we have TradeGrader.
That's where you should be going in,
putting all those trades into TradeGrader,
and grading them, and looking and seeing.
And in the beginning,
when you first start doing
this, you may not be
great at grading them.
You may grade them incorrectly
or you may have a lot to learn
about grading them because
you don't have that expertise.
But the way you get that
expertise is by practicing and
by doing that and by grading
them and by trading more.
And if you're not doing
well, then you trade
smaller and you trade
with smaller money.
Paper trading, I never advise paper
trading.
You're not going to make the same
decisions.
But you got to trade with some money.
But if you're not trading well,
then I wouldn't trade with all your money.
I would trade with a small amount that is
at least somewhat painful if you lose,
but not such an amount that it would hurt
you or change your life if you lost it.
And then build from there and just
practice with real money.
But yeah, if you give us actual examples,
then we can talk a little bit more
intelligently about the actual trades and
the decisions that you're making.
And that's where trade grader comes in.
And trade grader, who knows,
at some point with AI, maybe
someday we're able to get where
we can grade the trade grader.
We can have some function that we grade
your trades.
I know there's been suggestions of that.
Right now, it would be too
cumbersome for me to go and grade
everybody's trades and grade
thousands of people's trades.
But maybe with AI, we are programming AI
to look at things like I look at them.
And it's been very interesting
and very... I got a lot
of... I'm very excited about
that part of the platform.
Yeah.
And with some of the rollout of the new
platform, it's going to be even easier to
enter all this trade data into what
ultimately is your analytics to then be
able to do this
analysis and really crack
that down, which I
think will help everybody.
Yeah.
Our seamless integration, you're going to
be blown away with.
It's just incredible.
The portfolio management, everything,
just all integrates together.
And your portfolio, you automatically
close the trade.
It goes right into your analytics.
It's just been improved dramatically.
And we're going to be able to make more
improvements.
But when this next version
is... When I say it's a
giant leap, you're just
not even going to believe it.
Mm-hmm.
Kostas is asking... We're sharing.
He bought CRS this morning.
Yes.
CRS is actually on our watch list.
And it was... I mean, I probably should
have put it on this morning.
I didn't put it on.
But it was on our watch list or on deck
list for Focus.
And also, he's asking about SMTC.
Is there a question on CRS?
He's just sharing...
But your thoughts... Your
thoughts about that purchase
and then also on SMTC.
Yeah.
I mean, it's buyable.
You know, you definitely have a little
pivot developed here.
You know, it's a cheat... A little cheat
buy point.
So, yeah.
It's certainly buyable.
I don't know how... You know, how many of
these are going to hold.
I'd be quick probably to, you know,
reduce into strength and try to...
De-risk my trade as soon as possible.
What was the other symbol?
SMTC.
I mean, I'll just let you know, you know,
all I can do is tell you what I'm doing.
I'm not trading any longs here.
You know, I haven't bought anything.
And I'm just sitting back and waiting.
I'm going to let some pitches go by here.
Mark, you and Brandon, I haven't talked at
all about what you guys are doing.
I don't even know.
Yeah.
I don't know who to read on your trading
in probably a month.
Yeah.
No new buys either here.
Just sitting tight.
Yeah.
I mean, really, the Minervine
Select is pretty much a
representative of what we're
doing personally at this point.
You know, we're not... We're
just sitting back being patient.
And so the SMTC, yeah, I mean, this is,
you know, not, you know, really a big base.
It ran up.
This might have been earnings.
I'm not sure.
I think it was.
And, you know, small base now holding up.
It's holding up great in a weak market.
So, certainly, this is one, again,
that's one on my watch list.
Good.
Wilfred, new to the service.
Absolutely loving it.
Thank you for being on board.
Thank you for providing a phenomenal
training and helping me grow as a trader.
He's asking about GEV pivot near 368.
Yeah.
So, GEV, of course, is on focus.
Broke out here without a much of a pivot
on this right side.
So, you would have had to, you know,
put it on as a pullback buy.
And now you're getting that pullback,
filling the gap.
I mean, you see here, you're getting,
like, good close, good close, good close,
going inside.
This is acting really, really good.
As far as this, you know,
right here, that pullback action,
it seems like you're getting
a lot of supportive action.
So, again, you know, in this market,
I'd be careful.
We did clear that supply.
That's what I was nervous about.
If you remember, I talked
about this going through using
a pullback buy, but you were
going right into supply here.
And then it ripped through it.
And now you've pulled back.
And now the line of
most resistance, you know,
has turned into the
line of least resistance.
And now what needs to make sense is,
does it hold that?
Now, does it hold?
If this stock is really strong,
yeah, a pullback buy should work here.
So, I mean, if this goes inside
one more day, you know, I
would say, you know, you
can easily buy that turning up.
A question from Jen is asking if you can
just explain the process to cover the SPY
short with the two conditions,
if you can just explain that more.
I don't really have a process
that I could tell you is some
mechanical process that I
know I'm going to cover the short.
Most of the time, believe it or not,
you know, I let the SPY come all the way
back and stop me out at
breakeven very often, unless it makes
a bike a big move and I get
a big profit for a small risk.
I mean, even now, it's a great trade.
I mean, I think we risked under 1%,
right?
Mark, we're like under 1% on that stop.
Yeah, I think it was like 90 basis points.
So let's call it 1%.
So it's basically, it's a 5R trade.
So we made five times our risk if you sold
it right here.
That's reason enough to sell.
But, you know, these shorts, you know,
they're more...
Sometimes I put them on myself and I
actually have my real money on there.
When I do, and I did this time,
usually I put a huge position on.
When I have risk that's 1%, I'm usually
putting on a very, very large position.
And because of that, then, you know,
like a 5% gain on a huge position,
then, you know, I'll very often take it or
take some of it off.
But as far as the platform's concerned,
you know, I want to see this, you know,
give a pretty big gain.
I'm going for, you know, a double-digit
gain.
You know, 8% to 10% would be nice.
You know, but I'm watching it.
I'm just going to watch it and I'm
going to punt it if it... Here's the thing.
Whenever I get into these shorts,
what I would really like to happen is the
short to stop me out, lose money on it,
and have stocks set up.
Like, I don't want to get the market right
on the downside, to be honest with you.
I mean, you know, look,
when I go into cash and I'm
short, obviously, we want
the market to go down.
But I don't want it to have such...
to have a break and make all this money on
the downside on one trade and sacrificing
now that it might take a year to rebuild
and build a base because we have this,
you know, a major bear market or years
before I get an opportunity to trade
individual stocks because I'm going to
make way more money trading individual
stocks in a bull market than I am getting
the market right and calling the top.
That's why calling tops and bottoms is not
worth the effort.
You know, the real money is going to be
made in your trading throughout a market,
a bull market that lasts for a number of
years.
And you've got, you
know, set up after set up
after set up and you're
turning that money over.
So I don't... I look at this as almost
recreation.
Let's just put it that way.
With real money.
Okay.
Question for Mark.
I believe I've read on X, you personally
had a very... They're both Mark, by the way.
Yeah.
M, M, M.
Okay.
If you had a very good year in 24, did
you change tactics compared to the MTP?
Would you say your approach in 24 was
similar to what you followed in 2021?
Yeah, yeah.
I mean, I took what I could get,
especially, you know, as the end of the
year went and it was getting more
difficult.
You know, I mean, pretty much any market,
I can turn a profit.
You know, I can figure out a way.
May not be the best thing to, you know,
if I shift gears and make rapid shifts in
the way I trade to, you know, to teach
that because a lot of that is intuitive.
And there's, again, there's a lot of
shifting gears, but I think, you know,
the main gear that you need to shift to go
from, to make an adjustment for the
environment is just simply where you're
stopping and where you're taking profits.
I mean, I wouldn't change anything.
I never change anything as far as the buy
points.
Like, I'm not buying stocks from different
chart patterns or different buy.
I'm buying from the exact same buy points
as that we're putting on here.
The only difference is, is whether I stop
out quicker and truncate my loss and how
quickly I sell, whether I'm taking,
you know, a shorter term profit and
selling into that first move up,
you know, or that first leg up,
or if I'm, you know, what that risk reward
ratio is.
And that's all I'm trying to
do is just always keep that
risk reward ratio positive,
even if it's microscopic.
Even if my average gain
was 3%, you know, then
I'd have to keep my loss
at, you know, one or two.
So yeah, that's the shift, you know.
But the answer is, yeah, you know,
I'm always shifting.
I'm always, you know,
moving to whatever I
think is the best tactic
for the environment.
And that's what we talk about in my notes
and in the weekend sessions and these
study sessions, I give you
that color of, you know, what
the environment is and how I
think you should approach it.
And then we put, you know, the very,
you know, very strict, you know,
criteria on as buys.
But there's, you know, there's a lot of
decisions that are made around that,
that are intuitive and are subjective to
your own risk tolerance and style.
David has a question that I'm going to try
to simplify.
As much as I can, as it's a bit lengthy,
but referring to the NVIDIA breakout on
January 3rd, although he typed January
8th, I think he meant January 3rd.
He also traded the breakout, but he did
not have prior traction.
So he had to take a 5% pilot buy.
I also sold way too early at about 5%
profit.
As the setup was textbook perfect.
How can I have made a bigger gain on that
breakout?
Taking a bigger position, despite not
having traction, holding the position for
longer, despite my prior average gain
being only about 5% and understanding that
there are, there is only a few leaders
that I should only trade.
Should I only trade this?
I think you answered all your own
questions.
I mean, obviously to make
more money, you'd have
to have a bigger position
or have a bigger gain.
So, I mean, we sold it up 8%, Mark.
Yeah, I've also reduced it.
Yeah, reduced it into that gap.
I would push back, though, saying this was
not a perfect setup.
No, it's not a perfect setup.
And this was a little
sloppy and it was
getting pretty obvious,
which is what we said.
And we de-risked it pretty quickly,
thinking this may happen.
Yeah.
I said that this stock is not a winning
trade yet, that you can say this has worked.
It could still fail.
And sure enough, it was the next day,
I think.
And we had that big distribution day and
now we've come all the way back down.
But this is why we would de-risk into this
type of market and de-risk that run-up of
the right side that is a
form of a shorter-term
timeframe, but that's a
form of time compression.
So, we only sold one day probably later
than you.
Because if you said you took a 5% or maybe
you sold on that day around the lows,
I'm not sure, right on the gap,
we only sold a day later.
So, we didn't really handle it much
differently than you did.
So, I wouldn't be too hard on yourself.
Another question, which he's not sure if
you can answer, but he's observed the
price of beef breaking out of a 65-week
base.
Do you think these prices will be
reflected in the stock of food providers,
producers, grocers,
and restaurants and that
it could lead to them
breaking out as well?
I mean, that's interesting.
I don't really follow commodities.
That one time I did.
I know Mark follows them a little bit,
but I don't know.
Do you have any... That's a
question for... What's his name there?
Our buddy... Peter Brandt.
Yeah, for Peter Brandt.
I'm sure Peter Brandt knows about that.
I don't really follow the meat markets
either, other than the fact that I'm
participating in those as I'm a father of
five.
But the other thing I would just add is to
Mark's comment earlier.
You know, we don't need to know that
stuff.
If that's going to impact the
earnings of a specific stock or
company, we're going to see
that as we go through the process.
That's the whole beauty of this.
You don't have to reverse engineer.
You just trade what you see in front of
you.
Yeah, that, you know, trying to forecast
and get these heads up.
I mean, when we look back at the study of
the biggest winning stocks, 70 to 80% of
them already had the earnings on the
table.
You know, the evidence was already there
before they made the big moves.
So you really, we like to have the goods
before we go in.
Well, and looking at Gio, Mark, from
Focus today is a good example of this.
You know, I don't, I was looking into this
a little bit, but if you look at that
name, that showed up on our radar two or
three weeks ago.
Well, this stock clearly stands to gain,
you know, potentially from some of the
things going on, but you're seeing it in
the price.
We weren't buying, we're not buying the
stock because we like the story.
We stay away from a stock because it
doesn't have a story or has a,
maybe a bad story.
Sometimes you have a horrible story and
the stock's acting great.
And that tells me that I actually like
that scenario because that tells me,
you know, it's able to rally in the face
of bad news.
So, you know, that was, that was the case
with, what was the company?
W.R.
Grace, when they had the asbestos claims
against them and so forth.
And then the stock set up and,
you know, it was a huge winner for me.
I mean, a hundred and some odd percent in
just a few weeks or a few months, a month.
But yeah, I like this geo.
It's acting really well.
You broke out.
You got a pullback here.
It looks pretty natural.
You know, you could look,
if you didn't buy this, you
could look for some type
of pullback, buy the setup.
One of the better looking, one of the
better looking names here.
I meant to just go back real quick with
that SPY question that Jen was asking
about to understand the conditions B for
covering is the SPY, which is an ETF
representing the S&P 500, but it's not the
actual S&P 500.
That stop that is posted on the platform
needs to trigger.
In addition to the S&P 500
index, what Mark is referencing,
the cash index is also
hitting an all-time high.
So both of those conditions need to be
triggered.
I think that's what he was trying to get.
And what would usually happen is you might
get the ETF.
You know, maybe you get a little slippage
because of that.
So it goes and hits the stop.
Let's just call it par 100.
And it hits it at 100.
And then the cash index hits an all-time
high, you know, a day or two later.
And now the ETF is at, you know,
150 or 101.
And you lose a half a percent or a
percent.
That can happen.
But it's a trade-off for, you know,
the insurance that it actually is,
you know, the index is hitting a new high.
They're both hitting new highs.
I just found that I get shaken out less if
I do it that way.
And it's worth the little bit of extra, you
know, a little bit of extra slippage risk.
Yeah.
They're very close often,
but just a little bit is what
provides that confirmation
that Mark is looking for.
Yeah.
To not get head faked out or wiggled out,
sometimes that happens.
And at this point, I mean, being at a
profit and having a 5X, you know,
5R profit, generally, I
mean, I would never let,
you know, a stock come
back and stop me out.
But because it's an ETF and the stop is so
tight, I mean, if you let this go and all
they stop you out, once again,
it's under 1%.
So I might just, you know,
stick with the stop if I was
playing it for a bigger move,
let it come all the way back.
But generally, if that stop was bigger,
let's just say that stop was 5%,
I would definitely be moving to a break
even now.
Yeah.
Abdul Raham is asking about AORT.
Is this a potential candidate?
AORT.
Yeah, it's a good size base.
You know, I think the right side needs to
develop a little more.
You might get a pullback buy setup.
You know, these pullback buys going into
some supply, I'm real careful with those
in a market and I'm just looking,
this did come up on my watch list.
So it is on watch.
I'm going to actually move that up a
little bit.
Pullback now.
You know, in this type of market,
you know, I'd be a little more careful and
I certainly would only be starting a
position on a pullback buy like this.
Maybe you start with a quarter or half of
your position and then if it can build out
a bit more and maybe set up another pivot,
you add to it if it pivots from there.
But yeah, I mean,
it looks, it's a decent
size base and it's
holding up relatively well.
All right.
Ravi's asking for SEI.
Did January 10th look like a decent spot
to enter a pullback buy?
Yeah, so SEI is on my watch list here.
It was one that was setting up.
I think we had it right over here.
I think we had it on focus list.
It broke out and now it's
come in a bit here and it hasn't
completely failed but it's not
acting, you know, fantastic.
So it looks like it needs a little bit
more work.
If it comes off from here, if I was in it,
I would definitely punt it, you know,
below.
And this is where you're going to get
shaken out anyway.
2764 is the obvious, you
know, common area that
you're probably going
to have stops grouped.
So, but yeah, I wouldn't give this much
more room on the downside.
And then even if it, you know,
if I didn't own it, I might wait to see if
it can hold up and give me another buy
point.
But what was the actual question?
I don't remember what the... If
January 10th was the buy point?
Yeah, oh, 10th, yeah, January 10th.
I wouldn't have bought it there but I see
what you're doing on that pullback buy.
I don't think it's a bad buy because you
got that pullback, a little reversal,
the pullback buy, you're really close to
about 4% from that low.
It's fairly low risk.
So I see what you're doing.
I don't think that's a bad buy.
I just wouldn't stick around long.
If it doesn't work, you know, just get out
and wait, wait, wait, reset.
And he's asking, what do you think of the
base and Reddit, the power play and Reddit?
Yeah, you know, I don't like when they
come back to the 50-day on a power play.
That's usually a sign
of weakness, but maybe
in a correcting type
market, we can allow that.
This has gone up quite a bit.
This is a primary base
that has morphed into
a power play, which I
love when that happens.
It's very strong.
Obviously, this doesn't
have any right-side
development right now,
so there's no pivot here.
Would the break of the January
9th be a good start, a good
spot to start a position if it
did not collapse on Friday?
If it did not collapse?
There is no January 9th.
January 9th was a weekend.
No, no.
So, you said January 9th.
Yeah, that's weird.
Then that's missing data.
The 10th was Friday.
Thursday, the markets were closed.
That's why the 9th...
Not missing data.
No, the 9th was when
the markets were closed
for the holiday, so
he must be in the 8th.
Yeah.
So, a move above there?
Yeah, as he's asking, would that be a good
spot to start a position?
I mean, it would have,
if it went inside and took
out the high, you would
have gotten a pullback buy.
And I would say that's where, if you
wanted to own this, it broke out,
it pulled back, and that's right where it
should catch support.
Now, you've got one, two, or this low.
I mean, these are the areas
right here where you need
to get support or it
starts to trigger violations.
If you bring this up in Monalert,
you put the Monalert overlay on this,
you'll see that you're going to start
triggering some violations here.
You're below the 20-day.
You're now on your 4th lower low, so you're
starting to pick up a couple violations.
Yep.
Other than that, that would have been the
spot, yes.
Yeah, 98 and triple green across the
board.
With an 8 rating, obviously.
Does CRDO look like a power play to you?
If so, does the sub appear too volatile?
CRDO.
Yeah, CRDO is on my watch list.
In the morning, I watched it.
It was, you know, gapping down here,
so I didn't put it on.
So now, it's not staying tight,
but this is one also that ran up,
had that accelerated advance.
The difference here is that this,
and I believe that this data is correct,
that this was an IPO here.
It wasn't, yeah.
It was or was not?
Was.
Was is a newer idea, yeah.
Right.
So I like the fact that this is still
early.
So you get this accelerated advance,
but this is a stock that came out of a big
base that was an IPO base and making its
first leg up here.
So I would look at this
as, you know, potentially
a very early part of
the maturation cycle.
So if this tightens up here, this will
definitely go on focus.
Okay.
Stocks that were in recent new issues and
make all time highs and then set up,
whether regardless of the setup,
whether it's a power play, it's just a
simple, you know, VCP, a larger base,
they should always be considered.
That's a really, you know, great sign that
it's making an all-time high.
This goes all the way back to Livermore.
If you go read Livermore's book,
How to Trade in Stocks, it's a small book,
only about 100 pages.
He talks about this
and it was, it worked, it's
the same reasoning today
than it was in the 1920s.
Tal was also asking about Reddit,
so there you go, Tal, for your question.
Tamlin is asking, Mark, if Wix and Pega,
both on focus list, are not seemingly
extended from prior bases and not powerful
enough to be a power play.
Let's try to understand why they are both
on focus list.
Oh, the stock is holding up tremendously.
I mean, we're correcting here and this
stock is right at the highs.
So, as far as a tradable idea,
if this tightens up and especially if the
market comes off here, I mean,
the market's under pressure right now.
So, let's just say the market came off for
a couple more days and came down to that
200-day or, you know, was down 2%,
3%, 4% over a number of days this week and
this just stayed tight,
well, then, you know,
this strength is really,
really compelling.
So, and it hasn't made, you know,
a move that is so big, it's, well,
actually, you know, I have
a big correction here, but
that, you know, I would say
that it's severely late stage.
When I look at those moves, I don't look
at it necessarily percentage-wise.
I just look at how the number
of bases and how much
what it's done since it
went into a stage 2 uptrend.
So, right here is where it starts a new
stage 2 uptrend.
So, this base wasn't really buyable.
That's about as time compression as you
get.
Ran straight up the right side.
And then the price that had to be paid for
that was some consolidation.
Then we came out of a
base and now you're going
into a correction and
it's holding up really well.
So, this is one that, you know, broke out
right into the correction and is holding.
So, this is acting like a leader and
giving signs that it wants to go higher.
And Pega announces us.
Yeah, let me get
Pega is definitely weaker.
You know, I've been looking at Pega ever
since back here.
You remember it had that IPO or not IPO,
you had that good-sized base here.
It was trying to tighten up and never did.
It shook out and it just went all over the
place.
But then right here, it
actually got quite constructive,
but then it collapsed
I think before earning.
So, it's just too much volatility.
It was just a bucking bronco.
Now, you know, this is one if it stayed
tight, but it did not.
It did not stay tight.
This morning, it gapped down a little bit.
It didn't look like this in the morning.
If it looked like this, right
off the hop, I wouldn't have
put it on the list because
now it's sort of breaking apart.
You are going to the 50
days, so some people will say,
the first pullback to the
50 after a base breakout.
I'd like to see it set up and tighten up
more.
So, right now, if you're
saying Pega doesn't
look optimal right
now, I agree with you.
Not sure, Mark, if you can go to your
other screen where you show the intraday,
but Leaf was asking on
GEV on Friday, it looked
like it had a very nice
VCP on a five-minute chart.
He's just trying to understand.
I don't really want to get into intraday
charts.
I don't trade off intraday charts.
So, all I'll tell you is
this, is that you'll see the
same thing and intraday
charts will tend to occur.
You're going to get basing and you're
going to get pivot points and low cheats
and cheats and handles and
BCP action and everything you see
on intraday you'll see on
daily and you'll see on weeklies.
I'm not trading off of intraday charts.
Even when I make a short-term trade,
I'm always trading off the daily.
Now, there's a concept of time alignment,
have all the time frames aligned.
I got to take this.
Let's give me one second here.
Go ahead.
Take over there.
I'll just add, Bob Weissman
trades on the five minute more
than Mark or I saw he probably
want to answer that question.
I was just going to reiterate what Mark is
going to which is to say these principles
do work on all time frames and obviously
our separate methodology
weeks to even a couple months but for more
seasoned members and our traders who you
will find as Mark is saying even when
trading the shorter term time frames we're
still operating off of a swing trading set
up and criteria so having the names on the
focus list based on a daily chart and
weekly chart is what we're looking for if
you're just purely looking at 8,000 stocks
on 5-minute chart basis you're going to
find probably a thousand different options
how do you filter down the best of
In the breakout.
And that happens.
That can happen.
And if you're like Bob
Weissman, you have 97
charts up on your
screen, you might see that.
I don't do that.
I don't really... I mean, I
do have a five minute...
I'll show you what
I'm normally looking at.
I am normally looking at... Whoops.
Not there.
Let me get out of here.
Sorry about that.
Let me just go down here.
This is what I'm looking at throughout the
day.
And so I do have an... I have a five
minute down here.
So I am aware of it.
Like I'm aware of what's going on there.
And it's just to see like volume.
If the stock's moving big, I like to see
is there volume at that time?
Because I can't tell that from a chart
here to know where the volume is.
The volume might be picking up.
See right here today, that volume is very
low.
But all of a sudden, I
might see it picking up really
big on that five minute
bar as it's breaking out.
So I just have a level two and I have the
five minute.
So I am aware of the five minute.
If I see the five minute, it's setting up
and it's breaking out here.
Great.
I mean, that's wonderful.
But it doesn't mean
that I'm not going to
buy it if the five-minute
doesn't look great.
And so you can really...
you start time fishing
and, you know, a
couple things can happen.
One, you start rationalizing yourself into
a trade.
So you're like, well, it looks good on the
weekly.
It looks like crap on the intraday and the
daily, but it looks good on the weekly.
I don't like that at all.
And then the other thing is, if you wait
for every timeframe to line up,
you're going to miss
a ton of stocks that are
fine because it didn't
line up on the five-minute.
When most stocks
are not going to line up
perfectly on the five-minute
with the daily setup.
Yep.
All right.
Rahul is asking if you
could just, first off,
thanking you for a wonderful
product and service.
Much appreciated.
Here are his results.
Yeah, again, well, just to interrupt for
one second.
I just want to say once again,
and you heard me say this over and I'm
really like setting the bar high here,
but if you think that this product is
good, is even good, you're going to be
blown away.
I can't wait for you guys to see the new
platform.
And even what we're going
to show you this week is only a,
you know, we're not even
anywhere near where it's going to be.
And it's already beyond my wildest dreams.
So it's fantastic.
It's such another level.
So I just want to let everyone know if
you're happy with this in any shape or
form, the value is going to increase,
you know, tenfold.
But go ahead.
I'm sorry.
So Rahul is asking what should he focus on
next?
He had a 52% batting average for 2024,
average gain of just over 10%,
average loss just under 5%, 2.06 ratio and
adjusted.
That's 2.26 with a return per trade of
2.96%.
Okay.
105 trades.
So the question is, you want to manage
some of my money?
Yeah.
I mean, that's great.
That's perfect.
You know, I mean, you're
getting, you're making $2
for every dollar you risk
with a 50% batting average.
You should be doing fantastic.
And if you don't have
a big game, then that
means that it all came
down to position sizing.
And something to note with Rahul,
he's been with us for five years,
has been to the Master Trader program
twice.
And this is definitely the fruits of that
labor of delivery.
Are you as well coming to the gala?
I can try to tell you in one quick second.
Hopefully, we'll see at the gala.
I can't tell you right off the bat here.
That's okay.
You don't have to check.
But with that said, Rahul, what should you
be focusing on next, Mark?
Yeah, doing what you've been doing.
Consistent.
Yeah, and just optimizing it as best as
you can and really understanding why
you've had, you know, your wins and why
you've had your losses and the things that
may be the aberrations that
come around your trading
because there's some
aberrative, you know, action.
You might have maybe some big losses that,
you know, slipped through the cracks or
some times where you took profits and it
was very clear that you shouldn't have
been taking them, that the stock had done
nothing wrong.
Or maybe times where,
you know, you were
hesitant and you waited
longer than you should.
All that will be answered by using
TradeGrader and using Monalert.
By going in the TradeGrader, putting your
trades in there, and then looking at them
with the Monalert
overlay and with looking in
hindsight to see how
those decisions were made.
That's going to be your absolute best
teacher, and when you're starting from a
starting point and a reference point of
where you are, and a very solid,
you know, foundation of
good numbers, you're just,
you know, really the
sky's the limit for you.
You know, that's a great start.
And not that you've just started.
You've been at it for, you know,
obviously for five years with us.
Yep.
Question coming from Frank.
The strategy applied to MSP last year did
not work well, while some MPA members...
I will disagree with that statement,
but okay, go ahead.
I think it worked perfectly
as we designed, and
so I firmly disagree
with that, but go ahead.
I know you're looking at it from a
performance standpoint, but I disagree.
Go ahead.
While some MPA members did extremely well
with triple-digit returns, will you adjust
the strategy this year for the MSP
account?
I won't adjust anything, except I will do
exactly what I've been doing for 42 years.
So I don't know.
I don't know what you're asking me.
I mean, I'm not adjusting anything.
You know, my system has worked for 40
years, and I've amassed, you know,
tens of millions of dollars in wealth
using it, and so has Mark and Brandon.
We're not adjusting anything except the
adjustments that we make, and we know that
we should make according to our
discipline.
And we did that exactly with that
portfolio.
And if we started that portfolio,
you know, a fresh new portfolio,
and did exactly what we would do at any
other time, and the strategy worked
perfectly, because we had a drawdown,
I think, of a maximum of about 3%.
We did not participate in the upside,
because the ideas just weren't there.
It wasn't... we made any big, grave
mistakes.
It's just the trading environment wasn't
there.
If you look at the IBD-50,
it'll pretty much tell you
the whole, you know, the
whole answer right there.
Those... our style just wasn't in vogue.
And our goal is to, when the winds are not
blowing strong in our sail, to make sure
that we don't tip the boat over and
capsize.
And we did that flawlessly, flawlessly.
We had all kinds of problems
and ran into stop after stop
after stop, and never had
almost any volatility whatsoever.
I would... when I would so disagree,
I can't even put it into words.
But see, that's because
the average person is
looking at the result
to justify the means.
So obviously, if you didn't get it... and
that's like looking at a stock and saying,
you know, this stock, like right here,
this stock took off here.
So I should have bought this.
Obviously, I should have bought this here.
Well, no, it doesn't meet any of my
criteria.
There's huge volatility here.
Why would I buy this on this gap?
There's no pivot.
I can't look at it and say that it worked.
I mean, I can go look at anything in
hindsight, and there's a thousand stocks,
you know, this year that made a huge gain,
probably more than that, that made huge
gains off of arbitrary, you know,
price action that I could have never
predicted or had any kind of strategy to
apply to do it consistently.
So, yeah, we're only concerned with the
risk.
Now, we're not concerned because the S&P
is 10% ahead of us.
I've had quarters in months where I'm up
100% in one month, one quarter.
What do I care if the S&P is up 10% and
I'm flat?
But I do care if I'm down.
Okay, I do care if I'm not flat.
That's the real key.
If I'm down 10%, yes, that's a major
problem for me.
But if I'm flat and the S&P is up 20%,
I could care less.
It has absolutely zero influence on what
I'm going to do next.
And when you can get to that point,
you might have results like Mark Minervini.
Right.
The Andrew is asking about UI setting up.
UI.
Yeah, I mean, that's a really nice,
tight buy point.
I saw this stock, but this is
textbook acceleration short
base that I'm careful of,
especially in a tough market.
You can see here, I'll just show you and
see we're going on this direction.
And then we accelerate.
After a big move, it accelerates.
And then you've got a relatively short
base.
These are higher failure prone.
I got to really, really want to own the
company to trade this type of situation
because of this acceleration, this sort of
climactic move.
And it depends, too, how big this move is.
In this case, this stock went up about 50%
in maybe two or three weeks.
That's a climax move.
So you got to be real careful of buying
into climax moves.
This is where you exhaust the stock.
And even if it has a future life ahead of
it on the upside, a lot of times they'll
set up, they break out, and it looks
something like this.
Now, they break out.
They fail.
Maybe a couple of days later, they shake
out.
And then they come ripping back.
And then they hard away crossover.
And you've been knocked out.
And meanwhile, the stock works.
And you go back and say, well,
that Mark Minervini rule doesn't work.
Yeah, but the price that you would have
had to pay to get to that result.
See, that's the thing you always have to
understand.
What's the price?
Like, would you get on a bull that,
you know, you have the chance of him
bucking you off and stomping on you and
killing you, you know, versus,
you know, if I told you I have another
animal you could ride that's very docile.
And your goal, your goal is not to ride a,
you know, not to be a hero and ride this
aggressive bull, your goal is
to get on an animal and have
him ride you from one side
of the corral to the other.
Like, which one would you pick?
You know, I'm going to go on the docile
creature that gets me over there safely.
So that's the goal.
The goal is to get to the other side,
not have an ego and slay the dragon.
So, and, you know, hopefully, I know I
went, that's a pretty far stretch to make
this point, but hopefully it illustrated
it.
Alex is mentioning his current 8% average
gain, but with a low 30% batting average,
he calculated he would
need to take stops
of only 1.5% to maintain
a two to one ratio.
What do you do when
the required stop loss is
often too tight to give
names enough room to trade?
So, okay, great, great question,
by the way.
Excellent question.
And I'm going to give you an excellent
answer.
When you get to a point, all right,
this is sort of a general rule of thumb.
If you do calculate your numbers and it
comes back where, okay, I can adjust,
I'll just adjust my risk.
And it comes back and it says,
you have to have a 0.75 stop.
Well, that means that you're doing
something, well, maybe the market's just
bad and you aren't doing
anything wrong, but something's
wrong on the upside and
on the selection criteria.
You either have to increase your batting
average and have better selection criteria
or a better market environment,
or you're not taking big enough profits
because those stops are so tight that
now...
And I'm assuming we're applying this to a
swing strategy.
If you're doing day trading, well,
then that would be a different story.
But swing trading, and
it comes back where you
need a 1% stop, the
stop isn't the problem now.
The issue is the environment with the
batting average or the average gain.
And you usually need to get better with
the average gain, have an environment that
allows you to have more average gain or
better selection criteria and to be maybe
in less names or more selective in the
names.
I don't know, Mark, does that bring anything
to light that you would think about?
Well, yeah, normally...
Honestly, I don't think I've ever given
that answer.
And all the tens of thousands of questions,
I think that's a really great question.
Well, it's a good question, too,
because it tells me that he's really
spending time looking at his metrics,
which is always a recipe for success,
generally speaking.
But yeah, to Mark's point, though,
if you get to a point where you realize I
have to be so tight, I don't think about
it in terms of...
It tells me that it's more likely to do
with the environment itself, meaning that
that win rate, given his current win rate,
he's coming to one or two conclusions.
I either have to get so
tight in order to make this
win rate work, or I need
to get my win rate up.
And I would say the win rate up is your
better solution in this case.
And you have no control over that.
Exactly.
So you can't... Which is going
to be based on the environment.
Right.
You can't control that.
And where you're going with this is,
okay, the thing I control is my...
And your thinking is absolutely perfect.
You know, the first thing you go to,
the first thing you go to is the stop.
So if your numbers are, you know,
your adjusted win-loss ratio is,
say, negative or very low, you say,
okay, well, I control the stop.
So that's the first thing you go to.
But I'm saying when that information
comes back and it says you need a 0.
5% stop, you've got a
bigger problem, okay,
that fixing the stop
isn't going to correct.
So I would say, and I'll give you another
general rule of thumb, if you can,
if it comes back where the range is,
say, 2%, 3% to 4%, 5%, 6% stop,
that's what you should try to back into.
Between a 2%, if you're really short-term,
2.5%, 3% stop, a little bit more,
you know, 3%, 4%, 5%,
average 4% to 6%, we'll call it
5%, you should be able to
make money with that stop-loss.
You shouldn't have to truncate it much more
unless you're really short-term trading.
If you're doing the short-term trades and
you're buying them, and as soon as they
break out, you're selling
right into the breakout, yes,
then you've got to come down
to the sub, the 2% and sub 2%.
So that, I mean, that's...
But I got to tell you, that
question just sparked, I
mean, the holy grail answer.
Really, everything I just said is
literally, that's what trading is about.
You could forget about charts,
earnings, everything.
If you understand that right there, you
could trade anything, and you're equipped.
You're equipped to manage risk versus
reward, and understand that relationship,
and how... and where you need to
prioritize, what you need to prioritize.
All right.
I do have to wrap it up.
I didn't realize.
I had a hard stop at 1230, and I went
over.
So I have to go.
Yeah.
All right.
So we will call it for this session now.
And with that said, I'm not sure if Mark
and Brandon are actually traveling on
Thursday, so I don't think we're going to
have a Q&A session later this week.
I'll verify that.
And it will be posted on the platform
accordingly, guys.
But do stay tuned to the
live stream for real-time
alerts throughout the
remainder of the week.
We do have earnings season starting,
I believe, in earnest next week.
None of our two remaining
positions have earnings,
and we're not having
any concern with that.
And once again, the replay of this will be
presented and uploaded here momentarily.
And looking forward to seeing
everybody who is coming to
the gala in just a few days
this Saturday and Sunday night.
We will see many of you.
We will see many of you very soon.
Yep.
And many of you.
We're looking forward to it.
I'm looking forward to seeing all of you
and meeting you.
Yep.
To celebrate Mark's 60th birthday party
Sunday night as well.
So that will be a great event.
And the following Monday, just as a quick
heads up, the market is closed.
For Martin Luther King's birthday...
So we get to recover from the party.
Just for that recovery of the party.
It's open bar, so you can...
The stock market closed in honor of Mark's
birthday party.
And obviously, we'll have next week's Q&A
on Tuesday.
Of course, this will all be posted on the
platform as well.
Okay, great.
Yeah, we'll talk to you guys later.
With that said, thank you, Mark and Mark,
for your time.
And we'll get back at it soon.
Bye-bye.