Okay, hello everyone.
Welcome to this week's Intervening on the
Market Weekly Report, January 5th,
2024, starting the new year.
I just want to point
out real quick, we do
have the two events
coming up in Myrtle Beach.
And the reason why I'm
pointing this out is because, first
of all, they're coming up
soon, January 18th and 19th.
But we are going to be closing registration
for the gala and for the birthday party.
We need to tidy things
up and get the list
closed and start
preparing for these events.
So you need to make... if you're coming,
you need to register very quickly.
I'm not sure exactly when
we're closing registration,
but it's probably sometime
by the end of the week.
We will also be unveiling the Intervening
Markets 360 platform.
That's going to be the
platform that you will be
grandfathered into if
you are a current member.
And it will eventually roll over into this
platform.
We're not sure exactly
when that's going to happen
after it debuts on
January 18th at the gala.
But fairly soon after, maybe within weeks
to a month or so.
But we'll see where we are at that point.
We're still making some tweaks on it.
And we will be making tweaks for some time
to come.
We have lots of things
planned, even though the current
version that I've been
playing with lately is amazing.
We've got a lot more things planned,
and it's just the tip of the iceberg.
So register soon, and we'll see you soon
in Myrtle Beach.
I will see you.
Key components of market health.
Major indexes are negative.
Up-down volume.
You may think this is strange that it's
positive, and I'm going to talk about
distribution-dominant and not really any
accumulation in the averages.
But this is a little bit different
formula.
This is a moving average
formula that we use
on the New York Stock
Exchange and the NASDAQ.
So not exactly the same, but I will be
doing the analysis in just a second on the
individual, the daily work on the NASDAQ
and the NYSE.
New highs, new lows, negative.
Individual stock participation,
also negative.
Basically, we've got a picture here when
we look at the components and we look at
the STEM model, which is basically
assessing the individual stocks.
We've got a very difficult environment
right now, and maybe some stocks work,
and there are a few stocks breaking out,
of course.
NVIDIA, we added going with the leader.
TSM also, we didn't add that
as an open position, but it was
trying to break out on Friday
and looks pretty constructive.
But there's just not a lot of ideas.
And when there's not a
lot of ideas, we're definitely
going to be at the very best
at the cautious exposure.
But I think with all things
taken into consideration, hard
penny is definitely the correct
rating right now, if you will.
So SPY advisor models, now they're still
on buy signals because they're long-term
trend-oriented, and they are going to take
more downside to trigger.
And we didn't really come off that much
off the highs on the SPY.
But I do think they're at risk,
I think, of raising cash.
I don't think an outright buy signal,
I'm sorry, sell signal is in the cards in
the near future, unless we had a pretty
big decline.
But I think we are close.
So I just look at the individual models,
and I can't always tell.
But it looks like a few of them are close
to maybe hitting a sell signal,
which would raise maybe 25% to 50%,
maybe cash.
Again, looking at those, those are very
long-term oriented.
This is the 33 model, currently on the buy
signal.
Interest rate environment has been pretty
stable, and that's good.
We want to see interest rates stay pretty,
you know, relatively stable here.
If they spike up much, you know,
that's a sign of inflation.
If they plummet, that's a sign of
recession.
So again, you know, looking at the rates,
and I look at the one year, that's giving
us an indication of
whether we're going to be
able to persist with
this Goldilocks economy.
I mean, that's really important for a
continued bull market.
But within an uptrend and within a bull
market, even the strongest bull markets,
you have corrections.
And usually what happens
is you get sentiment that
gets very bullish, and
there's a lot of overinvestment.
And then the market needs
to pull back and cool that froth
off, and that's where it
looks like we're at right now.
The bullish advisors are coming in,
the investors' intelligence.
But they're not down to levels that would
be consistent with a bottom and a pullback.
What I also look at is the
combinations of the ratios,
and we take the bulls
divided by bulls and bears.
We're pretty frothy, and
we've been frothy up there
a few times for the
better part of a year or so.
Similar to if you go back to
2021 or into 2021 going to 22,
where we stayed up in those
frothy levels around that 80%.
And the market went a bit higher,
but then topped.
So looking at the sentiment,
definitely, you know, this is
limiting the upside somewhat
if you base it just on this.
The real problem is, of course,
is the distribution in the market.
And prior to us even seeing this heavy
distribution, I had shorted and was
getting sort of smelling the winds,
changing here, if you will.
Shorted on 12.9, still short with a stop
at an all-time high in the SPY.
Anyway, the Dow was the
one that came off more, so the
DIA would have been the
better short, as I pointed out.
Also, the NYA, the New York
Stock Exchange Composite, sorry
about that, has come off, you
know, more percentage-wise.
Taking a look here, though, if you look at
the volume, you can see that we're really,
again, still distribution dominant.
Now, around the holiday, you're going to
see lower volume, but even in those lower
volume registers there, you don't see much
in the way of any accumulation volume.
So it's all selling volume, churning days.
You look at the NASDAQ, it's not much
different, except we didn't come off as much.
And that's why I'm wondering if this
50-day is going to hold.
I don't think it's going to.
I think we're going to have to come in a
bit more.
We just need to see
some accumulation and see
setups before we can
jump into this market.
And jumping into a market that's under
distribution, that has no setups,
you know, in my experience, has not turned
out to be a smart decision.
If you go back and you take a look,
in the top, this top chart here is the
SPY, the SP500, going back to that 2021,
going to 22 top, where I actually shorted
the market right here where this red line
is.
And we had a head fake, and it went into
new high ground.
I got stopped.
And the mistake that I made there was not
re-shorting.
And you can see, too, if
you look at the Minervini
indicators, that's where
they actually turned red there.
I was shorting when we were still green on
the TPR.
Similar to, if you come
down here, this is the
current SPY, and this is
where I just shorted on 12.9.
Similar situation where I shorted when we
were green still, and then we started
getting that mixed picture where we went
yellow, green, red.
Same thing here, I shorted, then we went
But back then, like I said, we went back
into new high ground and got stopped there.
Now, if you look at the
NASDAQ, the NASDAQ topped
over here and did not
go into new high ground.
So it kept rolling over.
And that was really the
key, I think, the key sign
that I should have
re-shorted as we rolled over.
That was, if I grade that and look back,
that was a mistake that I think I made of
not getting, putting a trade on that
seemed pretty obvious at the time.
This is where we had a lot of divergence
and a lot of participation problems.
And again, similar to now, we've got some
divergences and participation problems.
If we just take a look also at the IBD
Mutual Fund Index, I pointed this out last
week, big, big down week, crashing through
the 200-day or the 40-week moving average,
continuing down, a very feeble rally.
You can see that was a very small rally
week.
And then continuing to the downside,
this is definitely not what I want to see.
So again, putting this all together,
I think we're in a market that's...
we definitely got to respect
the weight of evidence here.
Again, sentiment.
It's another chart of the sentiment.
We just looked at it.
Same thing.
Let me just... Okay,
sorry about that.
I want to go to this.
You know, that change
from the bulls to the bearer
sentiment, where we look at
it from a contrary standpoint.
I want to see the put volume also start to
rise.
You know, there's what
people do, and there's
what people say, and
I like to look at both.
I like to get them in agreement.
That's where you really get that really
strong bearer sentiment or even bullish
sentiment is when you get both in
agreement.
In this case, I'd like
to see the put volume
spiking with a lot of
bearishness coming back in.
But we're nowhere near that right now.
At least, you know, that's not what we're
seeing currently.
And we've got volatility.
And that's the real problem.
The volatility, you know, if you've got it
in the VIX, that's one thing.
And I'm definitely going
to look at that and say, hey,
okay, this is a market that
I may have to respect here.
But sometimes you don't get it in the
individual stocks.
And in your area that
you traffic in, maybe the
type of names, you
don't get the volatility.
In this case, you know,
we're getting some,
not crazy volatility in
the individual stocks.
So it's not as prevalent, but it may start
to leak over there.
And the real problem is there's just not a
lot of setups.
There's not a lot of stocks that are set
up in viable position.
So market is definitely still under
pressure.
That recent rally has come on low volume.
And we really got to wait.
Just got to wait for confirmation.
Even if the market index
is, let's say the S&P was
to rally from here and
go into new high ground.
That's going to catch some headlines.
But, and this, of course, is spelt wrong.
A follow-trow day, through day.
You know, that would definitely,
you know, maybe look good on paper.
But you really got to look at the
individual stocks.
We're distribution dominant.
And if we got a follow-through day,
even if we get some type of follow-through
in the market, and even if you hit new
highs, if you've got an elevated
volatility and there's not many stocks,
you still got to be careful.
So I would really just go right to the
stocks and look for the setups.
And even the sentiment and all these
other, you know, tea leaves, if you will,
if we had a lot of setups
and they were working,
we'd definitely be in
the market buying stocks.
S&P, like I said, the model is at risk to
go into cash.
So I would be prepared to maybe raise some
cash here.
If this market starts selling off more,
we're going to definitely want,
if you're in the SPY and you're following
our lead or our model to trade your 401ks,
maybe your longer term
IRA money, we're going to
want to raise cash if that
model says to raise cash.
And I've even suggested to raise some cash
even prior to that.
In the last couple of weeks, I pointed
out, you know, raising 25, maybe 50% cash.
I still think that's a good idea right
here, even on this rally back,
because you're coming closer to the danger
point.
If you haven't already
lightened up, now that you're
coming back up near new
highs, very close to that stop.
And if that stop were to trigger,
you know, I would be maybe willing to
even, you know, put that money back to
work.
We'd have to see what the circumstances
were.
But right now, I think it's a good time to
pull some chips off the table there.
That's about it.
Setups, discipline, we've got to wait.
Stock work, there's
not a whole lot to show,
but we'll put what we
have on a focus list.
And hope you had a great weekend.
And I'll see you tomorrow for live Q&A at
1130 a.m.
Eastern Time with myself, Bob Weissman,
and Mark Ritchie.
Bob is back from vacation.
All right.
Have a good rest of the night,
and I'll see you soon.
Bye-bye.