Okay, good morning and welcome to the
Minervini Private Access Training Room.
I'm Bob Weissman.
If you can raise your hand, let me know
that you're hearing me loud and clear.
Hope everybody had a happy new year and
enjoyed the holiday.
Let's also welcome Mark Ritchie into the
room.
Good morning, Mark.
Morning, Bob.
Morning, everybody.
Happy 2025 again.
For those who weren't there Thursday,
good to be back.
Yep.
Glad to have you.
And if you could just raise your hand.
I'm not seeing a lot of hands raised.
Okay, now I am.
Excellent.
And finally, let's get started
with kicking off 2025's
question and answer
sessions with Mark Minervini.
Take it away, Mark.
Hello, everyone.
Good morning.
I hope you had a great weekend.
Real quick couple things.
First of all, we are going
to be closing registration
very soon for the gala
and for the birthday party.
So if you haven't registered, that window
is going to be shutting very soon.
So I would suggest that you do that no
later than maybe today or tomorrow.
Let's see what else.
The market rallying here a bit.
The S&P rallying here is not surprising to
me, as I pointed out over the weekend.
Again, like we saw back in
2021, the 2021-22 top, we rolled
over on the S &P, but went
back into new high ground.
The Nasdaq diverged and did not go back
into new high ground.
And that was the top.
It went to a bear market.
I'm not expecting a bear market here.
That's not... And then again, what I
expect doesn't really matter.
We're just going to bend with the weight
of evidence.
But again, I could very easily see either
this failing and going lower or maybe even
moving back to the highs and
then maybe rolling over from
there, maybe going into the
inauguration, post-inauguration.
My initial was... initial sort of zone
that I was thinking would be the area I
want to get through
was the beginning of the
year, which so far that
hasn't been a disaster.
And then going up to the presidential
inauguration, which is one day after...
is the next day after my
birthday party, which is
on the Monday, which
is Martin Luther King Day.
Let's see.
So we did add NVIDIA, which is blasting
off here.
And this has just taken a little bit of
exposure.
There's not a lot of stock setups.
There's a few here and there.
PLNT is trying to break out today.
You know, a couple, maybe Burlington here.
We can keep an eye on this.
I'd like to see it maybe tighten up a
little bit more there.
What else?
Actually, this SEI is up about 6% now.
So it is moving out of a power play.
And then TSM, of course, time on
semiconductor.
This is one that I really wanted to own.
The only spot you really got to buy it here
was this pullback buy on an outside day.
I was hoping it tightened up a bit,
held up in a weak market.
And then I was going to be able to buy it
coming out.
But it just got away from us.
That would have been the other one that I
would have liked to have owned here.
But just not a very big list here.
There's a couple.
PDEX is blasting off here today.
This is one that I had on my watch list.
It was going to put it on focus.
But it gapped.
And now it's just, you know, gap and gone.
So you're seeing a lot of that.
I think Bitcoin...
I don't know, Mark, what are you thinking
about Bitcoin here?
But I was looking at this as a potential
power play, hoping it tightened up.
But it's running up the right side.
So, yeah.
I mean, you know, you just have a lot of,
you know, a lot of action here that's sort
of volatile and not able to really come
out of solid bases.
Not a lot of setups.
So, you know, we might rally here.
You just got to be patient and just wait
for the setups to come to you.
I don't know if you have anything to add,
Mark.
No, I think you pretty much summarized it
pretty well as usual.
But, you know, even this Bitcoin example,
you know, this is one I was hoping we
might get at some type of cheat or low
cheat.
It didn't fully form there.
But, you know, maybe we get some softness
in the market.
And then that's where it allows us to see
where's the real relative strength.
Because this really just needs to put in,
you know, either a better pivot or a whole
other base, which is just going to take a
little bit of time.
Yeah.
And some of you may be thinking,
well, if they're all taken off,
you know, going up the right side,
why not just buy them?
Well, first of all, you know, we don't
know which ones are going to do that.
And that's all after the fact.
And there's not a whole lot of names.
You know, really aren't a whole lot of
names.
And even if there were, let's just say
there was a whole big list of names and
they're all taken off up the right side
without coming through pivots.
Well, no, we wouldn't chase them.
We wouldn't change our tactics because we
still got to manage the risk.
And that's the main thing.
And sometimes you just have a market
environment that just doesn't allow you to
get on board the elevator on the floor
that you want to get on.
And you've got to wait.
You've got to wait for another stop.
And you've got to wait for things to set
up.
And it might be at a higher price.
But that's, like I always say,
you're not looking for the lowest price.
You're looking for the right price.
So, let's see.
This is classic action, though,
you know, pullback correction.
Very classic, the way it's unfolding here.
So, nothing out of the ordinary.
Let's see what you guys are thinking and
get to your questions.
Okay.
Also, wanted to just remind
everybody, Thursday, the markets
will be closed in observation
of President Carter passing.
So, the markets in the U.S.
here will all be closed on Thursday.
And we'll post that, of course,
come Thursday.
But no Q&A session with Mark Ritchie and
Brandon, at least on Thursday.
Mark, Joe is saying he's asking a question
on page 224 of your book.
You, quote, rarely does
a correct pivot point
fail coming out of a
sound consolidation.
And Joe is saying it seems like pivot
points on average, even in the best of
markets, are only going to work about half
the time.
So, what did you mean by that sentence?
Yeah.
So, this goes back to something O'Neill
said.
And he said, you know, if the base breakout
is failing, then you missed something.
Like, it wasn't perfect.
If you go back and you look at it and you
study the market and you study the stock,
you'll find that either something you
missed with the stock that just wasn't
right, or the market wasn't right,
that maybe, you know, the general market
was heading into a pullback or a correction
and there were signs of distribution.
And what I found was when you go back and
you do that, and you do that
post-analysis, that he was absolutely
correct, that, you know, when you really
get things right and you're patient and
you're really, you know, waiting for those
really choice setups, they rarely fail
when conditions are right.
The problem is that most people just lack
the discipline to wait for that.
And they lack the confidence that they
can, you know, it's like, you know,
individual traders act like they're mutual
fund managers, you know.
And, you know, if a mutual fund manager
doesn't get invested and the S&P gets up
20% and they're in cash, they lose their
job because they can't catch up.
You know, it's just the nature of the
beast where, you know, have to put all
this money to work and you just
can't move very quickly and very
nimbly in a nimble way like
you can as an individual trader.
I don't care if I'm behind that the S&P is
up 20% and I'm flat.
I know that I'm going to beat the S&P.
I know I'm going to have my turn and I can
be up very, very quickly.
I can strike very, very, very fast because
I've got that liquidity.
I'm able to move very quickly.
I'm able to take on
very large positions to all
these things that, you
know, a big fund can't do.
So I wait very patiently for those,
you know, those correct pivots.
Now, yes, you know, O'Neill would have
told you the same thing that about half
the time, you know, your breakouts are
going to fail.
Now, that doesn't mean just
be... Here's the other thing too.
You got to define what's a failure.
You know, you could say, well,
you know, pivots don't work.
Well, a lot of times if you go back and
you look at a lot of stocks that,
you know, beginning
of a bull market, you get
knocked out of, let's say,
say half of your trades.
And you go back, you look at them a year
later and 80% of them are up huge.
Again, it's that horse.
Does it go from one side of the corral,
but can you stay on?
So a failure might be for you,
might be the stock stopped,
you know, undercut a
previous low and went down 4%.
That's not exactly a colossal failure.
So I look at, you know, a complete failure
as the stock, you know, rolls over,
the base fails, and it goes
into a downtrend, you know,
maybe a stage three or
into a stage four downtrend.
So it depends on your definitions,
but I hear what you're saying.
A very valid point.
But the point is, here's
the big point, and this
is what everybody should
listen very carefully to.
You really want to get to the point where
you take full responsibility and you say,
hey, what did I, did I miss something
here?
And go back, analyze it, and
keep the bar very high on your
standards that you hold for
yourself and you hold for the stocks.
And when you think with that way of
thinking, what it does is it makes you be
accountable and really, really look for
perfect conditions.
And that's what you want to get good at.
And quite frankly, here's another thing
that some of you can maybe relate to.
When you get really good at knowing what
those perfect conditions, it actually
allows you...
Here's the irony of it.
It allows you to play less perfect
conditions a lot better because you have
this reference point and you know what
it's supposed to do to be perfect.
And then you can stretch the rules around
it a little bit and even play,
you know, maybe subpar, you know,
not aces and kings and you move it down to
queens and jacks and tens.
But you just, you want to stay away from,
you know, of course, the trash hands.
Hopefully that makes sense.
You can talk to us at the gala about poker
hands.
That's right, yeah.
A question, Mark, about Palantir,
if that is setting up here in your view.
I mean, setting up?
No, not really.
I mean, could it go from here and come out
of this little base?
That's anybody's guess.
As I pointed out before, you know,
I love the company.
I love the CEO.
I think they're doing great things.
I wouldn't be surprised if this stock is
up five-fold from here.
When you look down the road, five years,
10 years, I don't know.
But I wouldn't chase it myself.
I missed, you know,
the opportunities to buy
it were down here,
coming out of a nice base.
I never got the real crisp entry that I
wanted.
And I, you know, and I paid the price of
missed opportunity for it.
But at this point, this is just an
extended stock that's pulling back.
It's holding up great, you know.
And again, could it go higher?
Absolutely.
But I don't buy stocks like this, you
know, that are this extended at this point.
And maybe if it tightens
up a bit more, you know,
we might get some type
of power play-esque set up.
Mike is asking about his purchase of PLNT
today, along with GEO, along with TSM,
asking if he's... We're
still one at a time.
Well, these are all focus-less names.
He's asking if he's chasing these.
He's taking some pilot-by-sized positions.
And would he be chasing these names by
buying these three breakouts?
I think absolutely you're chasing.
Because first of all, this one went on
after it broke out.
So the pivot already happened.
So I pointed this out.
But, you know, I mean, you know,
it's something that I saw the way it was
acting here and said, okay, this maybe can
tighten up here.
I mean, I would prefer to see this tighten
up here a little bit.
And as you always know, I'm always looking
for these tightenings.
And again, they don't always happen.
But I would like it to be, you know,
something like this would be my,
you know, the way I'd like to see this
playing out.
But maybe, you know, start a small position
as it moves through this first pivot.
But this, we put this on after the fact.
And now we're waiting to see maybe if it
could tighten up.
If it just takes off, you know,
fine.
You know, you might have to miss it.
But I think he chased that one.
What was it, Geo?
Yep.
I mean, I don't know what you did with
Geo, but yesterday...
Yeah.
Well, he bought it right
in the morning when it just
got yesterday's high, it
looks like, is what he said.
Today?
Yeah.
Yeah, I mean, I don't know.
I would have bought it yesterday,
or Friday, actually, I'm sorry.
This was on Focus last week.
Correct.
And so you could have bought it Friday.
So I don't know, why would you buy it
today and not Friday?
If you like this name, I don't understand
why Friday wasn't good enough.
And today you're buying it.
That doesn't make sense to me.
So, see, I think what's happening,
and this happens to everybody,
doesn't really happen to me too much
anymore.
Almost never.
But it happened to me for many years in
the beginning.
You see the S&P, and now everybody's
afraid to miss the market.
So they start buying things.
That's where you got to take this damn
index off your screen.
I'm telling you, if you want to be a great
stock trader, you got to take these
indexes and just get them off the screen
and just look at stocks.
I mean, maybe after you
got 42 years in it, like me,
you know, you can put
this stuff into perspective.
But you're just not, as a beginner,
you're not good enough.
And you're going to get emotional,
and you're going to be chasing the market.
This has nothing to do with anything.
This is a weighted index of 500 names.
This goes up 10% from here.
It doesn't mean that you should be in the
market.
If the stocks aren't meeting, your individual
stocks aren't meeting your criteria.
You have to be patient
and disciplined and wait
for the individual stocks
to meet your criteria.
As I've said many times, you go in the
store, the lights are on, the doors are open.
Big sign, come on in, we're open.
You go in the store, there's nothing on
the shelves.
Can you buy something?
If you went there for milk and there's no
milk in the store, does it matter that
there's bagels and everything else on
sale?
No, because you went there for milk.
All right?
Think about that.
The store are the indexes.
Just because they're
moving up does not mean
that the market is good
for your type of style.
So he just added here that Friday,
he did buy Gio on Friday.
And then the last one is
TSM also was purchased
on Friday when I think
we bought NVIDIA, I think.
Okay, that makes sense.
I mean, Friday, I think Friday chased TSM
up a little bit.
Why not start a position on Thursday and
then add to it on Friday?
That would have been the perfect way.
I thought about it.
If it wasn't for, again, I'm not seeing a
lot of stocks.
And again, you can say, well, why are you
not buying the pullback buy?
There's the market overriding your
individual stocks.
Well, no, because the individual stocks,
we don't have hardly any stocks on focus.
There are very few
stocks that are setting up
and there are very few
stocks that are working.
So we don't really have much traction.
So it really isn't a market
just happens to coincide
with the market not
being that great right now.
But that's better.
Yeah, those are much better purchases.
And I think, you know, you're... And
here's the other thing, too.
I don't know what kind of
size you're putting on, but
maybe if these are pilot
buys, I think maybe... Yeah.
So that's fine.
That's fine.
You know, I think the first one,
though, was a chase.
Yes.
Ahmaud is asked or mentioning
he bought a half position
of Burlington with a stop
below of December 23rd.
Move the stop up today to below December
30th as I don't have much traction overall.
But do you think that moving the stop up
to that low is a good position?
Look, it's very simple.
It's really your risk tolerance.
And if you move it up, you're going to be
stopped out more easily, obviously, right?
But it's your own risk tolerance.
So there isn't a right answer.
I mean, if you look at it
technically, you know, is
this going to sour if it
comes back in a bit here?
No, it's not.
Matter of fact, it will improve.
So let's just say this pulls
back here, you know, and
that's not going to hurt it
as far as I wouldn't buy it yet.
But if it tightens up a bit, that would
actually improve, you know, the base as
far as, you know, if I would
want to buy it, I'd love to
see it just tighten up
something like that and come out.
So I think it's not a terrible play,
but you do have some overhead right here.
See, this is why I was thinking about
buying a little this morning.
I said, you know what?
This is probably going to come in here.
You're dealing with,
you see these pullbacks,
reversal here, reversal
here, reversal here.
You have some overhead right here.
It came off pretty good right here,
here.
So right in this 292-ish area,
295, you've definitely got some supply.
So that's where it should
tighten up and quiet
down if that supply
stops coming to market.
So that's why I'm holding off a little bit
on that.
But it could just go.
I mean, so maybe you take a little bit and
then build into it.
All right.
Question being asked on Generac GNRC.
It was bought on January 2nd, based on some
weather forecasts and a major snow event.
Is that too speculative?
I'm sorry, but I have to get laughed
because again, you're asking me.
I mean, come on, you know, you know the
answer.
All right.
I mean, there's no base here.
It's going to a ton of supply.
You know, I don't trade that way.
I think you know that.
So there's nothing I can say to you about
this.
I mean, I'm sure if you look at my
indicators that they're not terribly bullish.
So yeah, this is, this doesn't have any
base.
It doesn't even have a low cheat.
It's going right into supply.
So it wouldn't meet any of my criteria.
So I, whatever the news is,
whatever that is, that's, that's
all well and good, but it has
to meet the technicals here.
So I'll give you my general rule.
77 RPR, Mark.
And actually I was going to make the
comment.
Guys, when you ask about questions,
you have our charting page, which will
show you exactly what Mark is referring
to.
TPR, Mark is, uh, I think a C, uh,
yellow as well, red on the under pressure.
So.
Yeah.
A D I would never touch.
A C is questionable.
Very, very questionable,
but almost all the purchases
that I would make would
be a B or an A or a B.
That's the cool thing about those
indicators and the TPR and the virus.
They're not just like some indicator
there.
It's a whole bunch of indicators that are
programmed by me to say, Hey, these are
the conditions that I need to see to
consider a stock, not to buy it.
And not the fact that it's going to says
it's going to go up, but to that it's in a
position that I could potentially consider
it for purchase.
It has to meet these qualifying criteria.
So it's a great qualifier.
If you just look at that, if the thing's
D, there's no way I'm going to buy it or
be, you know, it gives you your answer
right then and there.
But, but what was I saying?
I'm sorry.
I was making another point, but I forgot
now.
Well, maybe I'll come
back to you with his
follow-up on DSP looking
like a decent entry today.
I wouldn't say this is a decent entry
today.
Again, this is just not even breaking a
downtrend.
It doesn't really have much of a pivot.
I'm not sure.
Let me see.
Measure this move.
We'll go back about eight weeks or so.
I'll come all the way back to here.
So it's definitely a power play type name.
Now I'm going to go out and look really
far.
So I'm just showing you sort of how I
would, if I look at a stock and I'm
looking at it as a power play,
this is what I do.
I first measure it, make sure it's doubled
with eight weeks or so.
Then I go all the way back
and I want to put it into
perspective and see, is
this one that's late stage?
Is it just starting?
So this isn't as much as it's made a
gigantic move, it's not terribly late stage.
It went into a new uptrend here.
So I would say that this is something we
would consider.
What's the RPR on this, Bob?
I'd want this to be at least a 97 RPR.
Give me one more second.
Yeah.
But anyway, let me see.
DSP is what this is.
96.
Yeah.
So we're right there.
We're very close.
So I would say I would
look for this to tighten
up and maybe give
us some type of pivot.
You know, if you can get maybe a cheat
here, similar to what we were looking for
in that Bitcoin and it didn't, we didn't
get it, but that would be the earliest.
Yep.
All right.
Question.
Could you evaluate your Roberto's pullback
buy of KNTK on December 31st?
All right.
So we obviously, we talked about this
because I have a few little drawings in
here and it, it seems like it played into
exactly what I was maybe speculating.
So I, I said that I
wanted to see this tighten
up a little bit and then
it can go from there.
And maybe I said that and it did that.
And that's why you bought it.
I don't know.
Um, but yeah, I mean, I, I think it's
great right here.
Right.
Um, well, this is the second, what was the
date?
Uh, December 31st.
Yeah.
I mean, that's fine.
And it would be fine to add to it the next
day.
That's coming out of a nice little
well-formed load sheet.
Um, and now, you know, you're going to see
if you can get that, that handle phase or
that cheat phase, which would be normal,
be normal for this to pull back here and
build a right side would be, would be
perfectly normal.
And I'll just add to, you see,
I got that nice volume confirmation first,
and then you had the little mini
tightening there with the volume drawing
up that that just increases your,
your probability.
Yeah.
Yeah, absolutely.
And it increases your probability that you
could get an explosive action out of there
that you can get yourself at a profit
right away.
All right.
Uh, also I was asking about Shake Shack
pull back by on January 2nd.
Let's see.
Jan 2nd, Jan 2nd.
So right here, that one I'm not too fond
of.
I see what you're doing above this.
I think that looking at this and looking
to the left here with this supply,
I would wait.
And I did.
And it exactly why it's just tightening up
here.
So this is normal and a little bit more
tightening.
And this is viable.
I was, that's why I put it on focus
because we're close.
Uh, he was also asking or sharing his
results from 2024 is average win of 5.
62 average loss of 3.51
with a 41, uh, roughly 41%
win rate asking if you
would evaluate his results.
I think you should try
to, you know, get a bigger
average gain or a, or a
little bit smaller average loss.
I would try to widen that, widen that
reward risk ratio a little bit.
Yeah.
You're a little bit below that two to one
target.
Preferably.
Yeah.
I like to see a raise the, raise the gain
a little bit, go for a little bit more
and, and bring the, the average loss in a
little bit.
I mean, if you can get the average loss
around 3% and the average gain,
maybe seven or 8%, then
you'd really be, you know, you
could, That 41% batting
average would be a moneymaker.
Question from Eric about ITRI.
Yeah, sorry.
Real quick.
That is a very, very small adjustment.
Like, that's not a monumental task.
That's just taking profits, maybe letting
a little bit more on the profits,
or maybe protecting a little bit more of
the give back and tightening up a tiny,
tiny bit on the stops.
That is very, very little shift that can
make a monumental shift in your performance.
Because now you're turning that over,
you know, many times.
Just to... Yeah, I just want
to add to that, Mark, too,
because I was just talking
to Renee Hirsch last week.
She's going to be talking at the gala,
so a little preview.
But she's going to be talking about the
exact point Mark just made and how she
made a small adjustment in terms of,
you know, her average loss.
And it was a game-changing, you know,
adjustment.
So, a little preview.
Yeah, so we have, just to let everyone
know, we took every ballroom in the hotel.
We sold... the entire ballroom is sold out
to the...
We don't even know how we're going to fit
everybody.
So, we're trying to figure that out now.
I'm actually going to the
hotel because I have to go
and figure out how we're
going to squeeze everybody in.
And we sold the entire hotel out.
So, we're... this year's gala is going to
be something else.
It's... I think we have double the people
of last year.
Yep.
Eric is asking about ITRI.
Yeah, again, you know, this really just
hasn't done anything yet to...
This looks like it's probably...
If you look at, you know,
the Minervini indicators on the
platform, it's almost certainly
under pressure, I think.
And probably, you know, maybe.
It is under... Yeah,
absolutely under pressure.
It's under 83 RPR with, again,
a C rating.
But his question really
is, it's viable if it's setting
up on the nice right side
below 111 within a week now?
Or is the base short-term
invalid because of
the short breakout and
reversal early November?
Okay.
So, first of all, three things I want to
point out.
Hopefully, I'll remember them as I go
through them.
So, the first thing is that I
was going to say, this looks
very much like a C to me
and a lower relative strength.
So, you beat me to it, Bob.
But again, how would I know that?
Because those indicators are based on what
I look for.
So, I just...
And you need to get to where you get to
this point where you look at a stock and
you can see, you know, this is just not
aces or kings, not even queens or jacks.
You know, it's just not a playable hand at
this point.
So, your question was,
too, you're saying, well, what
about if it's at 111 in here
and you start speculating?
Well, here's the thing.
First, it has to meet the criteria.
You're jumping the gun here.
It hasn't met that criteria yet.
So, why are you worrying about it?
Why are you trying to
forecast something when there's
other stocks that are
close and they're setting up?
You know, you've got a
stock like Burlington, which
this looks, in my
opinion, a whole lot better.
It's a whole lot closer to being set up in
a constructive base.
So, this is what I want to tee up,
right?
And then the third thing I forgot,
like I said, I probably would.
The underpressure, lower PR, okay.
No, no, I covered that.
I mean, yeah, it was, you know,
I... So, you know, with the...
Oh, so, also, I just want to point out,
I've been working with the programmers,
the new platform is, I'm telling you,
it is out of this world.
I mean, and we're not even...
When we do launch it, it's
still going to be in a phase
that we have a lot more that
we have not programmed yet.
But it is the F-16 fighter jet like you've
never seen.
Everything real time.
It's just unbelievable.
I just can't get off of it.
So, I'm real excited.
And it's going to do a lot of this for
you, all right?
There's a lot.
Everything is going to... Our charting
page, everything's on one page.
Your portfolio management, your screens,
your watch list, your monolert,
news, everything.
Fundamentals, all going to be right there
in bird's eye view.
Lightning fast.
Calculations being made automatically.
How much you have to
sell to... No calculation.
It's just going to be right there in your
table and say, you got to sell,
you know, 72 shares to de-risk this trade.
It's just really, really cool stuff.
So, I'm super excited.
And it's going to help you make these
decisions a lot better.
Question if AXP...
On the AXP base and buy point around 303.
Raul is asking.
I don't understand.
What was the question on AXP?
If you comment on the base and if there's
a buy point around 303.
I wouldn't really call this much of a
base, but I would just say this...
These are some stocks.
Some of these stocks, these big names,
the old stalwarts, you know, the AXPs,
and I don't know what Coca-Cola looks
like, but I'm just using it as an example.
That type of name, you know, the big names
that everybody knows.
Some of them have been holding up or
setting up lately and acting pretty strong.
AXP is one of them.
You know, I don't know if this is a shift
defensively or if it's just, you know,
they've been underwater for so long and
finally, you know, they're coming around.
So this is acting really strong.
It's looking really strong, but this isn't
really much of a base.
So I wouldn't really call this much of a
base.
It would have to tighten up a bit more,
probably at least a couple days.
And then from there, it's still a very
small base.
So not something that I would be too,
you know, totally excited about.
A question about GEV, if this is considered
a power play and buyable around 358.
So GEV is on my watch list.
I was going to put it... we put it on,
of course, prior.
And as I noted, I wanted it to tighten up
a bit.
It came off a little bit.
You know, you could, if
you're really aggressive, you
could have maybe put that
pullback buy on one, two.
But then it was strong on Friday and it
just got away here this morning.
So I didn't put it on.
But, you know, there's not much of a right
side being formed here.
So, I mean, you got to... you'd have to
play this off the pullback buy.
It's very similar to how TSM got away.
You know, you didn't get that right side.
If you didn't play, I'll bring that up.
Let me show you the similarities as far as
looking at the pivot.
See, if you didn't
play that right there on
that pullback buy, then
it got away from you.
And sometimes that happens.
And that's why, you know, you take some on
the pullback buy.
And it's a balancing act.
You have to decide, you know, how much
exposure do I want to put on?
How much do I want to own this stock?
Do I want to be in the market right now?
But the real key is to, you know,
not get so enamored with having to be in
the market that you chase and you break
rules and you put on exposure when,
you know, market conditions are not
optimal.
Some exposure, you know, that's the key.
Remember, it's not an all or nothing game.
You know, the market's maybe not exactly
right.
It's under distribution.
You don't have many stocks, right?
So you play smaller.
You take a few names and you take smaller
positions and a little less exposure.
Instead of being 75%, 100%, you're maybe
25%, maybe 50% invested.
Instead of taking big 25% positions,
you take some 510s.
Maybe, you know, your largest position's a
15%.
A question on CCL.
If this is considered a power play.
Come on.
McCall is asking.
Oh, let's see.
So again, first thing I'm going to do is
I'm going to go back from here.
I'm going to go back about eight weeks.
I'll give it a little bit.
But I even go, you know, I'll go back even
12 weeks or so.
Give it a little slack here to see.
It's up about 100%.
So it's not exactly in eight weeks.
So it's not super powerful.
Then I'm going to zoom out and I want to
see.
Is this late stage?
Is it beginning a new move?
Is it coming out of a period of dormancy?
You know, you know, of course, that
this industry got decimated from COVID.
And it's sort of, you know, in a recovery
stage.
So I think this is a power play.
You know, it could be considered as a sort
of a power play.
Not a classic and optimal.
But certainly here, it hasn't done anything
yet to give me a buy point, a pivot.
Also, power plays, we don't usually like
power plays to come back to the 50-day.
That's a sign of weakness.
They usually are way above the 50-day.
And when they pull back, they're nowhere
near the 50.
So the fact that this is near the 50-day,
you know, says...
It kind of takes it off of the power play
list.
Yeah.
If you look at a competitor, RCL,
Mark...
Also, check the RPR on that real quick.
Yeah.
RCL.
Making new multi-year highs comfortably
exceeding COVID sell-offs and just the
difference of this.
Yeah.
It looks like Carlos
eating the lunch of... Yeah.
Yeah.
Maybe this is one.
You know, maybe this is a better choice in
that group.
Carnival is a 91.
Okay.
So there you go.
Once again, as I said before, I want to
see 97, 98, 99, 100.
Well, in our case, it's...
Of course, we're at 100.
We go from 1 to 100.
So in our case, I want to see 100,
99, 98.
Yep.
Now, if you're looking at IBD,
I want to see 99, 98, 97.
Question about CXW.
If this is considered Bible as a power
play.
Yeah.
So CXW is a little bit volatile here.
If you see it come off
about... I think it's about 30%.
No, actually, no, it's not.
Why is it... Okay.
Maybe it's a different one.
Because we're not... We're
supposed to put this on...
Hold on one second.
Let me just check my list here.
Yeah.
That's on our watch list.
I'm just waiting for it to tighten up a
bit here.
Sorry.
I was taking another name.
It's just... You know, I
think it needs a little bit more.
It's a bit volatile here.
It fell apart right over here.
I was trying to tighten up.
Now, let's do the math again.
Let's go and see how much this went up.
Okay.
About 100%.
So this is getting there.
It's very close.
But with all this action over
here... And this volatility... Reversal.
Reversal.
Sell-off.
You can see right here.
Draw a line from that pivot.
Right?
Let's just draw a line across.
Look to the left.
See here?
Look at all this action right here.
So we want the line of most resistance.
Right now, this is the line of resistance,
right?
You can see it.
This is where it's having all the trouble.
It's coming against that area.
And you can clearly see that above that,
almost every trade is a reversal.
Almost every day.
Reversal, reversal, reversal.
Reversal, reversal.
And the ones even just right up to it have
a lot of reversals.
Every single trading day above that level
is a negative reversal.
So it clearly delineated the line of most
resistance.
Now, when this stock tightens up and the
volume comes down, now what you're doing
is you're forming what's called the line
of least resistance.
That line of most resistance becomes the
line of least resistance.
We prefer, though, for that to happen
maybe up here.
So maybe it even tightens up here.
I'm going to give you another scenario.
And then it comes up
here and it stalls out a
bit more because you
still have some supply left.
And then from there it comes out.
And that would be my preferred buy point.
But if it tightened up here, I'd probably
go into it right here and at least buy
some and hope that it gave me a spot to
add.
Why do we want to buy up here?
Okay.
Why would we want to buy at a higher price
and it's better?
Let's show you that.
This is for those of you that
are maybe more beginners
because I know some of
you understand this already.
So now if we draw that same line,
look here.
We only have one, two days above that,
right?
It's only traded.
So there's very little supply now.
Say we're working through the supply and
the fact that it tightened up and the
volume came down, that's telling you that
the supply issue has been worked out.
That is stock analysis 101.
What I just showed you right there has
made me tens of millions of dollars.
And O'Neill and David Ryan and lots of
other people too that understand this.
Once you understand this, you don't need
to know nothing else.
You may think you understand this fully,
but it might take you 10 years to really
fully understand it.
The question was being asked about IBIT,
if it was setting up as a load sheet.
I know you already reviewed that this
morning.
The question though, as a follow-up,
was given that this is based off the
Bitcoin that trades 24-7, should one look
at the Bitcoin chart that would add the
weekend days of data as opposed to just
the Monday to Friday IBIT is providing?
I think that's a wonderful question.
To be honest with you, I'm going to think
about that for a minute.
I'm not sure.
Personally, my first reaction is no.
I would look at the chart of this,
of it on its own.
However, it's certainly something to think
about because there's action that could
add to a gap and to have that stock sort
of, the ETF play catch up.
I don't know, Mark, what do you think of
that?
Well, there's nothing wrong with looking
at both.
I mean, listen, this is 99...
In terms of the daily action, it's 99.9%
correlated.
But again, to Mark's point,
this will smoothen out some
of those gaps if you want
to look at the 24-7 chart.
I have it on a secondary screen I look at
every now and again.
But look, it's in the same principles
though.
You're looking for that tight right side.
So if that 24-7 chart adds more tightness,
then by all means.
Yeah, I mean, I'm completely against
after-hours trading.
I don't...
Look, if you're going to make trading 24
hours, make the market open 24 hours.
This after-hours
shit, I don't like it at
all because it's going
to add to volatility.
It's going to add to...
You know, you get some
action overnight and now,
you know, the stock
gaps in the morning place.
I think all information, including
fundamentals, that companies should not be
able to release any information whatsoever
except during market hours.
Now, if you want to extend those market
hours, that's fine.
That's fine.
But so I think there's a flaw there in the
way we would be doing the best justice to
stock traders and investors in terms of
volatility.
But so I think it could add volatility.
That would be my only, you know,
my only observation of it, if you will.
All right.
On Thursday, when Mark Ritchie was
reviewing NVIDIA, said that even if
NVIDIA's setup is perfect, it will be
failure-prone since so many eyes are on it.
Can you please explain what does that
mean?
Mark, do you want to write it?
Well, I was just referring to...
I'm going to read it for you.
Yeah, I was just referring to the fact
that, look, the more obvious something
becomes or the more eyes
that are on it, you know, it
could just be more volatile
or a little more failure-prone.
Well, to be clear, though, we just bought
it the next day.
So I wasn't saying you don't trade it.
And the same...
Look, we thought...
I thought a year ago
the pivot was obvious last
January, and it was perfect,
and I took a big position.
I sold it too soon, of course.
But listen, sometimes the...
I would never not take a trade because
it's, you know, it looks obvious.
It was just that idea of, you know,
look, the more eyes on it, the more
aberrant potentially unless alpha you get
out of the immediate price actions.
Yeah.
And I made this exact point.
If you remember, I talked about this last
week, and I said that, you know,
that this stock is one of the
biggest stocks in the world
and has more eyes on it
than probably any name, Apple.
And if you're a breakout, if you're,
you know, thinking breakouts don't work,
this was the stock
that I use as an example
of how, I mean, look
how perfect right here.
It comes out of a perfect VCP.
You come all the way back here.
This is where I think we originally bought
it, coming out of this beautiful base
here, coming out of a perfect VCP with a
little shakeout.
I mean, everything's classic textbook.
This has been coming out of bases for its
whole move.
So you give them the benefit of the doubt.
This is the leader.
I mean, this, this,
NVIDIA, if there's an axe in
the market, if there's
a key leader, this is it.
I mean, I don't think you, this is the
definition of a market leader.
Um, so again, you know, Mark's saying,
Hey, you know, it's pretty obvious now
it's coming out of base after base,
after base, we're getting into maybe
third, fourth, but it's still,
as I pointed out recently, also,
this is not exceptionally late.
You know, I mean, it, it's still in an
uptrend.
It's made bases.
You had a big correction here.
I would say that was a reset.
So this is your new stage two uptrend and
your first viable base was here.
So you really are coming out of maybe a
third stage base.
You could go four or five or six.
So it's not necessarily
over, but what Mark's
saying is that there's
definitely not early here.
So it's becoming more and more failure
prone.
You might break out here and, and failure
prone again, doesn't necessarily mean that
it, it rolls over and it
goes into a stage four
decline and, and the moves
over on a secular level.
It could just mean that there's some more
volatility and you get stopped out.
That stock becomes more of a bucking
bronco around those buy points.
The other point I would make that,
and this is something that I learned right
here with the way a lot of you guys are
learning, is that there's just less
opportunity for inefficient pricing in
those crowded trades.
And that's what I'm after.
So if you think about it, just when Mark
talks about eyeballs or the fact that
everybody in the world knows who NVIDIA
is, look at another name though,
like a, like a geo or SEI, I can promise
you on our focus list, 99% of people in
the market have never even heard of those
companies.
Probably 99.99.
So, so, but that
differential is where the
inefficiency is and that's
where the opportunity is.
And a lot of you don't
understand that, but there's,
there's another million
dollar statement in my opinion.
People would say, well, why
would I want to be in the stock
where everybody's buying
and that pushes it up, right?
Yes.
But at some point it becomes supply that
everybody's bought.
But, and now there's nothing but selling
potential, but now you got a little
company like whatever, X, Y, Z,
and they do business with NVIDIA and they
make, I don't know, some thing that goes
in that helps them make their chips and,
and they do 10 million in sales and they
can go from 10 million to a hundred
million in tenfold just on the backs of,
you know, or say Boeing for, I use this
example, sometimes Boeing,
Boeing, you know, does, has,
does business with a company
that makes some little harness.
You know, I, there's been businesses that
I, you know, that I, or stocks that I
bought that were companies that were
supplying Apple or the things that they
needed to make their touchscreens and
things like that.
And although Apple's
this big company, it's very
hard for them to grow the
revenue, you know, huge.
This little company is now on the backs of
this big company and they're able to grow
their Revenue, hundreds of percent per
quarter.
So that's the cousin effect, or that's
where there's not a lot of eyes on that.
So there's a lot of upside.
You've got a couple of things.
One, the company's small, so it can grow
very rapidly.
And two, there's not much investment in
it.
So the price hasn't been bid up yet,
and it hasn't been discounted.
And the fact that you've got these big
earnings, you put those two together.
If you've taken the Master Trader Program,
you'll know where I'm going here.
When you have big earnings,
that's where you don't have to
worry about the PE very much,
because it takes care of itself.
No one can forecast for very long.
An analyst doesn't know, or the CEO
himself doesn't know that their company is
going to be able to sustain 100% growth
per quarter for the next 12, 15 quarters.
But if they do do that, I assure you,
whatever it started off as a PE,
whether it was 100, 500, or 1,000,
isn't going to matter.
It's not going to matter.
That stock's going to go higher,
if they can deliver that.
That was a gold nugget in mine, right there,
in the last few minutes, in my opinion.
Something to mark down and come back to.
Oh, there was one more thing I wanted to
say.
So Mark may turn out to be... his concern
may still turn out to be right.
We could say this is a successful trade so
far.
We could say this has
been successful, because
it's broken out in here,
and maybe we're up 6%.
You could take a little profit.
But, you know, this might still come in
here and fail.
You know, we're not...
this hasn't really come out of
the... we've gotten out of
the woods completely yet.
Exactly right.
I think that's the main key, is that you
just have to be more mindful that
something may not be as
smooth and easy as when
you have the volatility
that Mark was mentioning.
Yes.
And we're always adjusting.
You know, we're adjusting.
We're constantly... this is all about just
adjusting risk.
It's all about... I was
just at my shooting range
yesterday and was training
a couple of friends of mine.
And we're running... we're running through
these targets.
And some of the targets
have these big black areas on
them where if you shoot
them, you get penalized heavily.
So you've got a little tiny
area to shoot, and you've
got a big area that's
what's called a no shoot.
Other targets are wide open.
The whole target has got a big area,
and there's not much risk there.
So I run through the targets,
and I shoot them much
faster than the guys I'm
training, and they shoot it.
And then... so they shoot into the black.
So... and I said, now you know why they
shot into the black?
Because they shot just as fast as they
shot the open target.
They shot the target that only had a
little space and had a lot of black.
Their cadence was the same.
They're going bing,
bing, bing, bing, real fast
through everything, because
they're thinking speed.
They want to get through everything fast.
But you see, the risk manager says,
okay, I go really fast on this target.
But now when I switch over to this target,
whoa, there's risk there.
I got to slow down.
I got to... I got to make sure I got a
better sight picture.
I got to maybe pull my shots a little bit
slower.
Maybe I got to make sure I'm a little
closer.
You see?
So now I make an adjustment.
I see the risk, and I make that
adjustment.
There's... there's several adjustments I
can make.
I can wait till I'm closer.
I can shoot slower.
I can get a better sight picture.
That is the exact same thing as trading
stocks.
No different way.
And that's probably
why I'm a really good
stock trader, and I'm a
really good marksman.
Because I apply the exact same logic.
It's all about risk management.
You're adjusting risk.
You assess... you assess the reward, and
you have to adjust the risk based on that.
I think that was a golden nugget.
I just... that was just off the top of my
head here.
I've never made that... but use that
metaphor, that example before.
I think I'm going to use that another
time.
Yeah, 100%.
I feel like this is a phenomenal start to
the year here.
No, well, I'm always trying to bring to
life, you know, the lessons, and to bring
some visuals to it, so where you can grasp
it, and you can put it into perspective,
and gives context.
Adam Schell from USA Today, he used to
quote me quite a bit back in the day,
and he used to call me metaphor man.
He said he'd love to quote me in USA
Today, because they always got metaphors.
Dustin is asking, if a stock on focus list
becomes a potential buy candidate and is
moving towards the buy point intraday,
under what circumstances would you
incrementally scale
into the position, rather
than buy a full
position, if it breaks out?
You know, oh, hold on.
I didn't really grasp that fully,
but I don't know.
Maybe you did, Mark.
Bob, sorry, it was the first question.
What are the conditions where we're not
incremental?
Meaning you just...
You would be incrementally
scaling into the position,
rather than buying a full
position on the breakout.
Well, this is, again, hypothetical,
right?
We'd love to see an example where,
you know, without seeing the pivot,
but the biggest thing that's going to keep
me from... that's going to give me the all
clear to get aggressive right off the hop,
is how have my last couple of trades been
and how tight the pivot is.
So if the last couple of trades have
stunk, I can promise you I'm going to be
more incremental because the market is
telling me, you know, that being really
aggressive, it's not the time to be really
aggressive.
So that's sort of how I think about it.
And then liquidity is the other thing.
Look, it comes down to two things,
trades and my list.
And Mark will tell you the exact same
thing, you know, trades and your focus list.
How is your list performing?
So maybe you didn't make
any trades, but you see
your list is growing and
growing and growing.
The stocks are breaking out all over the
place.
You chose not to trade them because you
were maybe more risk adverse at that time,
but you're getting the feedback.
You're getting it.
Now, I'd like to see it with some real
money.
I put some real money at play.
If this market really is good, then my
trade should be showing me some profits too.
And that's, we back it with real money and
some test buys.
But as Mark said, you know, trades,
trades working.
That's the first thing.
We're not, we're never getting aggressive
without having at least the list doing
really well and growing
and seeing stocks breaking
out of bases and our
trades showing profits.
Never, never.
We're just going right to, you know,
heavily invested.
And never means never for anyone who's
never.
Never, never.
And Soros did the same rules.
You know, I posted that
video before you heard Soros
talking about what I call
progressive exposure.
But, you know, I look, I
learned this stuff from the
best, you know, and that's
how I became one of the best.
And that's where we're just passing it
down.
These are, you know, solid, solid rules.
And it's all about risk management.
You can Monday morning
quarterback all day and
say, oh, if I did this, I
could have done that.
It means nothing.
You can't do anything with that in real
life.
You know, look back
all day long and say
what you should have
done or could have done.
Doesn't mean shit.
Yeah, you got to manage risk in real time.
Kevin's asking or commenting, he bought a
quarter position of BROS on 1224.
Yeah, I sold half of it on 1227 and
stopped out on 1228.
Wanted to keep the position small and
tight in this environment.
Was this a good use of tactics or too
conservative?
Again, you know, when
you say too conservative,
I mean, it's really
your own risk tolerance.
I've been, you know, looking, measuring
this as far as, you know, percentage wise,
you know, it's four or 5% or so.
So it's too, it's too
conservative as far as,
you know, waiting
for it to completely fail.
It didn't fail.
But here's the thing, you see,
it wasn't really tight.
So maybe a little position there.
Now, there's a, there's a number of ways
you could approach this.
Now, this is one where
you could have played this
pullback by as it gets
near the danger point.
I'm not even opposed to buying some on
this day as it takes out the previous
day's high because it's so close to this
low.
You know, it's, well, it's about four or
5%.
So you're getting near the danger point
now.
And if you get it right, you,
you know, you hit it perfect,
like, and you might even
not get it perfectly right.
It might just come up and
then maybe tighten up a bit
and then you'll have an
opportunity to add, right?
So what you did was you went in a little
bit early.
And of course, we only know that's all in
hindsight.
I'm looking in hindsight.
In real time, this is what you saw.
That's what you saw.
So you got to make a decision.
So is this a bad decision?
Absolutely not.
That's not a terrible decision.
It's not perfectly tight.
It's not one that I probably
would get aggressive
on, but I could see taking
a small position there.
Then I would look to see if it tightens
up.
If it just goes great, I got something on,
but let's see if it tightens up now.
Well, okay.
So is it really falling apart here?
No, no, it's not falling apart.
So I don't, I think, you
know, you probably, you
know, you probably sold
the whole thing prematurely.
Now, maybe just cut.
I think the first cut made sense.
And if, and you cut quick too,
I think he cut on the 27th, right?
27th was already reduced and sold on 28th.
The fact that you cut on the 27th,
that might've had me, like if I cut on the
27th, I probably would've went through the
30th and gave it another couple of days
because I got out so quickly on that first
one.
Now, if I had not, I would have had more
pressure on me here.
And I, and it would be more likely that I
got stopped on the 30th because now I have
a bigger position and now I've got more
pressure.
And that's why it makes sense to,
to scale.
Yeah.
Again, this is, I think, another very
golden, golden thing to understand.
You know, if you scale out and you,
and you sell some right away and you,
maybe you take that two or three or 4%
loss.
Well, now when it gets down to a six,
seven or eight, there's less pressure and
you can, you can go through it a little
bit longer and maybe with stamp.
But if now, if you're down, you know,
8% and you've got a big position,
that's a lot of pressure, right?
And you're, now you're concerned,
it's going to be down more.
And if it gaps, so the pressure just
builds.
So it's all about managing.
See, it's not only managing
the risk, it's managing your
own, your own personality,
managing your tolerances.
Very, a very important word
that you have to remember
when you're, when
you're trading is tolerance.
You're managing your, your personal
tolerance.
And so one, one trader might say, well,
you know, this is not acting very well.
It hasn't tightened up.
Why would you buy it here?
Well, because my personal
tolerance is so low that, that
I want to get it as close to
the danger point as possible.
And let's just say that from here,
right?
You see right here?
Let me make this clear.
From here to this low, I'm going to be
hypothetical here.
We're going to, we're going to,
we're going to change the percentages.
We're going to assume that from there to
here is 1%.
Okay.
So at that point, the trade clearly fails.
It takes out the low of the base.
We don't want the low of the base taken
out.
So that's a clear base failure,
right?
Well, I, I know in 1% if it's,
if I'm wrong.
So I might get real aggressive there
because of my tolerance, even though this
is not maybe perfectly tightened,
I'm playing the pullback buy there.
And instead of, you know, instead of going
in here at a small position and building,
I might be willing to go in a large
position because my risk is so small.
So you see, I'm always weighing that.
I'm always weighing, where's the stop?
Where am I getting out?
What's my overnight risk?
All that.
And that is how I base my entry.
Your, your stop, your risk is your soul is
actually a selection tool.
Your risk is a selection tool.
You back into the risk.
The other thing I would add, Mark,
this isn't really a true power play,
but I would say normally, if this was the
re you, I always want to try and at least
hold a piece till the stop because
overriding a stop just doesn't saving that
one, 2% just doesn't
pay when you're in that
highest alpha low
standard deviation situation.
Yeah.
If you got a month, you might have a
monster by the tail.
So yeah, you want, it's a, again,
see Mark's thinking in terms of risk
versus potential reward, always weighing
the risk versus reward.
Your turn, Bob.
Back to you.
So Matthew is mentioning,
uh, cause we already
did talk about GEV,
but he did buy it as well.
Uh, on January 2nd, bought a 333,
right at the open with a tight stop of 327.
I saw this as a low cheat
near the danger point with
only 2% of risk out after an
inside day on December 31st.
Selling volume on previous days seemed
low, like supply was drying up.
And Mark Ritchie said on
Thursday session that he was looking
for a couple more days of the
stock moving up and tightening.
Just wondering if I jumped the gun,
even though the stock is up.
So the two things that I love that you
said is one, you, you recognize the inside
day and how, and, and how close it is to
the stop of the 2%.
So that right there tells me you get it,
you get it.
And you're going to be okay.
This is like, you know, your children,
you know, every now and then, you know,
my daughter, my back when
my daughter was younger, she'd
say things and I go, Oh my
God, I mean, I was so worried.
I'm like, is this kid going to make it in
the world?
And then now, you know, she, she said some
things every now and then she got older.
She's 18 now.
And I'm like, okay, all right,
my kid's going to be all right.
I think my kid's going to be okay in the
real world, you know?
And, and, and that's from the feedback
that I get by listening to what she says
and how she understands things and
processes the world.
And this is like right here, you know,
I, I see someone, the way you're talking,
I said, okay, this, this, this,
this guy's going to be okay.
You know, you, you under, you get it.
So I think that's a good decision.
The way, the way you Yeah, this is such a
really good example, too, how Mark's
talking about the way you use the tactics
and stepping in.
And the other thing I was just
going to add, though, is you
know really quickly is this
train coming in on schedule.
So you took a little, you know,
you went a little bit out the risk curve,
but you compensated for that by being
really tight.
Yeah, we get a lot of... It really has to
go.
It has to go.
Exactly.
Where we get a lot of questions,
people going out the risk curve,
it's not tight, and you don't know
relatively quickly if you're right or wrong.
Okay, so now you can look at this a couple
ways.
We can look at... Now, you say,
okay, well, Mark says to draw a line.
Well, why would you buy into all this
overhead?
I probably wouldn't, you know,
and that's why I didn't.
But if you're going to, you want to do it
very close to the danger point.
Because again, see, you have to adjust.
So buying into this overhead to the left
is a lower probability.
This result that you're getting here,
this is not... If you put these on a bell
curve, I'm going to tell you right now,
this is not a high probability.
And I think you know that.
I think you feel like you
might... Like the way you worded
your question was almost
like, did I get lucky here?
You know, did I do something wrong and
just get lucky?
I don't think you did something wrong.
And I think this is a little bit of luck.
But you see, you managed it.
You managed it.
And you say, okay, well,
maybe, you know, I got
to get lucky here for
this to work right away.
And still only have a full 8% stop.
And that's the way you think.
That's the way you want to think.
But I would have preferred to see this
tighten up and digest this supply.
I mean, that's, you know, and that's why
I'm not in it.
Okay.
Zalanka is asking a fairly
detailed question, but
I'm going to paraphrase
it and sum it up here.
She was looking at the NVIDIA purchase on
Friday when it was posted at 142.
The stock was already up 2.7% above the
previous day's close.
And by the time she saw it, it was at 144,
which was up already about 4%.
And even though she's
been watching NVIDIA for a
while, I didn't get in and
now I'm kicking myself.
So they've gotten in and maybe put the
stop loss low of that day.
What's your advice?
My advice is to first
stop kicking yourself
because you see a stock
up and you didn't buy it.
If you can't, if you can't do that,
then you have no chance of success.
Okay.
If that emotion doesn't get put in check
immediately and just forget it,
you are going to miss
stocks over and over and over
up way more times than
you're going to get them right.
Right.
So if you can't get used to
having a stock go up and you
didn't buy it or you made a
mistake, you have big problems.
I'm just going to tell you right now.
It doesn't matter how
good you are at anything
else because that
emotion will ruin everything.
So that's first of all.
Second of all, I think your analysis is
absolutely correct.
And the reason why, you know, I personally
don't own it.
I don't personally.
You know, we put it on and Mark put this
on and I said to him, I just said to him
this morning, nice, you know, nice,
you know, choice on NVIDIA.
But when it was put on, I said,
I wouldn't buy it here.
That was my response to him, putting it
on.
I said, I see what, you know, what it is
here, but it gapped.
And by the time it gets through that
pivot, it's up quite a bit.
So I wouldn't chase it.
However, you know, technically it's
meeting the criteria and it's a leader.
So, you know, do you give it the benefit
of the doubt?
Yeah.
Yeah, we put it on the list.
We give it the benefit of the doubt.
I wanted to give TSM the benefit of the
doubt, too.
I mean, you could very easily make a case
for this on this pullback buy.
If it wasn't on an outside day and it
opened up quiet, might be in this, you know.
But am I going to say, oh, I made this big
error and I, you know, I got to change.
Look, there's one thing of doing... and
this is where it gets confusing.
In one respect, oh, right, Mark,
you say, well, don't Monday morning
quarterback, but then we got to do
post-analysis and look for perfect trades.
Yes, but doing post-analysis is to look,
to find out how you can optimize what
you're doing and put
a plan for, you know,
into play and manage
your risk versus reward.
But it doesn't mean that the result
justifies the mean.
If you go back and you
grade this trade and you
say, well, okay, I made a
good buy because it's up.
And this whole right side is all screwed
up and it's all gapping all over the place.
There's all kinds of volatility.
And the closest low to a stop is 28% away.
No, that doesn't mean just because you're
profitable, it was a good choice.
Yes, you know, so again, you have to
separate the two.
And I think that's what your question is.
You're asking that is, you know,
because it's up, did I make a bad choice
by not buying it?
No, no.
The answer is no, you did not make a bad
choice.
Keep being disciplined like that.
All right.
Thoughts on UNM setting up, Lou is asking.
Yeah, I don't know this one.
Let's see.
This has come a long way.
It's been a very persistent sort of bull
market of its own.
So in a vacuum, not knowing a whole lot
about it and just looking at this right
here, this is definitely setting up in
this cheat area.
Absolutely.
So you broke...
This is just classic right out of my book
or right out of the master trader book.
Broke the downtrend, marked itself up a
bit, pulled back.
And now this is what we call the making
the turn.
Once it gets above...
Whoops, sorry.
This thing's...
Once it gets above this high right here,
that means the stock is now officially
back into an uptrend on an
intermediate-term basis, right?
It's in an uptrend here.
It breaks down.
Now it breaks that up, that short-term
downtrend, pauses.
When it gets back above that high,
it is now in a new uptrend, right?
So is this setting up?
Yes, it is.
It is setting up.
But that doesn't necessarily mean I would
buy it.
But certainly it's setting up in a cheat
area.
Okay.
Question about PR.
I'll take a look at it, too, because I
don't know.
Like I said, I don't know much about this
one.
So I got to see why I don't.
It's UNM, right?
You and UM.
Just put that on my list, because I don't
know a whole lot about that one.
Question about Prax.
P-R-A-X.
Would you say the
contractions start from
November 11th and was
viable on January 2nd?
Contractions start from November 11th.
Well, I mean, yeah, you know, this is
definitely a little VCP right here.
And so November 1st is where it broke out.
And the contractions start, yes,
from over here on 11.11.
But the real, the quality base is over
here.
This is a big base.
Look at how nice this base is.
And it really goes through all the
iterations.
Very orderly.
I mean, you could have bought it right
here on the 19th.
Let's see if you would have got stopped.
I mean, if you came out here.
Yeah.
So this came up about 10%.
So you'd have been knocked out.
So this is a perfect... This
is a Hardaway crossover.
This is where... Okay,
here's the buy point right here.
You know, you watch this thing.
You watch it.
You wait for it to tighten up.
Great.
It breaks out right here.
Let me show you.
Right here.
Breaks out.
Oops.
I'm sorry.
Wrong one.
Right here.
Breaks out over here.
Gets through this nice big VCP.
Right?
And then you watch the next day comes in,
comes in and stops you out.
Maybe over here or over here.
And it comes off.
And then, boom, next day, blast off.
Two days later, it's off to the races.
That's a Hardaway crossover, what we call
a Hardaway crossover.
It stops you out and then takes right off.
It doesn't give you an opportunity to buy.
You could say, well, maybe you could have
bought the pullback buy.
That's not a perfect pullback buy.
But this really, really would have...
If you just got stopped out, it's unlikely
that you've been buying it the next day.
But now, sometimes you get on a Hardaway
crossover, especially if it's a large base
like this, and it pulls
back to the top of the
base, you get a pullback
buy a post-breakout.
And that's exactly what happened right
here.
And that's where, if this were to do this,
your re-entry would be on the next
pullback buy on the pullback after the
Hardaway crossover.
And the general rule is, you want this to
be pretty short.
You don't want it to be much more than
about a couple days to maybe a week.
Because otherwise,
that's telling you that this
strength isn't really as
strong as it appeared.
The fact that it shook
out and it just blasted
right off, especially
if it's on big volume.
If it's on big volume,
you want to buy the first
pullback as it turns back
up to that first pullback buy.
You could even maybe even have bought a
little bit right here on that pullback.
But usually, you want a little bit more
pullback.
On that first entry of
September 19th, Mark, 99 RPR,
ATPR, buy risk, pressure,
all green across the board.
On this first entry, right?
Yeah.
So, it would have met all the criteria
there.
And that's, again, that's obvious, seeing
as, again, as I program those indicators.
But, again, another
nice thing about our
platform, and it's going
to be even much better.
Wait till you see the new platform.
You're going to be able to right-click and
hit Analyze.
And anywhere on the chart you are,
it's going to analyze it from right there
and analyze the trend and tell you what
criteria it's missing.
And it's really awesome.
But it's very cool.
You can go back and you can look at what
the RPR was back then and what the
criteria was so you could do lookbacks and
see, you know, when a stock was set up,
what kind of criteria it was meeting,
whether my indicators were bullish or not,
and things like that.
And we have some
really, really cool ways of
slicing and dicing that
in the new platform.
We put that on pullback
by Triggered on the
11th too, Mark, on
that day you highlighted.
I just double-checked it.
On the...
After the Hardaway crossover, the
one you pointed out was... Oh, over here.
I know that.
But that's, again, that just makes sense.
So, there you go.
Yep.
So, we did catch that.
A quick question, which is addressing the
platform.
Ben is asking, are the charts going to be
available on the mobile app?
And that is, yes, that is part of the
upgrade to the platform.
Well, let me say this.
The mobile app is going to be basically
the website.
I forget what they call it.
I don't know the technical terms.
Sometimes it's not an app app,
like a separate app.
It's going to be you're accessing sort of
the site on there.
And that's temporary.
Then we're going to be
working on an actual app
that is designed
differently for the mobile.
We just haven't been able to do that yet.
And we want to have you have something on
mobile.
So, just bear with it.
But I'm not sure sometimes, you know,
the way it scales and sometimes,
you know, if the charts or things are
small on there.
I don't know how it's exactly going to pan
out because I haven't seen that yet.
But it's temporary.
And then we're going to have an actual
app.
And you will be able to
get charts, everything, or
pretty much everything
on the app on your mobile.
So, yes, the ultimate goal is to have
where you're going to be able to do
everything right on your phone,
charting, and everything.
Yeah, it's referred to as a wrapper.
So, it's wrapping the web-based browser
into a mobile platform.
So, it is not quite as clean.
That's to get you up to speed quickly with
the new platform.
And then give us the time to then build
out the app and do it right.
Yep.
So, Tamlin is saying, I used to screen 700
charts manually on the weekends.
On the weekdays, I only reorganized the
stocks on my focus list.
However, one of my friends suggested that
I should screen all 700 stocks every day
to get a good sense of the market theme.
Do you think this is necessary?
Okay.
So, Mark, did you hear that?
I'm not trying to process that exactly.
Well, I would say, listen, I did...
Look, we always want to be working
smarter, not necessarily harder,
you know, or a combination of the two.
But I do believe if you want
to get a feel for the market,
there's a certain amount of
screening you need to be doing.
The question is how much, of course.
That's what... But
I think everything...
If you're new, I would suggest you just go
in through the screens that, you know,
we provide and just get in the habit of
doing them every single day.
You'll find that, yeah, it might
be... I don't know what's on average.
Is it 500, 600 names or something like
that?
And then I do a little bit more over the
weekend.
So that's pretty much what I do.
But look, there are also times where I
just look at the watch lists.
Are they growing?
Are they shrinking?
I'm not saying I don't put in the work
every single day.
But I don't think... Are there a
few times where I do a little less?
Yeah.
But on average, I basically have been
doing the exact same amount of screening
every single day, really, since I got done
with the first master trader program.
It's probably on average 500, 600 names a
day.
And then maybe it'd be 1,000 on the
weekend.
Yeah, I'm going to give you a few minutes.
And we got to wrap it up after this.
At least I have to go.
And prior to that, too, I just want to
tell you, trading near the danger point,
I added to my S&PY short position this
morning right near the high.
I'm actually up on it as it's coming off
the high here.
And with a stop that I
don't even know how tight
it was, it was like literally
micro-microscopic.
I think if it went up like 30 cents,
I was out.
And because I take large dollar positions,
sometimes I do that.
But so, again, that's just, you know,
I just want to point out, again,
trading near the danger point.
You know, perfect example of trading near
the danger point.
As it's gapped up, it runs up here.
As it started to stall out off the highs,
I said, you know what?
And I actually did it twice.
I traded a little earlier,
I got stopped out,
like I think it was a
20 or 30 cent stop.
And then it went up a
little higher, it started
rolling over again, and
I went back in again.
So I added to my S&PY short position near
what I call the danger point.
Right now, the danger point for me is
today's high.
That's on the overweight.
Now, we're still short from the old high
where we're right here.
We actually originally shorted here.
And that's also very close
to the danger point, very
similar type of trade where
it was, you know, 1% away.
I think it's less than 1%.
So really, really super tight stops.
All right.
So let me answer your question,
and then we got to wrap it up.
As far as screening is concerned, I'm going
to give you some general rules of thumb.
First of all, I do heavy screening on the
weekend.
This is where I run a number of screens.
And I spend a lot of hours really digging
in and doing some really deep work.
During the week, I'm trading.
You know, the whole day's trading.
I don't have the time there.
I do lighter screening.
Plus, I've already screened the whole
market on the weekend.
So now I do lighter screening.
And the other thing I also do is I look
at, at least once a week, all the stocks
that I got stopped out of, the stocks I
sold.
Because sometimes the best stock you buy
is a stock you just sold to your own,
you previously owned, or even the stocks
that you currently own.
You know, they might be setting up buy
points to add to.
But what I would suggest
is that when you screen, you
screen within your strategy
and you have some cutoff.
You have to realize, here's another
very...
I talked about a word tolerance,
a very important word.
There's another really
important word when
you're a stock trader,
and that is sacrifice.
You have to sacrifice.
You can't be in everything.
You can't, you know, make everything a
candidate.
So when you have these
qualifiers, if you say, hey,
I'm cutting off at 89
relative strength, 89 RPR.
I'm making... I'm only buying stocks in
stage two uptrends.
Well, there's going to be stocks.
You're going to go back and look at,
oh, shit, that one that was 87.
Look, it took off.
That one that was not in a... That I read
that story about, and it sounded so good.
And it was in a stage four downtrend,
just doubled off the lows.
Oh, if I only bought that.
Again, that's all Monday morning
quarterbacking.
You have to sacrifice.
And that's the key.
The key is to narrow the focus
and to focus on the best names
that meet your criteria and
really look at an elite list.
Get it down to where you're looking at an
elite list.
And we've done that for you now.
If you just look at the A's and B's,
you could just go and run the stage two
screen with A's and
B's, and you're going to
see pretty much everything
that you need to see.
Fundamentally, you'll
have to dig in and see
some stocks are going
to have no fundamentals.
There'll be a biotech.
And the other screen you could run is just
the IPO.
So now you see all the IPOs, all the brand
new ones that are not in stage two uptrend
because they don't have enough time frame
to be in a stage two uptrend.
And you're going to see all the stocks
that are in uptrends.
And with that, simple sorting functions
can get you to where you need to get.
You know, screening is the least thing
that you have to worry about.
All right.
There is no magic screen.
Just look at the stocks that are in
uptrends.
Look at the IPOs and then do the legwork.
Go in there, roll up the sleeves and look
at the earnings.
Understand the story.
What kind of situation you're dealing
with?
Go back, read my first book, Categories
and Catalyst.
Understand what type of stock you're
dealing with.
And you'll understand the catalyst and
you'll put it into perspective.
And then look for those stocks to set up
in basis and trade them from VCPs.
That's how I made my fortune right there.
I just summed it up.
That's how Mark and Brandon made their
fortune.
And I'm still working on that fortune.
And that's how Bill O'Neill made his
fortune.
And that's how David Ryan made his
And I can go on and on and on.
That's how they did it.
Jesse Livermore made his fortune,
buying pivot points, looking at stocks
that met a certain criteria, and then
buying those stocks when they pivoted.
And buying in the direction of the trade.
So that's it.
I got to run now.
I got so much work to do with the gala and
the birthday party coming up.
It's mind-boggling.
I'll just add as we close, guys.
I think this is one of the better sessions
I can remember in a long time.
Yeah, there's a lot here today.
This is one worth listening to again.
I'm going to listen to it again myself.
This is a really, really good one.
And just to point out, too, I learn
myself.
I'm always learning.
So just keep that in mind.
We're never, ever at a point where we can
say that we are above learning.
And with that said, guys, we'll wrap up
today's session.
I know we didn't get through all the
questions.
Just save those questions for the next
time we have the opportunity.
With that, though, the replay will be
available in the next few minutes.
Remember, markets are closed on Thursday.
We'll have the replay available here
momentarily.
And stay tuned to the live
stream for any and all real-time
alerts that are posted for
the remainder of the week.
No earnings with any of the names that we
have currently.
And we will get back at it very soon.
Thank you.
Mark and Mark for your time.
See you guys later.
Bye-bye.