Okay, guys.
Happy Wednesday.
Everybody obviously
doing this today because
Brandon and I are going
to be traveling tomorrow.
Looking forward to seeing
everybody that's going to
be at the gala and the big
birthday bash this weekend.
So just, yeah, we'll try and go for about
an hour here.
Just going over Q&A.
Obviously, market's snapping back pretty
strongly, kind of to be expected.
Not necessarily, you
know, with the headlines of
CPI, but we're, you
know, short-term oversold.
Look, you can just get on a chart of the S
&P here.
Coming back to the 50 would be normal.
And listen, this is where
you just start looking for,
you know, one, do we
get distribution right away?
And then how do names act?
You know, that's really what I'm focused
on.
We've had some names that have held up.
Obviously, focus list is acting well, but a
lot of those names have sort of gapped.
But that's still, we'd
rather see, you know,
can those then set up
follow-up buy points?
Do we get other names kind of setting up
in their wake?
So get any questions.
Michael is asking, have you ever considered
only trading the true market leaders?
This would limit the basket of possible
stocks to about 12 names.
In my experience, even a
mediocre setup of true market
leader works better than a
perfect setup in a mediocre stock.
Well, I guess my question there would...
That's sort of like saying, in my mind,
why not just only buy the winners in
general?
You know, like I could sit there and
post-trade analysis and go, you know,
shoot, if I, you know, had only traded,
you know, all the names that worked out,
we don't know which ones are the true
market leaders in real time.
Now, if, if what you're referring to is
saying, you know, names with big earnings
and sales on the table are more of those
classic can slim type setups versus maybe
ones that, you know, don't
have any fundamentals on
the table yet, but that are
just like higher momentum.
Well, that's fine.
And we've got a number of, I know a number
of folks who do that.
And you'll even hear me say
things like, you know, there's
certain groups I, I tend to
prefer or favor over others.
But I don't know where you're getting 12
names from.
In some cycles, there'll
be, you know, a lot
of names that continue
to base and rebase.
It's been a little bit more selective
recently.
But if, look, that's fine.
If you want to focus on, you know,
being more of a position trader in,
in say, like a name like NVIDIA last year,
but that's absolutely fine.
And we've got a number of, you know,
clients on the service.
I know several folks, you know,
that, that traded in NVIDIA, you know,
or held positions of it all last year are
still in portions of it.
So this is where you've got to kind of
define what kind of trader you want to be.
And, and then being okay with the
sacrifice.
You can't be all the things,
you know, or as Mark would
say, you can't kiss all the
girls or dance with all of them.
You gotta, you gotta, you know,
sort of stick to your knitting there.
I don't know, Brandon, any...
I think that's really well said.
You know, listen, given the work that we,
we do every day, we've just found that,
you know, that's, that's not how we want
to do things.
Yeah.
We're in the market leaders when they set
the, the, when they set up and there's low
risk entry points, but we don't want to
just limit ourselves just to, to,
again, we're always looking
for setups, things coming
out of well-defined
bases that are breaking out.
Well, I'll give you an example,
even from, from our work last year,
like ONON, which a number of people, we
were buying this name, you know, right here.
And Brandon and I, you know, we liked this
name a lot.
Primary base, good fundamentals, know a
little bit about the product and the story.
Classic, you know, growth situation.
In my mind, this looked like a key leader,
you know, breaking out here.
It was a nice trade, but this hasn't been
a barn burner.
You could still be in it.
We traded around portions of the position.
We're not, not a position right now.
Rather than digging in with an opinion
that ONON, I know is a key leader.
No, it's a primary base.
It has good fundamentals.
It should be traded, in my opinion.
And I'd give this setup more the benefit
of the doubt than a different one,
where you could have said, well,
NVIDIA, everybody knows at its later stage.
It had a bigger move.
So I don't want to necessarily,
yeah, dig in with that harsh of an opinion
on any one name and let, let the trades
come to me.
And then the setup tell me based upon how
it's acting, you know, after I get in it.
Greg is saying, last
year, I tracked my trades
for entry type and
short-term versus swing.
My strongest edge was swing trades from a
cheat entry.
Buying from a base breakout was a loser
for me.
My question is, if you would press the
reset button with a new year and market
correction, or should I use these numbers
for guidance until they change?
That's an interesting question.
First of all, the most important thing is,
you know, one, you're tracking everything.
And two, I think that if you're buying
properly, whether it's cheats,
maybe, and you're saying breakouts to new
highs, if I went back through probably
over the last year, I would probably see
something similar, Greg.
I would say that's more a function of
maybe the type of market we've been in.
And there might be periods where you just
get more cheats, say, than handles,
or you get more pullback buys than other
specific setups.
So in terms of resetting, I wouldn't reset
in the way of saying, you know,
take all the old numbers and they don't
matter anymore.
It also may be that you're just more
comfortable with the cheat.
And that's where I would have said I tend
to be, and probably even still tend to be.
Like, I prefer to buy the cheap or the low
cheap versus, say, the high handle.
But it doesn't mean I won't trade it.
So I'm just sort of taking that into
effect.
And then also always asking myself,
what's, you know, sometimes you get,
if the market runs off the lows,
maybe, or sets up in a certain way,
take like COVID, we have a lot of V-shaped
charts, and we had more sort of,
you know, compressed right sides.
That was sort of that theme in the market.
But I wouldn't then go back and say, well,
compressed right sides are all working.
And I should always trade those going
forward, if you know what I mean.
But it's a good question.
I would just continue to track stuff.
And then, listen, favor, obviously,
the cheat, if that's where the numbers are
telling you, hey, this is where my major
profits have come from.
You know, I wouldn't, again, ignore a
different setup.
I would tend to stick with what's working.
Yeah.
Sorry about that.
Yeah, Greg, I think you're thinking about
it right, too.
Because I really like the last part of
your question, where you make a statement
saying, should I use these numbers for
guidance until they change?
Yes, absolutely.
If you're paying that close attention to
your numbers, and you can see the change,
then that's the information you're waiting
for.
Gabby's saying, what was the
thinking for now taking an MSP
position in bros and not
staying in the waiting approach?
What changed?
In other words, why not put a toe in the
water before bros?
Well, you could have.
There's nothing wrong with that.
Wanted to see a few different,
you know, pitches, if you will.
There's nothing wrong with this setup.
We had a market that, you know,
even like, like I was saying, if you look
at the general market, getting oversold a
little bit, but then you had a number of
names kind of still holding up,
setting up.
I would have preferred to
see, you know, a number
of the names stay tight
and not gap even yesterday.
You know, as the market's coming off the
lows, that's where you want to see a name
like a bros, take a swing at a name that's
held up really well, where, you know,
even taking a look at this, you know,
here's your general market.
This has sort of been going the other way.
It looks like a leader.
This is where you could take a stab at it.
You know, you could have bought it over
here.
And we talked about this too.
It's a little, little short, a little
sloppy, but it held up well.
But you don't have to take as many pitches
as you want until, you know, you're,
you feel like it's time to take a swing.
Eventually though, you got
to swing at something and
that's where you start small,
but always be incremental.
And as long as there, if there's ideas on
focus, the market could be off.
I don't even think about the general
market, you know, as taking my cues from
that, but is, if there are ideas and low
risk entry points that are tight,
you can always take a position,
take it really small, take it even,
take it almost meaningless size.
But looking for that feedback
to say, hey, low risk entries
are starting to work or
breakouts are following through.
That's really what we're looking for.
See, Chris is saying in shaky market
conditions, often sell half of a trade for
a small gain, but then get indecisive
about what to do with the second half
because of the overall trade's potential
to lower my average gain stats.
For example, okay, good.
Love examples.
You bought hood on one three.
Let's just take a look at that right here.
Okay.
So it looks like you're buying it maybe
coming through.
I mean, you could call this a little
cheat.
It's definitely short and not something
that I would have played.
Aggressive.
I thought it was aggressive.
Okay, good.
I agree with you there.
So put a stop at two and a half percent at
the low of the day.
Sold half or five percent gain the next
day.
Widened my stop to five percent,
which has kept me in the trade.
If I closed out the
position today, the back
half of the trade would
be 13 percent gain.
The overall trade, nine percent gain.
It's below my average, but just barely.
So the question is, are you more likely to
hold the second half of a trade for bigger
move so that you don't hurt your stats,
even if the market conditions or the
stocks action make that seem like a high
risk play?
Good question.
And I like the way, first of all,
it seems to me, Chris, like you
understand, first of all, your own
metrics.
And I like, okay, you played something
aggressive.
You stayed tight.
You de-risked it quick.
Well, then I think you're thinking about
it exactly the way I would think about it.
Then you want to see how does the name
act?
Well, right here, now
you're getting short-term
extended as well, but you're
in a 98 relative strength.
You know, you got a market
that is just kind of coming off the
lows and this is stock is going
right into new high ground.
So I would probably even take the middle
road, maybe even kick out another piece,
cut it in half again.
But, you know, even to that point about your
average gain, you're right around there.
You're 1% below your average gain.
If you're happy with the trade,
that's where you just step aside.
You know, this is, this is the part
though, where I go, look, if you,
if you were able to hold this name through
a market that's getting wobbly,
I would at least try
and hold a little bit of a
piece that that's not
about the metrics though.
That's about where we are in terms of
you're in a name that's acting really well
coming out of a, you know, this is that
potential, maybe even beach ball,
you know, that you've been holding
underwater.
The minute the pressure, again,
this is where I was, this is where I look
at the general market in relation to the
stock I own.
So the minute the pressure comes off the
general market, this stock, boom,
comes right out here into new high ground.
That's what you want to see from a leader.
Now you happen to get on it a little bit
early.
Well, great.
So that's where I would say, you know,
take at peak, take again, de-risk it
again, put yourself in a position where if
everything comes back in, you're still at
a net gain, which is what you've already
done.
So I think it's like, if I was given
grades, I'd give you an A across the board
and say, you know, maybe potentially play
a piece for a little bit bigger.
Russell is saying, how
to plan to get ahead
when I can't be watching
charts all the time.
How, maybe how do I plan to get ahead?
How could I have planned to de-risk this
morning, not knowing position would jump up?
Well, okay.
So you're giving me the ticker after the
fact here.
Well, first of all, we don't
ever know ahead of time
in terms of when positions
are just going to go.
So that's why you always have a,
you know, have a plan for everything.
It's something Mark always talks about.
Look, you'll never trade perfectly.
You can perfectly follow a plan.
You bought a position SRAD on Jan 6th.
Another good example of if you're going to
be trading in an environment where things
have certainly been
less favorable on average
and where wins have
been harder to come by.
I like that you're looking
at a situation, higher RS,
it's clearly not being as
affected by the general market.
It's held up really well.
I don't love this entry point right here.
If it's Jan 6th, right there.
Sorry, trying to mark this for you guys.
There.
I'm not, yeah, I'm not in love with that
buy point.
And really at all, in my opinion,
you should have been buying maybe right
here or, or start a position as it,
you know, pokes its head out there.
While I was on a business
called the stock from first
to yes, down to yesterday's
highs, bought a quarter.
Okay.
And you're not really, I
guess, asking in terms of how
a specific in terms of
how to handle this situation.
But look, if I bought this here where I
would have been buying it, or maybe even
here as it's breaching these highs, you
really weren't put under much pressure here.
So in terms of like
planning ahead, it's as
simple as, you know,
where your stop should be.
And then once you're at, you know,
multiple of your risk, then you're,
you know, considering taking, you know,
multiples or kicking the trade out.
And I would use the same logic at,
you know, talking with the previous
question about, you know, something like
an HOD and probably de-risk the trade.
And one we were
selling, you know, I took a
small position in this
geo off our focus list.
Well, this morning into this gap,
we sold half the name.
Basically saying, look, de-risk it here.
And then hold a piece.
I see you're also talking about Wix.
Same question.
Okay.
So here's what I would say, Russell,
is like, if you have, this is where
pre-planning in the morning,
if you know, you're not going
to be in front of the screen
is probably really key for you.
So, you know, just to Marky's point,
ask yourself, where would I be selling a
piece or the whole thing if I might add a,
you know, 3R trade?
And then having that order in there
pre-market so that if the market gets
there, at least you
know, you know, you have
a good shot of selling
it at that price point.
I know there was a time
where I think I was getting
something, a procedure
done in the hospital.
This is before Marky and I were partners.
I was talking to Marky before,
you know, I'm in the bed and the nurse is
mad at me because she wants to put an IV
in.
I'm trying to get all my
orders in before I go under so
that I knew at least I was
covered once the market opened.
So I hope that's helpful.
Yeah, obviously, you know, pre-planning,
you know, is the... I can't remember what
was the old... having a plan is half the
battle.
Well, when it comes to
trading and that kind of stuff,
especially if you are working
a job or those types of things.
Nowadays, of course, you can set alarms
and things to your phone and it's easier,
but that's the type of stuff you got to do
ahead of time.
So if you know you're not going to be in
front of the screen, I mean, good example,
we're both traveling at the same time
tomorrow.
It's like, okay, we've got to have,
you know, things in place and we try not
to even, you know, generally, as a general
rule, if we've got positions on,
one of us is usually always in front of
the screen.
But if not, then we've got a contingency
plan for that.
So there's not really much I can add other
than thinking of it in terms, though,
of trying to always have a reasonable plan
for everything.
Because if you do this long enough,
lots of different things will happen.
There's lots of scenarios.
That way you're never,
you know, you want to avoid
that surprise, I don't
know what to do scenario.
So even in good scenarios, okay,
if you were in a name like Wix and it gaps
up 10% tomorrow, you a seller,
running through those things in your mind,
so you know ahead of time, this is what
I'm going to do.
Then you don't have all those emotions
that go with woulda, coulda, shoulda,
and Monday morning
quarterbacking, which,
you know, are just
generally not constructed.
So yeah, having those things in your mind
ahead of time, that way you're just simply
reacting to what's happening and following
your plan.
Devin is saying, please help with
technical analysis on adding to a position.
I understand that all trades have to stand
on their own, but it seems that all I do
when trying to add just messes up my cost
basis and spoils the trade.
Could you use the recent
purchase of bros to show
when technically one could
have added to the position?
Well, for starters, your comment about,
yeah, letting things stand on their own.
As a general rule, though, I don't want to
be adding, or if I'm adding at higher
prices, which is what I'm generally doing,
I only want to do so incrementally so that
I don't, you know, run up my average cost
basis too much.
But here, okay, if you own this name over
here, and this is precisely how,
let's say, if you start
with a smaller position,
the only spot I see
to add is yesterday.
Or if you don't own it, you buy it there
because you had the pullback, pulled back
to the breakout, you
caught good support,
and then the name
started to follow through.
So if you bought some here, maybe,
let's say you tried, you started a
position, stock comes in, it doesn't pull
down or pull back enough to hit your stop.
And then good tennis ball action,
right at a new high ground, two,
three day pullback, you get
that decent support inside
day, then following through
back into new high ground.
So here's where then you can incrementally
add to the name.
And here's where you can also do,
you know, raise your initial stop on the
whole position here, depending on how
aggressive you want to be.
This is precisely how, you know,
we would trade around a name or add,
you know, to a name that's acting well,
because the setup is potentially improving.
That's the other thing I always want to
ask myself.
Do I feel like if I didn't own it,
would I buy it here?
That's the that's the first question.
And is it improving?
If the situation is getting better, then
theoretically, I want to own more of it.
So that's kind of how we think about it.
Roberto was asking about Reddit.
Saying I bought it on the third.
Let's take a look at that.
Okay.
Right here.
So I'm guessing you were using maybe this
day as some sort of, you know,
as it turned back up,
maybe not a pivot, very
aggressive, not, not an
entry I would have used.
Next day was up 10% above my average gain.
But since it was performing well at the
time, I decided to hold that position.
The following day, I pulled back 8% from
the high with the general market.
So I decided to reduce near break even.
Can you comment on my trade?
My initial plan was to hold, but I didn't
like the 8% pullback in one day.
Well, the 8% pullback
in one day is also a
function of the fact
that this is really short.
And, you know, you, you played something
really aggressively.
So, you know, you've got to account for
that.
And nothing about the
subsequent action after this entry
is surprising to me, because
you got a name that ran a ton.
It's really short.
You didn't have a really clear,
crisp pivot.
And so now the volatility just kind of
calm me down.
So this is where, even if I
was going to play it the way
you did, presumably you
bought it right through here.
I probably would have been really tight.
I wouldn't have gone to this low.
I probably would, if it just doesn't go,
I'm out.
And then I would have
de-risked into some of
this and probably got
knocked out at even.
Now it sounds like you
took sort of a different
approach where it
didn't follow through.
Maybe you just took the
whole trade off at even,
which is probably how I
would have handled that.
Because I don't want to be stuck in this
back and forth action, especially,
like I said, in a name where the pivot
wasn't well defined to begin with.
So it just wasn't a great buy point
because, again, you'll hear me ask,
where's the pivot?
And even using this day, you know,
you're looking at just, you know,
it's what, eight, eight and a half percent
using the width of that day.
If I'm going to take an eight,
eight and a half percent stop on
something, I want to see at least a better
technical pivot than what I see right here.
Let's see.
Attila is saying, I'm new, but welcome.
Purchased a 25% position of MTRA on Jan
3rd.
Right there.
Okay.
Here.
Make sure you're using,
you know, maybe this
little, I guess you'd
call that a little cheat.
Well, 163, another 50%, or 165 the same
day.
Can you comment on this?
Also, if the remaining 25%, the allocation
should be purchased, one would be good.
Not 100% sure what you're asking in that
follow-up question.
Look, this is short.
And this was one, you
know, we're kind of watching
last year, just sort of
stair-stepping itself up.
And, you know, it's gone through a number
of these shorter bases, if you will.
Held up pretty well.
Look, if you're going to
play something short like
this, I'd much prefer to
do it off of the low cheat.
But, you know, given
the overall action, I even
think they're better names
than this one to play.
And at this point, I would be,
if you, you know, use that one,
I certainly probably would move a stop to,
you know, to this area.
Don't love this reversal at this point.
It looks like you've got some supply now
it's contending with up at this area.
And that's what you
get, again, for, you
know, sort of those
shorter right-hand sides.
I'm not 100% sure what that second
question you asked was.
So if you want to maybe
put it, put that back in the
chat box in terms of, you
know, some more clarity.
Matthew is giving his stats, saying 2024,
32% batting average, average gain of just
over seven, average loss just over two and
a half.
And with adjusted win loss of 1.32.
Saying from January to March, I was up
about 15%, finished the year up seven,
seemed like a battle
the rest of the year,
stepping in the gas and
slamming on the brake.
Yep, I can relate to some of that.
Reviewing my trade seems like I was
positioned larger in losing trades,
smaller my winners, or trimmed winners too
quickly.
Just asking what you think going off the
stats.
Well, first of all, look, your stats are
positive, which is good.
That lower win rate is really
kind of something we've
been seeing, you know, over
the course of the last year.
And we're in that similar category,
a little bit lower win rate.
That's a function of the market.
And the fact that things are just a little
bit more selected, you still have an edge.
And I think that's what will ramp up,
you know, that adjusted win loss will
likely go from say 1.3 to 1.8, maybe
two or higher in a much better environment.
So that's where, you know, again,
I think you're doing a good job.
You're certainly doing a good job with the
average loss and your gain is,
you know, close to three times that.
So it's just a function of, you know,
waiting for a little bit better waters in
terms of, you know, the overall
environment that win rate picks up.
I think your edge is going to be that much
better.
One is saying, I'm
new, still in need of
more knowledge, your
knowledge and expertise.
When a stock's pivot is in
single digits, how do you know
it needs more time or an
additional tighter contraction?
Not when it's time compressed.
Example, Wix, CRS, ERJ.
Let's take a look.
Wix, we talked about, and remember we were
saying, and Mark covered this on Monday,
saying that, you know, yes, this looks a
little bit short, but we're in a period
where the market's
coming under pressure and
this stock is refusing
to give up ground.
And we're looking for a little bit more
tightening here.
So to answer your question, when do we
know we need a little bit more time?
Well, look, some of this is based on
experience and precedence, but the idea
of, like, when do we know for certain when
we need a little more time versus,
was this acceptable?
Yeah, but is it really crisp right here?
No.
So another, you know, even if we'd have
gotten, you know, one, two days right
here, this just has a better look to it
than what we have.
And I would, the other
symbols you put in there,
you know, I would put
in that same category.
And it's also a function of how aggressive
do you want to be?
I was just going over, someone was asking
me about, you know, you know, we got
questions on this from
last year where I was
just saying, okay,
this was really tight.
We're looking at Tesla and
I'm watching Tesla again
here, seeing if we can get
some type of a little cheap.
I'd jump back in this because it's held up
pretty well.
There's a stock, one of the most obvious
stocks in the entire world has doubled.
It's power play-esque.
Even again here, you know, if you look at
the weekly, I'm looking for that.
The way I think about this one is the
tighter, the better, because you're just
torquing that risk reward ratio in your
favor.
So a lot of you guys, you know,
want to play certain IRS names and I go,
well, look, if I've got to wait eight to
10, 12% to know if I'm right or wrong,
or if my timing's right, that
means a two to one puts me at,
I got to wait for 20% on the
upside just to make two to one.
I don't like that.
Where a situation like this, where I was
nibbling on the name here as it's coming
off the lows and adding to it,
it's breaking out at its widest spot.
It's 2%.
At 10%, I'm at 5R.
That's the difference.
That's why I, if all things being equal,
I'm always going to prefer the tighter,
the better.
Some of this, when
you're saying you're new,
the more you do this,
the better you'll get.
That's all I can say in terms of
identifying, you know, those right sides.
And then you'll be shocked how you go
through a year doing this and you're
thinking like, okay, my eye's getting
better.
I feel like my eye is so much better than
it even was six, seven years ago.
And I'd already been doing this, you
know, eight or nine years at that point.
Brandon, you want to add to that?
Well, yeah, Juan, I
was just going to say,
listen, you're not too
far off on CRS and EJR.
We were just being really, you
know... We're being picky right here.
Exactly.
So, yeah, I think your analysis of those
names is right.
We are just, again, given the conditions
in the market, we're being, yeah,
super picky.
Next question here.
Sorry, you're making sure I'm not missing
a question from Bob.
Don is asking about CXW saying,
on the training session held January 6th,
Mark spent some time explaining why buying
CXW at a higher price would be preferable
to a lower because there's less overhead
supply.
With that in mind, please help me
understand why it's okay to buy stocks at
a low or mid-cheat when there's always
overhead.
Please give me your own experience using
low or mid-cheat entry points.
Well, your first observation there,
Don's correct.
By definition, the cheat has more supply
to contend with than the handle.
But if you often look at... and the low
cheat, of course, a little bit more.
So, and this would be an interesting study
even within our own numbers.
Probably the pure win rate, I would guess.
I'm just guessing because I've never
actually broken it down set up by set up
where I've said, okay, every
low cheat I've ever taken
and every cheat I've ever
taken and every high handle.
But if I did, the win rate
on the low cheat is probably
a little bit lower, but
the multiple is higher.
So, I'm accounting for that as I use the
low cheat.
But then I'm also always drawing a line.
How much supply are we talking about?
And Mark, with this particular example,
I think was talking about how,
you know, we were talking
about it over here, where we're
saying we've got quite a
bit of supply in this range.
Reversal there, reversal here,
reversal here.
So, this stock is already showing you it's
having trouble getting through that level.
And reversal, you know,
and this is probably before
we even said it, it came
back up and reversal.
So, if you're playing it right here,
still sloppy.
See how even right here, this volatility
is widening.
So, we're just saying, like, we want to
get through some of that.
And you can see coming right back up to
this level again and putting in a reversal.
The stock is contending with supply at
that level.
So, this is that where we want to see it,
you know, calm.
Now, imagine if it calms down right in
here.
It even puts in, you know, three, four
days and then lines up with this level.
Then as the stock comes out, put your stop
right here.
We've come through all that.
You've only got a tiny bit of supply left
to contend with.
So, this was a probably
more of a specific
example, but that's why
each one in a vacuum.
This is such a good
example rather than saying,
well, why should we
prefer one versus the other?
In this case, we want that tightening to
line up with where the stocks had,
you know, trouble getting
through that level as a
sign that that supply is
no longer coming to market.
The stock's, you know, going to move more
at ease.
Remember, the whole goal is we want to
stack as many things in our favor as
possible so that that stock
is moving with ease back
in the direction of the
dominant trend, the uptrend.
Timothy's saying, can you explain the bros
trade?
Only went up 84% in eight weeks.
Had an RPR 96, so not really a power play.
Short.
Prior to two days were average volume.
The previous day closed in the lower half
of the day's range.
The best setup for a pullback buy.
It wasn't an especially tight stop either.
Looks like the type of setup to buy when
things are going well, not when you're
coming from 100% cash in a hard penny
environment.
I don't think... I disagree with a few of
the comments, but again, like we said,
okay, we've got a market that's been in a
correction.
This stock is begrudgingly pulling back.
Now, you're right.
It's not a textbook power play.
I put this more in the really primary
base.
This is a name so I can go even wider.
You know, that this
is kind of the first...
We were watching this
name several years ago.
And it's a name I know a little bit about
fundamentally.
It's got decent fundamentals on the table.
It's in the consumer retail area.
And again, it's just held up really well.
So this is where context matters.
A short base that's not quite a power
play.
As the market's really extended and names
aren't really working is a no-fly zone.
A short base, as the market's
already corrected, where
the stock is refusing to go
down, is a different scenario.
See how the context changes?
Now, I'm not saying this was
a... This isn't a gangbusters setup.
It's not somebody
didn't just slide you a pair
of aces and is betting
aggressively into you.
I'm just saying it's acceptable.
And this is the type of
name where I I think it's worth
a decent first shot or
foray back into the market.
And there were several others on focus.
You could have tried as well.
Yeah.
And, you know, listen, we did a half
position.
The risk is, you know, minimal.
So we're getting off a zero here.
And this was, you know, the one name that
was breaking out that we decided to buy.
Andrew's asking about LRN.
And here's the other thing.
Just because we're
highlighting the name we're
buying it doesn't
mean you have to buy it.
There are names, you know, on focus.
We don't trade or certain names that, you
know, maybe Mark puts on that we don't buy.
And that's just, that's part of trading.
Remember, the goal isn't to just buy
everything that either gets highlighted or
pointed out by the platform,
but to learn the techniques
and then uniquely apply them,
you know, in your own lane.
Andrew's saying, is LRN viable today if it
breaks out of the 112 level?
No.
This would be another example of,
if you were going to buy this name,
it really, you know, you
could have, you could
have, I would have been
buying probably right here.
Because you've got some sign of support
here.
You went tight for a day
and I would have bought
the next day as it poked
its head out on 1.6.
If I really wanted to own the name.
And then notice I'm measuring,
this is an acceptable stop level at,
you know, or you could stagger between
that low and this low, 4, 4-ish, 5%.
Now it's poked its head out, couldn't
follow through.
It's sort of widening.
If I wanted to buy the name, I'd wait for
this to subsequently tighten up a few more
days and set some type of better looking
right side.
Robby's asking about S-E-I.
I asked about it on Monday.
Don't think it was clear on the pullback
buy question.
Well, hopefully we can get that
straightened out.
I was interested in the pullback buy on
Jan 10th.
So you're looking at it.
Okay, so you're you're waiting.
You're using this day right here,
I'm guessing.
And as it comes through that high on the
10th, you wanted to buy it right there.
Wanted to know if the low volume sell,
despite being a large sell bar of around
eight and a half percent on Jan 7th,
weren't giving me giving S-E-I the benefit
of the doubt when it's set up in the 10th
pullback buy, or was it was this bad in
general and I made a big deal out of
nothing?
Good question.
I'm not I'm not sure I'm not sure which
he's referring to.
Yeah, which day you're referring to.
Hold on, Jan 7th.
I don't see... First of all, Jan 7th was
not even above average, say, down day.
Now, in terms of this stock, you know,
closed down 6%, not great.
And keep in mind, we're talking about a
situation that's pretty short.
So this, again, you know, if you're going
to play, you know, this type of a pivot,
this would be normal.
I actually like your buy better because
it's a little bit tighter and you're more
or less trading right near the danger
point.
I'm measuring... You're still
about 5%, but 99 RS, so you're...
If you're going to buy this,
you should have bought
it on 110 as it poked its
head right through there.
Stop at that low.
And if it goes, you're in it.
And if it doesn't, you're not.
So that's how I would have handled it.
I think if this was a name I knew more
about or really wanted to be on board,
I would have been looking at the same way
you were.
I just wouldn't have let this day,
you know, potentially keep me from buying.
You're also asking about ERJ.
Want to know if it was a bit aggressive or
sloppy.
I entered a small position on the 13th
based on a pullback buy.
Let's take a look.
13th, right?
Yep.
There.
You're buying it right here using
presumably that high as your trigger.
Got stopped on the 14th.
However, I noticed
it took out the high of
the 13th even though it
was on an outside day.
The stop loss was about 3.14% and I
entered a small position again.
So you bought it back
and you're wondering,
I guess, you know, if
that was acceptable.
Well, first thing, normally, if I'm really
tight, which it sounds like you were,
that affords you to be able to do what you
just did.
So, okay, you got shaken out here and you
went right back in.
I think that's fine.
I don't love it in this particular setup.
But again, this is where if you're going
to jump back in and aim because you think
you're a part of the shakeout
and that happens to us, if
you're going to be a low-risk
trader, you will get shaken out.
That's just part of the deal.
So you got to account for that.
And this is where I like the fact that
stop loss is two and a quarter and,
okay, you get a 10% gain.
You can take, you know, at
least three shots at that and
still, you know, be pretty
close to a two-to-one trader.
So, I don't love this particular
right-hand side as much.
You know, it's not, it's kind of short.
It's, it's not really as high a momentum
name.
It's in the defense area.
But, you know, maybe you
know something about it or there's
a reason you wanted to own
it and you stayed tight on it.
So, all things being equal, I think it's
an okay use of the tactics.
Let's see.
Harpreet was asking about those bros and
GEV viable on the third.
We talked about GEV, you know,
again, Mark was talking about how,
say you got this cluster
of good closes and we
were saying, you know,
this could coincide in it.
Again, it didn't and just gapped out.
You really had to be more aggressive on
this one.
On the third, we talked
about that as well and I was
saying this is where I wanted
to see another tightening.
Well, I didn't get it and that's where,
you know, you could say, well,
you shouldn't have been with mine being
patient waiting to see what I want to see
and if I was going to buy it as I talked
about, I would have started with a smaller
position to account for the fact that it's
a little bit wider on the right side.
Same logic with bros and then CHW we
already talked about but yeah,
GEO on the eighth.
Yeah, you could have bought this on the
eighth.
I think you could have started this one.
This was sort of the problem.
You had, it was tightening up here then it
went outside.
It followed through.
I liked this action here where you got,
you know, sort of back-to-back good closes
and then we were buying, yeah,
on this, I want to say it was on this day,
took a small position.
David's asking about W-A-Y.
Here's a really good example of a name
talking about being a part of the shakeout.
Who bought that?
I think, did we buy this name right here,
Brandon?
And it shook it out the next day and then
only to watch it, you know, rip.
Obviously, really strong name,
newer issue.
It's just short, which is exactly what
you're putting in your comment, David.
So I agree with you.
It's just, it's just too short right now.
What was your preferred price behavior for
a possible entry?
I just need more time here.
You know, this, it's not long enough to be
a base.
It's not strong enough to be a power play.
So it's just in that no-fly zone.
You got to wait.
One saying, sorry for the basic question.
For starters, don't ever apologize for
basic questions.
There's nothing wrong with that at all.
We encourage, you know, from the most
basic to the most advanced.
We'll do our best job to answer it
wherever it falls in that spectrum.
Curious that I've had since Red Minervini
and later O'Neal, when you count the
length of the base in weeks, do you start
from the top of the cup or like O'Neal who
waited for the first week
for example, CXW, you
know, asking, I guess,
where does the base start?
Yeah, I would just start right from the
clear high.
And even then, I wouldn't even,
if it's a few days different or even one
week, it's not going to be a huge
difference.
The key is getting, my eye goes here to
the right side.
Whenever I'm looking through stuff,
I don't count the, I'm just looking,
especially when I'm
screening or looking at
potential ideas,
looking at that right side.
And that's where my eye goes immediately.
If it's not tight or actionable,
it's just on to the next idea.
So, yeah, don't get overly obsessed with,
you know, sort of where exactly to start
the base count versus looking at the
precedents and honing your eye in terms of
what does a really good right side look
like?
What does a really well-developed VCP look
Lance is saying, what did you guys buy
this week?
If anything, please describe why you chose
that stock and the setup.
Thanks.
Did we buy anything this week,
Brandon?
Bros.
Yeah, we bought Bros.
We did buy a little position in Tesla as
well, but sort of being creative.
And I'll tell you exactly how
and why we handled that because
we took the position here,
sold nicely into this move.
And this is where sometimes we'll take the
attitude, okay, we'd like to maybe play
this for a bigger move, but it just got
what I would almost call stupid extended
in the short run, like
especially with a name like
this where it just, you
know, a pullback's coming.
We'll kick out the position and then lean
on that to buy it back where we think it
should find, you know, some kind of
support.
So we nibbled back, you know, a little bit
right here.
And we're using this to pay for this,
if that makes sense.
but really haven't done a whole lot just
yet.
And, you know, this is where I found and
Marcus talked about how nobody minds being
under-trading or under-invested in a
market that isn't acting well.
Then all of a sudden you
get a market that starts
running off the lows and
everybody's like, I got to buy.
What can I...
It's like, listen, I've made far more
money waiting for the market to settle out
and buying a whole bunch of names higher,
even higher than they are now or at
different places when they set up
properly.
That difference between waiting for the
right price not the low price has been
truly a massive, massive sort of aha
moment over time.
And massively wealth-accreted.
Tamlin, Sink, and Hood and TWLO will be
included in the focus list.
Yeah, if they continue to
hold up well, those are two
names they sort of got on
that high RS polls type list.
I think so.
And if they stay tight and hold up well,
I think you'll see it on there.
Let's see.
Elliot's saying, great to join live from
Myrtle Beach.
I think that means if
you're coming for that,
that'd be great if that's
what your comment implies.
How do we think about risk on total equity
versus individual trade risk?
I noticed you take a certain position
size, 12 or 25.
Are these sizes only acceptable if the risk
on total equities within a certain range?
And are you always backing into risk on
total equity?
Brandon, you want to kick us off?
absolutely.
We're always aware of what total equity
risk is.
But listen, again, if we have a 25% position
and we're taking 5% risk, isn't that 1.
25% of total equity?
So, again, we always have that in mind.
But as things work, that expands quickly.
We're not too worried about adding to that
risk to a certain point.
And to be even more clear, in terms of
risk to total equity, we know that on
every trade, we know it on all trades
combined.
And every day.
Every day.
Like, we always know our worst case
scenario.
So, yeah, absolutely.
And we're certainly not going to get heavy
in anything where the stop is even wider
on average for us because of exactly what
you highlighted there.
Costas is saying he bought CRS on Monday.
I de-risked it when it reached 7%.
Okay.
Cut half.
If the stock consolidates
in that level and breaks
out again, does it make
sense to add it back?
Generally, do you pyramid in a stock while
you've already de-risked it?
Sometimes, this is
where you wait to see
what the next card
out of the deck is, right?
Well, if this...
And this is the advantage of buying the
cheat and the low cheat.
Especially, this is where I like the low
cheat.
If you can get...
And this wouldn't be the
best example because you
really didn't get a crisp
low cheat down here.
But where you can get a low cheat where
you can trade out at 2 or 3 to 1 prior to
the stock even making
new highs or breaking out of
the base, you can have
your cake and eat it too.
Where you can de-risk the trade, then
wait to see how does it set up from there.
And it sounds like you took a tight stop
on this, maybe coming through this pivot,
pulled off a piece here.
Well, now you just got to wait.
Look, if it does one of these and gets
extended, you just sell into that.
But if you get some type of a handle,
and this is where, again, once you know
the difference between normal and abnormal
price action, maybe you get a pull back
buy and you can add
a little bit back here and
then it turns into a handle
or something like this.
And we bump the name that way.
There's a number of ways these things can
go, but if they're really under
accumulation and acting right,
there's only three, four, five different
techniques on this right side where you
can potentially add the shares back.
But this is, again, we're
learning to be incremental, trading
around a portion of your
position, you're handling it right.
And I would have started smaller on a name
like this anyway, or any of these names
right now because the environment has not
been, you know, unless you're really
short-term trading and had
a ton of traction, I wouldn't
be getting super aggressive
with anything right here.
Daniel saying looking
forward to the gala and seeing
everyone, it's just a good
time to enter the SPY.
If you're talking about trading the model,
you got to get in sync with the model.
We don't trade the models for our own
account.
And we don't trade the SPY the way you're
describing.
So I'm not really 100% sure.
I would not, certainly just
looking at the right-hand
side, I would absolutely not
be buying the S&P right here.
And if I'm going to
trade the index, it's
because it's meeting
the same type of criteria.
I'm looking for that tight right side.
We will trade the
indexes on occasion or
something like the SOX,
the SMH when they set up.
But again, it's because it's got that
tighter right side.
Our risk is well defined and VCP
characteristics.
Franco is saying a question
about how to be more
organized and efficient
when creating watchlists.
I get messed with tickers
and end up with 25 or more
tickers in focus, which is
difficult to handle at the open.
I don't know, Brandon, you want to at least
give them in terms of how we handle it?
Oh, yeah.
So listen, sometimes in a good period,
we'll have 25 names and before the open is
really when we set all the alarms so that
way we're not having to click on every
single chart every second to see what it's
doing.
So that way the alert pops
up saying, hey, XYZ stock
is going through the price
point we want to watch.
And if it's something we're buying,
obviously we're buying it right away.
We have those orders queued up,
so all we have to do is hit transmit.
But again, alerts are everything to us,
so we don't miss anything that way.
And sometimes we put
alerts below the pivot, so we're
watching it as it potentially
is going through the pivot.
But listen, right now, 25 figures seems
like a lot to me.
So maybe really review the
names that are on your watch
list and see how close
are they really to a pivot.
If they're anything more
than 8%, you probably don't
need to be watching that
right now, or at least intraday.
And the follow-up question was about SEI,
whether it was viable today, listen,
this is I'm just measuring.
Is it acceptable if you wanted to own this
name?
It's mid-single digit and it's 99RS.
So in that sense, yeah, you could have.
I like to pull back by a little bit
better, but if you had to put a position
on it and a name, this isn't
the worst place to potentially
be buying SMTC, the other
one you were asking about
I like this a little less in terms of,
because it's a little wider.
Again, always measuring.
And you sort of gap through 8%.
Yeah, and I don't know what it was up,
you know, what was up on the day when it
hit this level or either of these levels
is probably even more aggressive play.
And as a general rule, when the market is
gapping up, guys, we're not buying stuff.
We're not playing that game.
Yeah, it usually costs us more.
Yeah.
When I get the market gapping up,
it's just like, oh, no.
Yeah, exactly.
I saw another hedge fund
manager friend of mine saying the
same thing on X today going,
you know, I hate gap opens.
That's how pros think.
And what we mean by gap, you know,
when a market's gapping one and a half
percent from an oversold condition,
I'm not saying you can't, you know,
buy names if they're breaking out of,
you know, good low risk entries.
But we didn't have a ton of those today.
Gal saying just sharing that it's
frustrating to wait and wait for the pivot
point with low risk and then most of the
names on the watch list are gapping up.
It's way more frustrating in my experience
to lose money.
So there's a price to pay for everything.
If you just want to trade everything,
that's great.
You can do that all you want, but you
probably won't make any money.
It's like I've made the point before,
you can trade everything you ever want to
or you can have discipline, but you can't
have both.
So which would you rather have?
And there are names all the time that I'm
waiting for.
They don't quite tighten up or look right
and you got to let them go.
But that's the cost to do it.
That's just the cost, again, of being
disciplined and having strict criteria.
I don't know, Brandon, we've been doing
this long enough to experience where if
you're not patient and you're not
disciplined, the cost, you know,
the fear of losing money
is greater than the cost, you
know, this idea of missing
out on a gap like today.
We could care less about that because we
have the confidence and the experience now
to know we're going to
get what we're looking for
eventually and then we're
going to really make money.
So we're always thinking risk first.
So breaking discipline is risky.
So that's why we're willing to just sit
and wait.
And I get it, when you're new,
the uncertainty is just eating at you
because you don't know if this is your
moment.
If it's not quite tight enough,
start, be incremental.
Be small.
Because again, you don't want to get
yourself into a hole.
What was the...
Sorry, here, give me a second.
you know, this is a name I wanted to own
over here.
And I talked about Reddit this way too.
It was a name I wanted to own and didn't
quite tighten up enough.
In hindsight, I could sit there and go,
that was a big mistake.
Maybe it was, but there'll be another one.
And similarly right here.
I really, this is probably
more of a party file than even
over here because as a primary
base is holding up pretty well.
coming out of this more corrective period.
In the general market, stock came right
back up near the high and tightened up.
If I'm going to grade
myself for not taking a setup
or being a little too
picky, this is where I'd be.
But here's how I look at it.
I'd much rather be too picky than way too
loose.
Because one saves you and the other harms
you.
how do you want to think about it?
But again, and the way to
handle that is if it's not quite tight
enough or maybe as tight as
you like it, you be incremental.
You start with a smaller size and then if
it tightens up and improves, you add.
Adam is asking, if you could
go back and give yourself one
piece of advice from when you
first started, what would it be?
That's a really good question.
Actually, we're going to
obviously talk about this weekend,
so Adam, you're kind of
cutting into our spiel, if you will.
Are we talking about how we basically got
to where we are today?
So I think that question is definitely
part of of that journey.
And for me, it would be, I just wish I was
more patient with the process.
I kind of wanted to rush everything.
I wanted the success quicker than it came
and I wish I would have been just more
patient with it and enjoyed maybe the
journey a little bit better.
I don't know.
What about you, Mark?
I would say that as well.
And one of the things that Mark said at
the very first semester trader program is
this idea of everyone, and this is true in
all areas of life.
We overestimate what
we can do in the short run
and underestimate what
we can do in the longer run.
And there's no question when it comes to
trading and in the markets and when you're
dealing with money and all the different
things that go with it, emotions and
experience, there's no replacing
experience.
Everybody thinks they're going to make a
million dollars their first year.
That's what I thought.
I'm going to be a millionaire my first
year.
I was only trading between $50,000 and
$100,000.
Was I really going to make 1,000% my first
year?
Never made 1,000% guys.
I've been fortunate enough to make many
millions.
But that experience and confidence,
I was just talking with this about
somebody else who's newer, saying listen,
I can give you an idea, I can give you a
stock symbol, I can give you a strategy,
but only you can develop the conviction.
And that only comes with time.
And those of you coming to the gala,
I think Renee's talk is going to be really
good, because one of the things she talks
about specifically is how going through
the process in the analytics gave her the
confidence she needed.
Well, no one else can can, how can you
give someone else confidence?
And this is true in anything in life,
confidence in, you know, in your,
in a relationship, in
a sport, in anything
you're doing, it just
comes with experience.
So be patient with yourself and work at
that.
Leif is asking about CRDO.
Yeah, this is, this is another one.
I'm really watching here for the same
reason.
It's just held up so well.
This is a power play because you got this,
you got this double.
It's not coming out of that period of
dormancy, but I would give this the
benefit of the doubt if we can get a right
side.
And you can see
where, as I look at this,
where's the tight area
to shoot at this from?
Well, we can know in relatively short
order.
Now, if this just goes like that,
you know, to a prior person's question
going, oh, you know, it
was frustrating to wait and it
never tightened up and then
tightened up and then took off.
It's like, well, yeah, the other price to
pay for that is getting in so wide.
So let's say it makes a move
like this and I buy tomorrow
or the next day through this
high and put my stop here.
Great.
I'm barely at a two to one.
I don't want that set up.
I'm in a situation where I can know in
relatively short order.
So I'd love to see this even if it comes
back up to the highs and then gives us a
tightening or some type of tight area that
we can shoot at.
You have to imagine that bar is not there.
We get something like this, you know,
just, you know, and now it's got,
you know, you've got a two T scenario,
that little two tightening, where if the
train's coming in on schedule,
then as it comes through, you've
eliminated all that supply and you've got
a mid single digit stop.
You get a 10% move, you're at a two or
three R.
That's what I'm looking for.
We already talked about bros and why we
like that one.
Go one or two more questions here.
Joey's saying what?
Two third position on GE.
On one three after quiet cell volume at
the end of and sold the query.
Let's see one three.
Right.
There.
Yeah, I don't like this setup for a
variety of reasons.
One, you're running into it.
The only thing I could say complimentary
on this is it's somewhat tight,
I guess, down here.
Maybe you're looking at this area,
but I'm looking here.
You got all this supply.
All this red right here.
That tells me you picked this off the low,
I guess, and traded it into this,
which is exactly if I had traded something
like this, I would de-risk a portion or
all of it because you're running into all
that supply.
It's an 84 relative strength.
And this stock is acting even relative to
the market, not very well.
And so I think there's just much better
names to be entertaining.
If you're going to be nibbling, I certainly
wouldn't have been doing it in this name.
Oh, he's saying G-E-V, not G-E-V.
Oh, I'm sorry.
My bad, Joey.
I see you.
Okay, so let's strike everything I just
said.
So you are looking in the right area then
in terms of an aggressive buy.
You bought it, yep, right here,
sort of as this is turning back up and
looking at this little area, how this
volume is drying up, saying and look,
this is, if you're, again, you're going to
play aggressive, this is how you want to
do it, expecting this to just get going
and now you're in the name.
Looks like, yeah, you took a little bit
smaller, sold a quarter of the position.
Look, I think you did it right.
This is exactly, you know, as it turned
back up or you could have maybe even
started it on that day and added as you
did when you got the good close.
Yeah, that's how you
trade near the danger point
and in the right area
to potentially do it.
Let's do one more.
Florencia is saying, this question for
Brandon, you mentioned a few trades in
your stock analysis,
which you guys entered with
full position, stops around
78%, for example, APO.
If the trade had gone the opposite
direction, would you have been
incrementally cutting
your position or would you
have honored to stop
even with the full position?
Yeah, so with those stock analysis reviews
that I've been doing, those are the
personally, we would not take, sit around
for a 7% or 8% stop on a full position.
We would be looking to cut it way sooner
than that, at least incrementally.
Incremental, right.
Yeah.
So again, like when, like, this is the
difference kind of, and Minervine would
probably say this as well, like,
we're giving you the suggested max stop on
those ideas with the
idea of like, you have
to, you're controlling
your own risk, right?
So you have to decide, am I okay with
taking a 7% risk on a full position?
And full position is relative to what you
think.
Listen, there are people I know who will
put their whole account in one name.
I've never done that ever in my entire
career.
But, and I can promise you anyone that's
doing that, if they're not really tight,
you will blow up and they're not going to
carry a 100% position, you know,
certainly overnight in a situation like
that.
Listen, if you're saying like,
hey, I'm willing to take a 25% position
and take an 8% stop and you're okay with
that total risk to equity, then okay,
do that.
But, yeah, we're going to be way more
incremental if we're taking a full
position to us, which is, you know,
20, 25%.
So, we don't want to take
a full stop, an 8% stop,
put it that way, on a
big position like that.
All right, guys, we're going about an
hour.
Obviously, I know we have a lot of other
questions.
Save them for next time and we'll get to
those.
And for those of you who are going to be
coming to the gala this weekend,
we look forward to seeing everybody.
Obviously, don't be shy.
There'll be a lot of us, but we'd love to,
you know, put faces to a lot of the names.
And, yeah, look forward
to seeing those of
you that will be there
and those that aren't.
Obviously, look for the weekend study
session and then we'll be back.
for Q&A, Mark, Bob, Weissman, and myself
on Tuesday.
All right, guys.
Hopefully, see you all this weekend.
Take care.