Okay, good morning and welcome to the
Minervini Private Access Training Room.
I'm Bob Weissman.
If you can raise your hand to let me know
that you're hearing me loud and clear.
Hope everybody who came to the gala event
enjoyed themselves.
I had a great time being able to see and
meet so many of you.
And also enjoyed watching
my Eagles win, playing
for now the Super Bowl
this coming weekend.
With that said, let's welcome Mark Ritchie
into the room as well.
Good morning, Mark.
Good morning, Bob.
Morning, everybody.
Also, just echo what Bob said.
Say a heartfelt thanks to everybody.
All the kind words, all the handshakes and
everything.
I just posted something on Twitter as
well.
But it was a great weekend.
An overwhelming one, but a really good
one.
Just raise your hand
real quick to let us know
you're hearing Mark
loud and clear as well.
Okay, that sounds good.
And also, let's get started with today's
session with the birthday boy,
Mark Minervini.
Good morning, Mark.
Good morning.
For those of you that were at
the party and the weekend, you
probably know why I didn't do
a study session this weekend.
Still recovering.
A heck of a weekend, as those of you who
came know.
Real quick, we're going to do a highlight
reel.
For those of you who weren't able to come
to the event, we're going to work on a
highlight reel and put something together
so you can see what you missed.
Hopefully, we'll be doing it again at some
point in the not-too-distant future.
Market.
I know we didn't get to talk about the
market over the weekend.
Let me just give you
a really, real quick,
my summary and what
I think is going on here.
We did get some follow-through action up
the right side here.
You can see this day, we had a gap at the
end of the week with an increase in volume.
Now, you don't want
to just rush into the
market just because you
get some accumulation.
There's a couple of things we're going to
look for.
One is a lack of distribution.
No immediate distribution
like we got last time
when the market tried
to rally off the lows.
Came right back down, got some
distribution.
That may happen again.
We don't know yet.
We're going to watch.
Stocks, of course, setting up.
Pullback here would be normal.
We ran up a little bit up this right side.
A pullback would be normal.
And if it lacks distribution and we see
stocks setting up, that's the best scenario.
One of the good things is that we had a
massive drop, about a 10-point drop in the
bullish percentage of sentiment,
of bulls, of investors' intelligence.
And that was a great thing to see that
fear come into the market.
And from that point, we rallied,
of course.
I don't think the bulls are going to come
back to where they were.
So I don't think that this is having us,
this sentiment getting backed at levels.
That would be dangerous again.
So again, we just got to watch now for the
individual stocks.
But this is a time now where,
yes, we should be... Holy cow.
We're doing some blowing outside my
window.
It just gave me a heart attack.
I don't know if you heard that or not.
But... No.
No?
Wow.
I don't know how you could not.
Good mic.
So yeah, this is where you want to look
for stocks and start buying a few.
If they're breaking out, we'll highlight
what's setting up here.
And I would take a few positions,
smaller positions.
Now, you may even get the distribution.
Let's say we get distribution.
This market even takes another leg down.
You could take another leg down,
even take out the lows here.
And stocks that broke out might pull back
and not stop you out.
This is really an important thing to
understand around the time when you're
looking to get in the market
from cash or from a correction
or a bear market is that
the leaders tend to lead.
Well, they always lead, but they tend to
lead these lows and sometimes make their
bottoms and break out of their bases still
while the market is finding its low.
So that could happen.
It could happen in a completely opposite
fashion, too.
The market runs up, goes into new highs,
and a lot of stocks run up the right side
and they get extended and they're not
buyable.
And you sort of feel, you know,
you feel like you're missing the party and
you are at that particular
time and you just
have to wait patiently
to get those setups.
So either way, the individual stocks are
going to have the last say.
And that's the way we do it.
And that's the way we've always done it.
And it's always worked over time.
So that would be my recommendation here.
Still short, the SPY.
And as I said, I could care less if this
SPY stops me out at a 1% loss.
If I've got stocks setting up and I can
get long, that would be great.
That's exactly what I would prefer.
The market rolls over here.
You know, again, we got a
couple of shorts on, but it's not
really a profit center for me in
the long-term scheme of things.
I think that's about it.
Let me see.
Anything else?
Nope.
Talked about that.
Yeah, that's it.
And they're great footage.
If you haven't seen
on Twitter, a lot of
people are posting
videos of the birthday bash.
It was just beyond tremendous.
And I just want to thank
all of you that came,
that made it thousands of
people over the weekend.
We had between the gala and the birthday
bash.
I don't know, 1,800 people or so.
It was really something else.
So thank you so much for coming,
those of you who did.
And I appreciate your friendship and
loyalty.
And those of you who didn't, try to get to
the next one because it was awesome.
Let's get started.
Let's take your questions.
All right.
Alex is asking about SFM.
Does the fact that it already came a long
way affect the rating?
Why was that why you didn't buy it today?
Yeah, well, so this hasn't come a long
way.
See, oh, down here,
if you remember, this is
where we were talking
about it originally.
And I felt like this is more
of the, you know, the earlier
stage when the stock turned
into a new stage to uptrend.
So now you've run up quite a bit.
And that doesn't mean it can't go higher.
This acceleration right here is what gets
me a little concerned.
So now you've got a combination of an
accelerated rate of advance at the end.
And I'll just, let's see what that
percentage is.
I'm just curious because I don't think
it's huge.
You have maybe about 30%.
So it's not a huge climactic move,
but it is a little bit climactic.
You got one here.
You accelerated here.
It was a couple of times.
So you're getting where now you've gotten
one here, here, here, here.
You're on like your fourth accelerated
advance after it's made a big move.
And it's a bit V-shaped here.
So with all that taken in consideration, I
would look at this as being maybe tradable.
But it just doesn't have that right side
development.
It's a little late stage.
So it kind of misses the mark for me at
this point.
You know, it's not just, it's just not
making the cut, but it's got to pivot.
It's definitely viable from a trading
standpoint.
David's asking about ATMU.
Missed it last week.
Is that a valid cheat today?
Yeah.
Well, I mean, missing it last week would
really be, you know, bottom fishing.
I mean, and if you're going to bottom
fish, that's the way to do it.
You see stabilized here.
I like the reversals off the low.
You got a number of reversals.
So, yeah, I mean, this would be definitely
a bottom fishing low, a low cheat,
bottom fishing low cheat.
Now it's run up this right side.
And this is not a cheat area.
Absolutely not.
I mean, it's, it's still time compressed.
You would need this right side to build
for me to be involved with it.
I would not be buying up this right side
here.
Okay.
Question from Roberto.
Very grateful and happy to see you.
Also very motivating.
Thank you for everything.
Could you also tell me Mark Ritchie's
average position size in 2024?
Mark.
Oh, yeah.
I'm not sure you know that exactly,
but...
Yeah, I don't, I don't know that I have an
exact either, but yeah, I would guess
somewhere between 10
and 12%, you know, about 10
to 12 and a half percent
would probably be average.
On average, yeah.
So, yeah.
Ravi's asking, what do you think about WWW
as a starter position?
As is this set up a low, and is this set
up a low probability trade?
It's on my, it's on my watch list.
You know, this is, it's pretty strong
here.
It's fairly early.
You see that the new trend turned up,
the stage two up trend.
So it's fairly early.
And I think this was on earnings.
You know, it came down
to, I would rather have not
come and sit on the 50
here, but it didn't tighten up.
You see, it started getting loose here
today.
So I was looking for it to tighten up
right into this supply.
So I think it just needs more work.
And I would look for that work to occur
below this level.
You know, maybe, maybe you just need to
tighten up a bit right here.
And you can, should I give, just give you
a little example.
And I wouldn't mind seeing a little more,
even a little more VCP action in something
like this, where maybe you tighten up and
then you come out.
That would be a little more constructive.
Yeah, he bought it Friday with a pullback
buy using the Thursday low as a stop.
So he got knocked out this morning.
Yeah, so you took a very small loss on it.
And, you know, this is one where, you
know, now you wait for that second try.
But, you know, certainly the volatility is
increasing here.
So that's not where
you want to start getting
aggressive and trying to
revenge trade on this thing.
All right.
You're going to revenge trade.
I'm okay with revenge trading and getting
even by being successful.
But revenge trade from a subsequent setup,
that's even better than before.
The stock should improve.
Whenever you're making second buys,
here's a general rule of thumb.
Your second buy should be from an improved
chart, right?
Usually when we're trying to buy early,
we're buying off the low cheats.
That's where our tactics tend to be more
sloppy or we're buying into supply.
Then later on, as the stock builds out and
it's still in that base and builds that
right side, the chart
should actually be
improving, even though
it's at a higher price.
It will almost always be at a higher price
if it's improving.
But that doesn't mean anything.
We're looking for the right price,
not the lowest price.
And the fact that you already got in at a
lower price, and now it's rebuilding and
it's building that pivot on the right side
at a higher price, that's giving that
confirmation that then you can get more
aggressive.
I thought that was a good line,
Mark.
What did you say?
Revenge trading by trading a better setup?
Yeah, yeah.
That's how you revenge trade.
I revenge trade all the time.
I get even by making
a lot of money from the
damn stock that stopped
me out a few times.
Well, I think it's just a good,
especially if you're new, like to Mark's
mindset, but you'll hear things like,
hey, the best revenge is living well.
That's how you do it in trading,
what Mark just described.
Yeah, trading well.
Best revenge is trading well.
Next question is from Damiano,
and Damiano is a relatively new client
from Italy with the last name of
Minervini.
Damiano, are you...
You're from Bari?
Are you related?
A lot of the Minervinis are from Bari.
That's where my family's from,
from Bari, Italy.
Let me see.
He's saying Molfetta, Molfetta.
Okay.
All right.
Those Minervinis, by the
way, know how to make
great meatballs, I
learned over the weekend.
You learned that, huh?
He's saying Molfetta is close to Bari.
That's what I'm saying.
Yep.
That's the region.
That's the area.
Yeah.
It's, he's saying...
So we have a Minervini signed up as an MPA
member.
We do.
Is that right?
He's only about 15 miles from Bari.
Wow.
That's awesome.
Yeah.
That's a first.
So let's get to his questions.
He's asking, how close do you set your
alert to the buy point?
When are you looking for the
stock to, you know, when do you
want to be notified of a
stock getting close to the pivot?
Yeah.
I mean, that depends.
I mean, if you're like right in front of
the screen and you've got everything,
you know, some stocks, like, I know I want
to own this damn thing and I'm on it and
I've got my buy order
already set up, you know, in
my brokerage firm screen
and it's just ready to go.
It's a matter of, then it's like right
there.
I'll set it right at the price for a penny
or two below.
But if you want to be alerted,
maybe, you know, certainly if you're away
from the screen, if you're using some type
of alert that would go on your phone or
something, then you might want to set it,
you know, 20 cents or 50 cents below.
Sometimes I set alerts, you know,
when they're coming up, maybe,
you know, the previous days, a couple of
days ago, high was the pivot and something
like this, maybe this high over here is
the pivot, but I'll set it at this high.
So when it gets to that first high,
it lets me know.
But it's kind of personal.
I mean, on how much headroom you want or
how much lead time you want on it.
So I'm watching the stocks.
Generally, when I'm ready to trade
something, I'm watching the screen carefully.
So I'm usually watching it in real time.
Although I do put alerts all day long.
I'm constantly setting alerts.
And his other question on PEGA?
Yeah, Peg, yep.
He's asking if it was buyable on January
15th.
After the shakeout, how do you manage
conditions like this one?
Well, you know, again, this is somewhat of
a hardaway crossover, you know,
where it tries to tighten up or either it
breaks out and then shakes you out or
doesn't break out and undercuts the low
and then rips back.
The only way I would
look at this as buyable
is trading what we call
near the danger point.
That's the shakeout day and trading on
this pullback buy.
So you would trade it as it moved above
the high of the 13th.
And it's actually,
you know, that's not a
very risky trade because
it shook out the low.
And now you would have been about maybe,
what is it, about 3% or so?
Yeah, you're about 3%, 4% from the low.
So that's a fairly low risk trade.
And his last question, Siena, C-I-E-N.
Yep.
Named for the last from the past.
Was that viable today using the low of
the...
First off, he's asking if
it's a cheat and looking
at using the low of the
last three days pivot.
Yeah, I was, you know, was a little
reluctant even putting this on.
It does have an accelerated rate of advance
here, but it's just starting to turn.
So that improves the probability,
but it's a small base.
So, I mean, I wouldn't be surprised if
this is one that still needs time.
It's buyable, but it's not one that I'm
buying.
So what was the other part of the
question?
If it was a cheat and using the low of the
cheat, the pivot as his top 3.5.
Yeah, absolutely.
I mean, it's definitely a cheat.
And I would, you know, once this breaks
out here, I would definitely use,
especially today, the low, I would use
this day's low 83.95 as the stop,
because you don't want it to now have an
engulfing day.
If it engulfs, then, yeah, then it would
take out this low.
The volatility would have widened.
And then I would want to see it retighten
and maybe go inside or even shake out,
maybe it shakes out the lows a bit and
then start retightening.
And then, you know, you start looking for
another entry point, which would be great.
See, this would be a perfect example of
the chart improving.
If I got that, well, now I went to another
iteration and I set up even a little
higher and tightened up again and the base
built out longer.
That's an improved chart.
I'm more interested in this chart up here
than I am down here.
Only a thousand more points.
I'll get back to its 2000 high.
Haha, there you go.
How do you know there was a good
probability that the SPY would undercut
the previous January 2nd low and that was
a good spot to add?
That it was a good spot to add on to your
short.
How'd you know?
Over here?
January 2nd low.
You added to it when, you know,
right there.
Uh, the 2nd.
The 2nd or 7th.
Yeah, the 2nd.
That's what he wrote.
Yeah.
2nd's right here.
Oh, just got to go back and look at the
posts.
No, I guess he was saying, he was
thinking, you must have made a comment,
Mark, that you thought we
were going to undercut that spot,
that low, which we did, you
know, five days later or so.
I don't remember.
I mean, just a feel of, you know,
watching markets for 42 years,
but I wouldn't, you know, I wouldn't,
that's not what I would try to emulate.
That, you know, that's not something that I
think you should be worried about too much.
I mean, you know, again, just get off
these indexes for as your major,
you know, main
indicator or indication of
market health and for
what you're focusing on.
Focus on the individual stocks.
I mean, that's what's really important.
That's where you're going to make your
money.
And that's where you have the
opportunities.
Jerry's asking on BE, what would you need
to see for this to become viable?
Yeah, I mean, it's on my watch list.
You know, it's right here on my watch
list.
Tightening, once again, tightening.
You know, we just want to see.
Again, this is one that, you know, you made
that big move, a couple hundred percent.
If you look at the correction,
you'll see it's come off about 25%.
That's the problem.
And then it's also come back to the
50-day.
The strongest ones usually don't come back
to the 50-day and they don't correct 25%.
So this is definitely a weaker,
you know, a weaker choice in that terms.
Yes, let me just get rid of that.
But tightening, you know, I want to see it
just like always.
I want to see this tighten up.
This could tighten up for a few days.
You know, maybe, you know, maybe we could
start a position on it.
Greg is asking about Rocket Lab RKLB.
Yeah, well, that's, that's, that's
rocketing.
He bought it on Friday at the low of the
day because Vine was drying up.
He de-risked this morning.
He's up 20% on the remaining, probably
more now.
Average return is about 4%.
Should I sell the rest?
Sell the rest, I'm assuming?
Not save.
Sell the rest.
What are your thoughts?
I don't understand.
Average return.
What does that mean, average return?
I think that is his, his average return of
his trades overall is 4%.
So he's got a huge winner here.
I mean, you know, it's, I
don't even, I don't know what
the news is here right now,
but I see it's breaking out.
It was on my watch list and you could have
had the nice little, you know,
cheat area there if another day of
tightening, but you got to pull back by
coming off of, you know, sort of low risk
entry.
So, you know, I don't think I would have
bought it like you bought it.
Um, but, um, you know,
it was viable this morning
too, as it, but I guess
it moved very quick.
Yeah.
There was, there was a story that,
uh, president Trump pledged to send
astronauts to Mars during his term and
rocket labs at direct play all that.
Yeah.
So, I mean, I, I personally, you know,
going up on news, I, I would, you know,
I would definitely de-risk it,
but again, being up, and this is something
we have in the new platform where it'll,
it'll show you how much you have to sell
to de-risk, fully de-risk
your position, being up this
much, you only have to
sell a very small portion of it.
And I think you just said you did that.
So that's the way to play it.
And then, then it's up to you.
I mean, I can't, I can't tell you,
I don't have a crystal ball.
I don't know if this is going to go up or
down, but you know, we do know you made a,
you know, you're up way above your average
game.
Uh, real quick, Mark, not that I think it
matters, but just so you know,
it is showing you as Bob Weissman still,
not Mark.
Yeah.
I didn't change the name.
We'll know who you are, uh, Patrick is
asking, Patrick is asking about hubs,
H-U-B-S, four minute sheet entry at seven
2460.
What score do you give this to the setup?
Um, yeah, I don't know it really,
really well.
So I'm just going to look at it
technically here.
I mean, and again, somebody look at this
as a big VCP, but yeah.
And while it is, you know, this correction
here is 72%.
Um, so I, uh, that's not, doesn't really
mean anything to me, but what,
what is meaningful is that it's,
you know, turning into a stage to uptrend,
but it's early.
See it, it's an early turn.
So, um, let me see.
So how much is it going up?
Up these lows.
Yeah.
So it's not powerful enough to be a power
play.
It's early turn.
So I'd still be, I still would be careful
with it, you know, but it's, it's,
you know, it's fine if it stays tight
here, if it starts turning up here as a
pullback buyer, maybe above this pivot,
uh, you could start a position.
This, uh, 70, uh, 7, 24, 60, they provide
cloud-based customer relationship
management software, a hubspot,
a question on S R R K.
S R R K.
Thoughts of this being, uh, focus list
additional.
Yeah.
I, to be honest with you, I didn't see
this one for whatever reason.
Um, it's very tight.
I, I, I like it.
I mean, it looks pretty good.
Um, very tight, but I have to look at it
more closely.
Um, but it looks, it looks pretty
interesting here.
They had a good, good phase drug result
back there in October.
And then in November, it looks
like they had a competing firm
have a negative drug result
on their drugs helping S R R K.
November.
Okay.
That's good news.
That's two back to back really,
you know, good news events.
Um, so the fact that
it's staying tight, you
know, that's, that's,
uh, definitely positive.
I'll, I'll take a look at it.
If it's, uh, something
that, uh, I like, I mean, no
one else, maybe this is
one that we, we put a buy on.
Yep.
Um, Lou is a, uh, a lot of SFMs today,
actually a lot of SFMs.
Um, Anders is asking to evaluate his RBRK
trade.
Um, that was on focus list last week.
Um, he bought it on the 15th at 6620,
putting a stop at the low of the 13th,
five and a half percent.
Um, I mean, I was looking forward to just
tighten up a little bit more.
I would have liked to seen it tighten up a
little bit more.
It might've been one that
I went in if it, if it did that,
but you know, you're in good
position now you're up on it.
So that's good.
His main question was asking if,
if you felt his stop was too tight at five
and a half percent using the low of the
13th.
Low of the 13th.
Let's see.
So that's over here probably.
Oh no.
13th.
Um, I'm not sure why that low is
significant.
Maybe it's just from a percentage
standpoint.
Um, I don't think it's too tight.
Is the question, is it too tight?
Yeah.
That's, he was asking if, if, uh,
do you think my son was too tight?
Oh yeah.
So he's still in it.
Cause, uh, he followed his plan and exited
the trade on the 16th.
The next day, he said the
low of the 10th would have
been about a 9% stop,
which was too high for him.
Yeah.
I see that.
No, I mean, I don't, I don't think so.
I mean, that's, you know, obviously you
got shaken out, I guess here, right.
You're shaking out on the 16th.
Probably took up.
Yeah.
You just kind of, you know, fell victim to
a shakeout.
So, um, I, again, looking back,
it was too tight.
You can look at it in hindsight and say,
well, I got stopped out.
It was too tight.
What, what, what the
real answer is, is what
your plan was and how
much you wanted to risk.
So you're right.
You're right.
You answered your own question.
That other low that's 9% away is too big.
So you had to come up with a,
you know, come up with a percentage
stop and that's what you came
up with and you got unlucky.
So next hand, uh, our pre is asking about
SMTC.
Yeah.
SMTC is again, is on my breakout list.
You know, stocks that have recently broken
out.
So what's the question?
Um, he, please look into SMTC and thank
you.
Uh, he also was thank us for the gala.
I think he actually was asking more about
BKV.
If this is set up BKV.
Yeah.
I mean, it's wedging up a little bit here.
Um, but, um, this is on the watch list
this morning.
We just, just didn't put it on.
Yep.
Uh, okay.
Now there are a lot of thank yous for
people coming to the gala here.
So kind of getting through a lot of
comments here.
Sorry.
Costas is asking about W-A-Y.
He bought it today.
Your thoughts on the setup?
Yeah.
Let's see.
Um, again, this is one that,
you know, it doesn't have,
let me just, let me just
measure it back a little bit.
Yeah.
It doesn't have enough gain to be a power
play.
So you're buying it from
a little low base, but, uh,
you know, and a little pullback
bias, maybe a small gap.
I mean, you know, it's not one that I
would be that excited about.
It doesn't have the power.
Um, but I don't think the buy is that bad.
You're buying it coming from a pivot,
uh, you know, fairly tight pullback buy,
I guess you use today.
Um, you know, I would just, uh, today
I wouldn't want it to take out Friday.
Friday's low.
Um, and certainly, let me just see what
percentage that is even.
Yeah.
A couple of percent all the way down here
is 6%.
So you could give this some room.
I mean, you could give it a little bit of
room and, and, uh, maybe even,
uh, you know, allow it some fluctuation in
here.
Or if you took a bigger position,
maybe just trim it as if it, if it takes
up, you know, this low and this low,
you just start scaling out of it.
If it, if it goes lower, so maybe use a
staggered stop and that could give you
more room to let it volatile, to let it
move, um, in a volatile fashion,
um, and still not take as much risk.
Okay.
Uh, um, Solomon is asking if you can rate
his GEV purchase on January 2nd,
still sold some today, holding the rest
into earnings.
Yeah.
I mean, it's great.
It's, it's a real, real tight there.
Um, you know, this is one that I was
watching very carefully and.
Looking at that overhead to the left and
it, it got right, it got through it,
ripped through it on a gap, pulled back.
I think we put this on our focus list a
couple of times, if my memory serves.
So it looks fine.
It pulled back a very, uh, successful pull
back.
You can see each time it pulled back,
look at the, look at the closes.
Look at how those three closes are tight
right across the top.
As a matter of fact, it's tight to the
fourth close.
That's very constructive.
When you pull back to the breakout and
then you get that nice close and then you
get all these closes tight, that's very
constructive.
So it's not, it's no surprise to me that
this then gap to move higher.
So, so far, you know, everything's going
great.
Now you got to think about where you're
going to take a profit.
Um, one is asking, how do you deal with
and balance the potential paradox of a
champion mindset and trying to be humble
in stock trading?
Or should we be all out champion mindset?
A champion mindset is being humble.
So I'm not sure why you would,
why you would think they're differently.
Matter of fact, I, the real champions like
Michael Jordan's, um, you know,
Kobe Bryant, something
we can use basketball, we
can use, you know, what
baseball, whatever you want.
I mean, yes, there's a couple a-holes
every now and then, but I, I found all the
greatest people I've, and I just spent the
whole weekend with some really,
really great people.
They're spectacular people, talented
people, people worth, some of my friends
came in on private,
they're private jets and,
um, you know, very,
very successful people.
And, um, they're the most, some of the
most humble people I've ever known.
So I don't, I don't, I think, you know,
being a champion is being humble.
Look, confidence is one thing.
I don't, I don't think you should not be
confident.
And, and certainly if you've got the
success, you know, you want to flaunt it.
That's fine.
That's not, that's not being
unhumble, you know, being,
if you want to get humble
as a Trader, just trade.
Trust me, it'll humble you.
And that's all you got to do.
All right.
George mentioned he
bought a 10% position today
in APP as it broke out
over yesterday's high.
Got stopped out in short order with a very
small loss.
I know the technical
setup wasn't ideal, but
the fundamentals are
strong and the RS is 99.
So I gave it a shot.
Can you advise if I stretched the rules
too much?
I mean, I don't think it's a huge stretch.
It's certainly a, you know, powerful
leader, you know, and you're right.
It's got, you know, some really great
things going for it.
So that's where if you're
going to give the benefit of the
doubt, give it in the stocks
to, you know, showing all that.
And on top of it, what was the buy was
today?
Yeah.
And then you stopped
out like so quickly that
of course you could
try that a bunch of times.
So yeah, I mean, you're doing it the way
you should do it.
It's not the setup that I would trade
from.
I just don't, I just don't make that,
that leap.
Like when I make leaps, they're not like,
well, it's got great fundamentals,
great management, this,
that, and other thing with the
technical setup isn't, you
know, precisely what I want.
I really want to get the technicals right.
So if it doesn't make my cut, there's,
I'm not going to rationalize myself into
it, but if you're going
to, you know, I think
everything you just
did was the way to do it.
Okay.
Michael's asking if you can explain the
AORT buy today.
To me, it looked like it was watching.
The AORT buy today?
Yeah.
We bought AORT today?
No.
Okay.
That's the news to me.
I guess you mean it's up for Friday.
You mean explain it today, maybe?
I don't know, but... Yeah.
Um, yeah.
Uh, so one, one, six, two, one 16.
Um, and again, I think I...
Yeah, I think I read it wrong, Mike.
Mark, you're right.
So he's just asking to explain it.
AORT purchase.
Yeah.
Well, again, I think I pointed this out,
um, last week.
This was, it was, was, uh, Mark,
uh, Mark and Brandon.
I don't know, Mark, you are Brandon.
If you may collectively made this
decision, this was a buy they put on it.
It, it moved very quickly and I was like,
oh, wow, that was a, you know,
that was a good, what, what'd you see
there that I didn't see?
Um, so it moved very quickly in,
in, in the direction of the trade,
obviously, and got out of profit.
Um, so Mark, I mean, you know,
you can explain it.
I mean, it's a, it's, you
know, certainly had a nice
little pullback by there
a couple of days earlier.
I don't know if, um...
Yeah, I would have preferred it if it had
tightened up again, but even measuring,
you know, if you just measure to that low,
is it, is it acceptable?
Yeah, is it perfect?
No.
Um, stock held up really well though.
And, you know, good, good earnings and
fundamentals on the table.
I think it's a decent
spot if you're, you know,
going to try some exposure
to, to, to take a line.
Yeah.
And I'll give, I'm going to give you what
Mark's saying here too.
It's like, so for instance, you know,
buying this coming out, you know,
or buying it coming
out of this, uh, obviously,
uh, uh, uh, coming
through these highs here.
If you measure this down from there,
so I don't know, where's our purchase?
Um, it's, so 3102, right?
Yeah, it was, it was moving quickly.
Yeah.
So we, I mean, the, the, the pivot was
here.
I mean, maybe we got
a, might've got a little bit
of a bad fill, but let's
just put it at the pivot.
Cause that's where we're
measuring from when we're
deciding whether we're
going to take a purchase.
You take that and come all the way down
here.
I mean, you're like 5%.
You come all the way down, maybe not down
to here, about 8%.
So, I mean, you got quite a bit of room to
let it fluctuate and, and maybe not stop
you out, especially if you use a staggered
stop.
Um, so again, it, the lack of the
volatility is sometimes we're weighing
the, um, you know, how powerful the chart
is.
And if it's really powerful and maybe it
doesn't have that perfect pivot,
well, okay, well, how much volatility I
get this was, let's just say that this
move from, from this high down to here was
15%, then it might be a different decision
because now, you know, that thing could
maybe, it can move easily 5, 6,
7% and it will barely budge the chart.
Um, and we get stopped out and it didn't
really do anything wrong, but you could
let this come all the way down and take
out this low, uh, and even lower,
and you're still in the 5, 6% range or
well within it.
So sometimes it's just a decision of risk,
you know, versus a stock that,
uh, you know, you want to own,
but I, I, but I think, you know,
we have, you have to say, I think,
you know, that this was definitely,
you know, chasing a little bit up that
right side.
Uh, question from Devin is asking if
NVIDIA is setting up again.
Well, I know, you know, I know NVIDIA is,
you know, uh, is basing, um, setting up.
I wouldn't call this setting up.
I mean, we're going into a real hard
reversal here.
Obviously it reversed up this high.
So there's definitely some selling happened
around that 152s change level, 153.
You're, you're, you
know, you don't have really
any right side built
here with any pivot.
So I would say, no, not yet.
It's basing.
And it's, you know, if you were saying,
if it was, uh, you know, three or four
stages of, you know, going from no basing
to basing, to setting up a right side and
having a pivot, you'd probably just be in
the stage one of just a basing.
A question from Tamlin,
more towards Mark Ritchie,
making a comment last week
that the list is working well.
He's wanting to know, are you basing that
on just the stock being up from,
you know, a setup because he's commenting
that there were a lot of gap ups,
or would you say a list is
working well if it provided you
the opportunity to get in
with a low risk, uh, entry point?
Well, I would prefer the
low risk entry points and of
course, names holding on
balance and following through.
Yeah.
I was simply saying that
at least those names were
participating as the market
was coming off the lows.
Look, if you were aggressive, you could
have gotten on, you know, maybe one or two
or a few, uh, but you know, look right
now, what Mark said to start the video,
we've got this markets running off the
lows.
If we can avoid distribution, here's where
even names, maybe that gapped,
can we get a pullback by, do we get higher
handles or some form of cheats?
This is where you just start looking for
those pivots, even in names that have
already maybe broken out, looking for
another spot to get on board.
Ritesh, Mark, a relatively new trader,
uh, what should be visualization routine
one should follow guidelines and or
techniques will be very helpful.
Um, I mean, there's, there's so many
things that you can do with visualization,
obviously, and I got to work on things
that you want to work on.
I like to in the morning and I do this
just automatically when I wake up in the
morning, I don't just jump
out of bed and run to work
or go run to the kitchen
and get a cup of coffee.
Or usually I go to the bathroom first.
That's that.
And then I come back and I lay down and I,
and I'll take five or 10 minutes and I
just lay there and I just think about the
day.
I do turn on the TV and just check what
the market, if it's going to be up big or
down big, because if it's going to be down
huge, I know I'm going to be dealing maybe
with some gaps and maybe some,
especially if I'm, you know, invested,
if I have some big
positions and same thing with
up, I know I'm going to
be dealing with some gaps.
So I kind of get the idea of what I'm
going to be faced with.
If it's a flat open, then, you
know, probably, you know,
you're not going to have the
market pressure in many stocks.
And then I sort of visualize, you know,
what I'm, what I'm going to face,
you know, and what's in my portfolio.
You know, I know before I go to bed, I
take a look at what I have in my portfolio.
I do a reconciliation of everything and
just, and even if I have like meetings
that day or I try to get
things in order, you know,
in chronological order
and say, okay, I got it.
This is what I got to do.
This is what I'm going to face at this
time and just, and get that, that plan.
Because the thing is, is that you have so
much tugging on you, you know, all day.
There's so many things, especially if you
kind of phone and you've got TikTok and
all that other crap on it, because you're
just getting fed all these videos and
people, and maybe you have kids and your
wife and, you know, a job and,
you know, all these things tugging on you
and you've got to prioritize.
You've got to get things in order and put
those things that are most important and
the trades and, and, and the stuff that
you need to focus on.
You got to put that in your mind's eye and
get your intention focused.
So I just, I just try to focus my
intention.
And, and, and then I, I just, I think in
my mind, you know, priorities and I try to
get what's my number
one, two, three things
and everything else
kind of falls under that.
So I get up and I get to work and now I've
got that sort of mental image and plan.
And that just sets me in motion.
And everything else after that seems to
fall in place better.
And then at night, I do it again.
Just before I go to bed,
I do five minutes of box
breathing and I do like
a kind of a meditation.
And I meditate on what happened during the
day.
Then I follow my plan, you know, and
just sort of a reconciliation of the day.
And sometimes you do that reconciliation
and you're like, holy cow.
You know, I mean, I just... I got nothing
done today.
I let people just pull me all over the
place.
And I'll give you a perfect
example of what I was just
talking about with somebody
and my wife this morning.
I, you know, I underestimated or I was a
little bit delusional that I thought that
I had at the birthday party, we had about
a thousand people.
We were supposed to have almost 1,200 and
ended up some of the fire in California.
We had some people cancel.
But we had almost about
a thousand people, just
under a thousand people
at the birthday party.
And 300 of them, 350 of them were
literally family and close friends.
Even more than that, probably.
But 300 that were in my app were a really
close list.
I thought I could manage that.
Like, I thought I was going
to go in the crowd and like be
able to go and see everybody
and shake their hand and hug.
And I actually did hug and shake
everyone's hand, but it was like for one
second each, I underestimated getting to
each of those people.
I was going to have to plow through
another like, you know, 700 people and
shake their hand to take pictures with
everybody.
So, you know, it's just like what I,
you know, the plan, you know, again,
and I go back and I look at it and I go,
whoa, that, you know, that wasn't right.
I'm going to reformulate that,
you know, same thing with trading,
you know, visualize all that stuff,
go get in there and, and, and,
and get in the game and then come back
out.
And at night, go over what happened,
you know, what's the gap between where
you, what you visualized
in the morning and
what you thought would
happen and what happened.
And that's, and then close that gap.
That's the key is
constantly closing that gap
between where you want
to be and where you are.
Juan is asking, regarding the 50- and
200-day moving average, how do you get a
feel for the health of the market regarding
stocks above their 50- and 200-day?
You know how you show that often.
I'm talking about those charts of the
percentage of them.
Yeah, I mean, look, those are news more,
not just on an everyday basis.
If the market is well above its 200-day
moving average and in an uptrend,
and you look and you see that there's 35%
of stocks above their 200-day moving
average, well, that
tells you that most of the
market is already corrected
and is below the 200.
Usually, that will pull... there's just a
matter of time, and you're getting close
to a correction in the indexes that are
going to come and come down to the stocks.
So, they're just looking for that differential
to see if there's a major disparity.
But it's not something you should be
looking at every day that, in minor
movements, you're going to get... you're
going to glean anything from that.
A question about SOC being ready for focus
list.
I don't think it's ready just yet,
no.
I would like to see it tighten up.
So, for me, no.
Yuling, Frank bought a quarter position in
Skyworks, S-K-Y-W.
Yep.
At 113.
Is that a good buy?
Well, so I was going to buy it this
morning.
I was going to put it on the platform.
It was spready.
So, it wasn't real spready, but it was a
little bit spready.
I think it was 111.70 or something by
110.30.
It was a bit spready for me.
And I decided I didn't want to be at that
loss right away either.
So, I don't like to take really small
positions.
I like to take... even when I'm taking
starter positions, you know, relatively
speaking, dollar-wise for me, you know,
it's a lot of money.
And so, I don't want to
sit there and be at a 5 or
10 or sometimes 20 or
$50,000 loss right off the hop.
And I haven't seen a lot of traction yet
and breakouts working.
When I start seeing stocks breaking out
and really popping and working,
I'm willing to go in
there because it's much
more likely that I'll be
at a profit right away.
And maybe, you know, that stock will take
off and be up.
Like one of these, you know, CMRX is up
10%, today 11%, CLPT.
CLPT is what I wanted to buy this morning,
but it gapped.
It's up 23% now.
You know, I was hoping that this stayed
tight.
So, yeah, you know, I'll, you know,
I'll, I'll shy away from them sometime if
they've got, if they're too spreading, if
I haven't seen that type of traction yet.
So, but I think it's fine.
It's a, you know, it's breaking out of a
very nice tight.
I love this shakeout right here.
And then it tightens up.
I love that last iteration.
That said, I wouldn't be surprised if this
spends a little more time.
It's coming right into this supply right
here.
Again, let me just give you, again,
we're going to go through the pivot,
go to the left, always,
always throw the line to
the left, and you're
going right into this supply.
So, for this to, you know, even come in
and maybe even got a little violent there
and to tighten up more,
that would be completely
normal, but that would
totally improve the stock.
Now, let's just say, you know,
you went to another iteration of
tightening and it looks something like
this.
Oh, yeah.
Then I'm... Now I'm
going to go all over it.
Okay.
There are a lot of comments, Mark,
that will...
I don't have time to
acknowledge everybody
wishing you happy
birthday and love the gala.
So, just so you know, guys, we'll get the
messages over to Mark.
Well, I'm not going to read them out loud
here right now.
And then I just, again, I want to say,
you know, the love and friendship that was
poured out to me was just beyond,
totally emotionally overwhelming.
I just want to let you know.
Joseph's mentioning he has an
average gain of 8%, average loss
of 3.6 with a 41% win ratio of
being, win-loss ratio being 1.61.
He's asking how to improve.
Well, you know, market conditions,
you know, you have to look back and see
if, you know, your market conditions
affected, maybe you're making good plays,
but the market just was crappy at the
time, and that might improve the batting
average, and that would improve your
adjusted win-loss ratio.
Or, obviously, you got to get a little
more gain.
8% is a pretty good gain, you know,
for a swing trader.
You know, 10 or 12 would be really good.
15 would be spectacular.
You know, I would say that for a swing
trader, that's sort of the range.
8 to 12 to as high as 15, that's sort of
the range that I've seen, you know,
the better traders, so you want to
optimize that, I would say, to try to get
at maybe 10, 12%, and again, the smaller
you can get that risk, the better.
The tighter you can get that risk without
choking off the trades, you can get that
number to go from 3 or 4% to 2 or 3%,
great.
You know, that's, my first
focus is always on the risk,
because that's the thing
that I have direct control over.
The batting average, I don't have any
control over.
The average gain, I have some control
where I sell, but even that, it's,
you know, it's a little less direct
control.
The loss side, I can
absolutely direct, I
can control that even
before I buy the stock.
I can make that decision before I even
enter the stock.
So that's the one you have the most
control of.
So I put it in order of what
I have the most control,
that's where I put my focus
to make my adjustments.
Okay.
Joey's asking or commenting you made
previously, you mentioned the importance
of an inside day, and she's
citing GEV on December
31st, shortly before a
stock can be bought.
Can you discuss the importance and the
reason behind an inside day?
Well, just another form of volatility
contraction.
You know, for instance, right here, from
here to here, we've got that inside day.
Just another form of, we want volatility
contraction as much as possible,
all the way to where we're going through
the iterations, through the pattern,
to where they're getting smaller and
smaller.
And then you've got patterns within
patterns, we call them fractals.
And then from there, now we're going down
right to the buy day.
Well, we want, we still want that,
that contraction of volatility.
And that's going to show up as an inside
day.
Yeah.
Also, the fact on this GEV, she mentions
the stock continues to go up, but on
lighter volume, should this light volume
be a concern?
No, I wouldn't get too concerned with
that.
You know, as long as, the volume that you
really want to see is on the breakout,
and you want to see the contrast between
the pullbacks and the rallies.
And I'll tell you right now, you
can see, like, you might say,
well, there's some red volume
here, but look at these closes.
These closes are all at the, almost right
at the high.
So that's actually accumulation right
there.
I would look at that as accumulation.
I would not look at that as selling days.
That's why you always have to look at
price and volume together.
Paul bought GTLS the
January 14th at 2.06 with
a staggered stop of
just under 200 and 191.
Also, would you please comment on these
purchases?
Yeah.
I mean, I think, you know, I see what
you're doing.
I mean, it's a little, you
know, I should say, you
know, a little bit loose
for me, but stops are tight.
You know, you're buying it on the way up.
It's fine.
And also Reddit RDDT purchased on the 15th
with about a three or 4% stop.
Would you please comment?
Yeah.
I mean, just coming
right up the right side
like this without a
pivot, I don't normally do.
I could see buying it on the
pullback buy right here on the
14th and maybe then adding
to it here as it follows through.
I'm actually more inclined to buy it today
or actually Friday than probably I would
be on the day you bought it or inclined to
buy it on the 14th.
Kelly is mentioning you suggested or
commented that you would be good to take
25% to 50% off the
long-term SPY investment, even
though the buy models
are still showing 100%.
Are there any suggestions?
Well, I said that a while ago.
I mean, yes, that was said.
Last few weeks.
Yeah.
Any suggestions of when to be adding that
back?
Yeah.
I mean, you know, that's
a great question because
that is the problem that
you back yourself into.
And that's why I said, if you're going to,
you have this longer term money,
just don't get too cute, you know,
but you've got to make a decision.
Look, am I going to trade or am I going to
have this long-term money?
And I go with this long-term model.
And that means that there's a price to
pay, that in order to stay in and go
through that volatility and get to that
bigger return, you have to go through the
pullbacks and know that in order to get a
sell signal, you're going to give back
some and the buy signal, you're going to
have to go up.
So you give up that short term for the
longer term and the lesser trades,
you know, the lesser So, but to answer
your question specifically, I mean,
a new high in the SPY, you know,
you definitely got to throw in the towel
if you're going back in line with the
model.
And I think also at this point,
this is a little more sophisticated,
but I think it's easy enough for you to
understand.
We got some follow through.
If you got pullback here, let's just say
the market pulls back, you know,
I don't know, a couple
percent, you know,
maybe get a couple
of days like this, right?
And that's that right side.
It should build right there.
And this is on light volume.
There's no distribution.
I'd add it back right there.
I'd add right back on that pullback
because now it's constructive.
You know, I mean, we tried it,
you know, and, you know, you got out,
it didn't roll over.
So you protected yourself.
It's gotten more constructive.
And to be honest with you, again,
I'm going to go right back to,
you know, I would be more inclined to give
you the advice.
Or if you were, you know,
using this for your 401k money
and they're longer term
SPY to just go with the model.
Just go with the model.
I'm going to give you my color.
I'm going to give you what I think in my
gut.
But it's going to be hard to emulate.
It's going to be hard to emulate because
it's not systematic.
All right.
Kavitha, thank you for the event.
Thank you so much.
I drew some lines on Costco at 945.
Before a breakout above
January 17th, I wanted... Costco?
Yep.
C-O-S-T.
Wanted to buy, but still thought of taking
a confirmation from our experts.
Is Costco buyable at 951?
951.
It's not meeting my criteria.
You know, so I see maybe... Is
this considered a load sheet also?
951.
A load sheet?
No, not really.
You just don't have to pivot.
It's a pullback.
It's just bottom fishing.
You know, it's stabilized a little bit,
but it hasn't really formed that pivot yet.
So, I mean, Costco is a super quality
company.
If the S&P goes higher, it's probably
going to go higher because it's part of it.
And it's a market-type
stock, but not one that
I'm interested in at
this particular point.
Okay.
I also want to say thank you to everyone.
I know I have a ton of gifts.
I tried to put it out there not to bring
gifts, but it wasn't necessary.
Your attendance was more than enough,
but I got a lot of gifts.
I don't know, 100 and something gifts at
least, maybe even more.
So, it's been a whirlwind.
Some of them, I don't know if I lost the
cards or I didn't have a card.
Some of them, I'm not sure where they're
from, but I want to say thank you.
Some of them, I know exactly who they're
from.
They made it very obvious, but if you want
to make sure that I know where the gift
came from, you certainly can drop us a
line and say, hey, I sent this gift.
That's fine, but I had
some really nice, thoughtful
gifts, some very unique
gifts that were pretty neat.
I got a Wall Street Journal, an original
Wall Street Journal from January 22, 1965.
So, I'm able to read the Wall
Street Journal of what was
going on in the Wall Street
Journal on the day I was born.
I thought that was pretty neat.
Yeah.
GEO.
Stock was bought at 29.75 on January 8th.
Sold half of it up 10%, holding
the balance to see if Tens
Ball or Egg here and looking
for an additional re-entry.
Any feedback?
Well, your feedback is, I'm kind of pissed
off that I don't own it when you own it.
So, it's, this is the one that I was
watching for a while and really liked.
And again, you see how this one didn't
come all the way back to the 50.
You know, I don't like
them, like I said, to come
back to the 50 when you
get these powerful stocks.
You can measure it from, you know,
back here, up here.
You got the power play.
It tightens up.
Volume gets really, really light here.
You break out.
Pullback is successful.
You know, so far, it's doing everything
right.
If you put this in, you know, in charting,
in our charting, and you overlay monolert,
throw up the no-nos after you buy,
you're going to see there's probably none.
I don't see, I see a
good close, good close,
good close, good close.
You know, probably, I don't know, five
out of eight, maybe something like that.
Good close versus bad close is more up
days than down days.
You know, it's above all the moving
averages.
There's no real violations here to speak
of.
So now you're right.
Now you got to, you're going to have to
either sell in the strength or,
you know, it's going to pull back at some
point.
You got to go through that pullback.
And then you're taking that, you know,
you're taking that risk for a bigger move.
And then you'll get that answer,
whether you start getting...
And there's another form of recipe, too, in
the modeler, which is tennis ball or egg.
And you could, you could throw that up,
too, to get, to get a look at it.
Glenn is, after many
thanks, Glenn's asking,
can we entertain stocks
in a declining market?
Since you mentioned, don't look at the
markets, especially if small caps are
setting up while the larger caps are,
are taking, you know, a rotation.
Again, I don't know, what's a declining
market?
I mean, you're not, you're not giving me a
definition of a declining market.
If there's a bunch of, if
there's stocks setting up, I
mean, how much of a, of a
declining market could you have?
I don't know any, you
know, what I would call
a declining market,
like in a bear market.
I haven't seen any
bear markets where I've
got a bunch of stocks
setting up working out.
So I don't know the definition of what a
declining market is.
But if you're saying maybe the indexes are
going down a certain percentage or
something, and you have stocks setting up,
I would go with the stocks.
If you have stocks setting up,
and you're buying them, and they're
working, and then there's more setups,
I don't think you're in a declining
market, and you can buy more, yes, in a
declining market, if you have that scenario.
Craig is asking if you would call the SPY
a double bottom.
I don't know.
A double bottom?
No, I wouldn't call it that.
I'm sure some people would call this a
little double bottom.
You can call it that.
I mean, if you test it down, it could be a
triple bottom.
It came down three times.
I mean, what does it matter what it's
called?
Let's see.
Ethan is mentioning or asking,
do you include the whole day movement of
the stock or just the open
and the close of the stock in
determining your stock being
the tightness of the stock?
Are you including the whole range of the
day or just from the open or the close?
The whole range of the day.
Okay.
And he's asking, what does
it mean if a stock to have
symmetry, which I thought
we have a tutorial, but... Yeah.
I think we have a tutorial.
And also, I explain that in my books.
You need to read my books more to get a
good explanation of that.
But, you know, certainly, you know,
having that right side development where,
where, you know, if you
look at a, at a cup, you
know, that's why O'Neill
calls it a cup with handle.
You'd see where it's equally on the left
side and the right side.
You have some symmetry to
that and not being lopsided,
you know, where I'll
give you a quick example.
I think GEO, Mark, is an
example of just a name
with decent symmetry
that you just highlighted.
Yeah, I'd rather do something that's a
little more like a cup with handle,
though, that's a little deeper,
but yeah.
Yeah, it's kind of hard to notice without
being something a little bigger.
Let me see if there's...
I just want to see if I can find
something.
Yeah, so, I mean, over
here, you know, if you're right
here, this, this, this doesn't
have any right side built.
So, this is just running up the right
side.
The symmetry starts building when we start
getting this nice, like, right over here.
See, now we've got that whole VCP action,
and this right side is built out.
So, you've got this right side building
out, you know, the left side.
You've got this whole nice picture of this
cup with handle, as William O'Neill would
call it, and you've got this tightening on
the right side.
That has more symmetry.
But again, I would, I'd go back to the
books and restudy.
This is a very, you know, basic remedial
terminology.
All right.
I do have a hard stop at 1230,
so we have to go one more question.
Why don't, Mark, why aren't you,
you didn't answer hardly any questions.
Why don't you stay
in here for another 15
minutes, maybe a half
hour, at least 15 minutes.
Do 15 minutes and take questions.
All right.
I got to get, I got to get, and it's for
your benefit.
I'm getting with the coders, and we're,
we're, we're immediately getting on doing
what we have to do to get this new
platform in your hands.
Yeah, actually, the last question I was
going to ask, Mark, was several people
asking when, when do you anticipate the
release of the new software that we used?
I don't want to promise a date, because
then, then I'm going to disappoint you.
But we're shooting for, I mean,
I'm shooting for tomorrow.
That's not going to happen, of course.
I'm going to tell you right now.
So I'd like it to happen tomorrow.
So I'm, I'm telling everybody to go as
fast as they humanly possibly can.
You know, it's probably going to be 30
days.
Now, I would say, it will be definitely
two to three weeks, maybe 30 days.
And as much as pot 40 to 45 days to 60
days, if we ran into big problems.
But I would say, I would say probably
certainly within 60 days and very likely in 30.
Yeah, I was going to say, I
think we even had a few ideas
that we just realized that
would be better to include in it.
So we're adding those as well.
So it's making what will be the launch.
Good point, Bob.
We got some suggestions at the gala and it
was most of the suggestions we got,
we already planned for,
but we realized that we
had to bump them up and
we had to get it on now.
So, yeah, so we're moving that,
we're moving.
And there were still some
things that we had to,
we had to tighten up
that were needed to do it.
We already knew, and there was a couple of
things that we realized that after hearing
everybody, we need to, we need to
prioritize and we need to get them in.
So we're working on that as fast as we
can, but you'll have it really soon.
All right.
Perfect.
Yeah.
All right.
I got to run.
You guys continue.
All right.
Okay.
You guys later on.
And you want me to throw up a chart here,
Bob?
Yeah.
I was going to say, let me see if there's,
yeah, you might as well be ready for that.
Um, just another reminder as well,
for everybody to know the symbol Dropbox
is the way that you can also drop these,
uh, ticker symbols into the Dropbox.
They do get seen and reviewed, uh,
by Mark, uh, not necessarily every day.
You're not going to get
a response or reply back
to him about it, but they
do get reviewed and seen.
So if it is, if it is something to,
uh, right, if it is something to,
um, be added to the focus list,
that's how you'll know that it is
something where, uh, Mark agreed with you
and saw it.
Uh, plus also just a reminder,
we will have the opportunity for another
question and answer session
on Thursday, back to normal
this week with Mark Ritchie
and Brandon Hedgepeth.
So you do have that, uh, coming up in a
couple of days for any questions that
we're not going to be able to get through
to today.
Uh, and a question being asked by Chin on
MRVL, take a look at MRVL.
Yeah.
Uh, possibility I'm out Thursday,
but Brandon will definitely be in.
So, um, just following up there real
quick.
Okay.
Yeah.
MRVL is one I've got on like a secondary
watch list.
Look, you could, you've tried it right
here.
You know, this is again, one of these not
powerful enough to be a power play.
You had the, this sort of post earnings
drift bottle.
It's trying to tighten up.
So, you know, if there
was a spot to try it, it would
have been sort of right
here near the danger point.
But right now, you know, where's the
pivot?
You're just, the stock has no pivot here.
So it pulled, you know, pull back into
here.
It'd be very normal.
And I'd want to see this build out.
We get some type of, you know,
pull back by or something like this.
Uh, that's what I'd be looking for or,
or then some type of handle.
All right.
Um, something Chen, you want to definitely
learn about is making sure the stock has a
pivot from which we're looking to buy the
breakout most often.
That is our entry technique.
So, um, keep that in mind.
I know you mentioned you're a new
subscriber.
Well, lead is asking thoughts on RJTI.
Uh, yeah, absolutely not.
I mean, listen, this is only a 99 RS.
I'm curious what it is
even on our RPR, because
we're talking about a
stock now that's broken.
You know, what is this 80 plus percent?
This is an absolute no-fly zone.
You're running into massive overhead.
When you get a gap like this, do you know
how many trapped longs are up here?
Um, assuming this is a real gap,
Bob, you know, I'm, I'm assuming this is,
I would absolutely stay
away from this, uh, not even
going to, not on my radar
and won't be anytime soon.
So assuming you're thinking this is a
power play, which it was, uh, when it was
on January 6th there at the high,
but one of the rules of a power play is a,
is a, uh, stock keeping
within 20% of that high,
this has gone down
about 70% from that high.
So this immediately is, uh, eliminated
from any consideration.
Well, yeah.
And just, just to clarify to what Bob was,
what Bob was referring to is this had the
power, um, here, but you know,
this was not even set up.
This was something you put on another list
to see if it's really a power play.
There was no power play pivot here,
which I know Bob knows, but you know,
now it's completely off the radar.
Yeah.
It was a candidate that we actually
referred to as a poll.
So that's a poll stock that would have
been a candidate to consider if it did
develop into a purchase, but once it,
uh, came in, you know, in excess of the
20, even 25% max, which
is clearly did on January
8th, that no longer was
now a qualified candidate.
Uh, Brandon asking about PLNT.
If this is a, uh, cap pattern that it's
trying to emerge from.
No, uh, sorry.
I'm just taking a look at this one and
obviously it's on focus because we're
looking, if this could stay inside here to
sort of that viable first, like pullback,
do we get some type of orderly pullback
back to, back to the breakout here?
It's the name that held up really well.
Well, the market was, you know,
sort of correcting.
You had short base held up really cap is
12 to 18 days, you know, above the base.
So could this develop into a cap?
Yeah, but it's, it's too short for that
right now.
Yeah.
Doesn't mean though, just because it's not
technically a cap.
I mean, if this stays
inside and even stays tight,
you can, you could buy
it as it reemerges here.
And we're just always measuring, you
know, I'm just measuring even right here.
You know, this is 3%.
So sometimes, and just like I'd,
I'd said earlier, when somebody was asking
about the names on focus list,
well, maybe you're watching this name.
It didn't quite tighten up.
It broke out.
Now it pulls back orderly.
Can you get a low risk entry?
We're just always looking
for, you know, low risk entries
up that right-hand side
where we can get on board.
Um, I think this is a good question.
Just, uh, John's asking about,
you have a holiday weekend, of course,
the inauguration of president Trump,
of course, a lot of stocks correlated to,
you know, his policies, new
administration.
He said this morning, he had 47 alerts
going off.
Many, uh, with prices moving through
multiple trigger points.
It was a bit overwhelming,
uh, unable to keep,
uh, to get on board a
couple of the names.
How do you manage situations like this
where you have so many alerts going off
first thing in the morning and,
and on, on days like Bob just described,
or maybe big gap up or gap down in the
market.
I don't know if I've had
47 go off, but you know,
you'll have a cluster of
alerts that that's normal.
So, but the key is, you know, this is
where you do your work ahead of time.
You, you may have the alerts going off,
but you still want to be just shrinking,
you know, the size of your list down to
something that's manageable.
So even when our focus list has got 20 or
30 names, you may have alerts on a lot of
them and that's fine,
but you're not going to
buy all those and you
don't want to buy all them.
So that's where, look, I'm, you get those
alerts that pop up.
You just, you quickly silence them,
but focus on the one or two names or,
you know, maybe three or four that you're
really focused on in any one day.
He highlighted a few.
Well, that's where you'd sort of see,
look, are they viable?
When we get a market though, that's
gapping.
Generally, I try not to do a lot and,
and then at least initially, and you wait
to see, you know, do we get some type of
orderly spot to get on board, but look,
if you're going to set a
lot of alerts, you're going to
have times where a lot of
them go off, that's normal.
But the more, more you do your work ahead
of time, it just helps you filter through
to, to figure out where, where the names
are you really want to get involved with.
All right.
A lot more thank yous.
What do you think about Dash?
D-A-D-A-S-H.
Was it Biob on Friday?
Yeah, this is one, you know, I have on a
secondary watch list as well.
I don't love, you know, this break here
and how it's sort of, you know,
hovering around the 50, but you really
could have, you could have cheated on it a
little bit Friday or even
today as it's coming through,
you know, do you have
a little tightening here?
Yeah, you do.
I'm just measuring 75.
This, even all the way down here is about,
you know, 7%.
If you really want to own the name, it's
not the best looking one in my opinion.
So it probably would have
gone with it, maybe a little
bit of a smaller position,
but again, acceptable.
Yeah.
Perfect.
No.
So that's sort of my answer.
Okay.
I bought iBroker on the 16th.
Khalid's asking your opinion.
I-B-K-R.
Yeah.
Another one I had, you know,
I think I was thinking about
even sending this to Mark
for potential consideration.
He bought it where?
16th.
Okay.
So maybe you're sort of waiting for a day
after it came up and you're playing it
kind of sort of a pullback buy of sorts
once it stabilizes and just measuring,
you know, that's pretty tight.
So I don't, I answered this question a
number of times over the weekend of people
asking me and I was like, listen,
if you're playing a pivot, I wouldn't play
as a general rule, the tighter,
the more likely you are to get sort of
anyone's blessing on it to potentially
play it.
And this is a good example though,
where you're anticipating, okay,
this stock is, we may get another tightening
here, but you want to start a position.
And that's exactly how I would have
handled it.
If you're going to play this name,
you buy a portion of your position and
then see, you know, you're in it if it
just goes.
And then if it tightens up, which is what
I'd like to see or maybe expect,
you add to the name.
Also, you know, factor that in as well.
I don't think it's the worst buy.
Good.
Interesting that we're seeing, or I'm seeing
a lot of the same ticker symbols today.
A lot of them.
Which tells me, you know,
again, there wasn't a ton that
was, there wasn't a ton that
was imminently buyable today.
And that's fine.
And we know, we know we're
in a more selective market, even
in Q and A's where to Bob's
point, you get 20 questions.
I see tons of SFMs, a lot of CINs,
you know, those type of things.
Yeah.
I'm going to see how that just is a blast
from the past.
Julia is saying she bought EAT this
morning.
Can I have your view on Brinker?
No.
I mean, this is a name that's just gone a
long way.
And again, where's the pivot?
It's just sort of wedging up here.
So, back to the comment
about, remember, we want
abnormal price action to
knock us out versus normal.
This could act very normal and pull back
even to undercut here.
It really needs to rebase.
We were buying this name over here.
That was your proper buy point.
And your follow-up spot or add point was
right there.
And see how tight these are?
And this is a really good example.
Let me go to the weekly, to the question
on symmetry.
See how symmetrical this base is?
You really can't see it as well here.
It's zoomed in as much on this charting
software.
But this was a really nice symmetrical
base.
You went through that proper time.
Had the nice contraction here.
And then another one here.
And even another one here.
And each time.
See that volume here.
Coming down as it pulls back.
Just textbook.
But now, it's just extended.
This is where... If
you're still in the name...
And I know we had some folks that are
still in it.
They're using a 50-day break, even or
better.
Or you should be at this point.
I would close below the 50.
You're still now riding a nice trend.
All right.
Okay.
I'd like to know your sentiment towards
commodities.
Notably gold.
And what about Bitcoin?
Any rule of thumb that Mark goes by on
these instruments?
My sentiment?
I don't even know necessarily what that
means.
Look.
When anything sets up properly.
Or gives you a low-risk entry.
You have my blessing to potentially trade
it.
Now, gold does not have that really right
now.
I actually took a small position in this.
I think it was right here.
Kind of coming off.
And hoping this was going to tighten up.
Either into this level.
I have found, personally, if you're going
to trade commodities, at least for me,
commodity-related stocks, or the
commodities themselves.
They have inverse cycles.
Most of you probably don't fully
appreciate what that means.
But that generally means that when the
earnings and the sales and all those
things are on the table is often when the
moves are over.
So I've also found that
when they're breaking
out to new highs,
they're just a little noisier.
Versus where... That's
where I prefer the low cheat.
Or something in the mid to lower third of
the base.
The other thing with the general
commodities I've always found is if I'm
going to play them or the stocks, I'd
like to see the entire group setting up.
You can go back and look at how we played
XLE.
I want to say it was
that early 22, Bob, where
there was a lot of
oil names acting well.
We played that once or twice that year.
So you sort of see that thematic move.
Same thing with crypto.
Just wait for them to set up.
And that's precisely how
I've taken the same thing
I've learned here and just
applied it in those areas.
Yeah, the nice thing, I think,
which is to say you can apply Mark's
principles of his submethodology to any
security would be accurate.
And crypto, I think, is probably one of
the better opportunities in this day and
age because you just have a very low
amount of coverage there.
So you just don't have anything that's
going to help get those things to be truly
efficient other than
just true supply demand,
greed, fear, market
forces on those names.
And that, of course, is
where our ability to read that
technical action is incredibly
our advantage, our edge.
And that is giving us that on a commodity
like gold where there's just gold or
silver, perhaps, or some other very few
precious metals.
And yet there's, you know, a million traders
trading those very few select things.
Those are very... doesn't
mean they're not volatile, but
they're very efficient priced
in real time throughout.
And currencies have the same, you know,
denotions.
There's only so many currencies,
so many pairs you can trade.
And there's a million, you know,
forex traders as well.
So that's not playing in
the inefficiency edge that
we're trying to really identify
and take advantage of.
Let's just see.
I think we're pretty much at that time.
Anyway, with that said, we will have the
replay up and available here momentarily.
Thank you, Mark, for your time.
Glad, again, everybody really enjoyed the
event.
I know we did.
For those that did come to
the gala and the birthday bash,
it was a phenomenal time to
be able to see, meet people.
We had people from nearly 50 countries
around the world all coming to the event.
So just an opportunity from a global
perspective to just see how all of us
there are there for one primary focus,
how to become, you know, we're all
passionate about the markets and how to
become the best traders that we can become.
And that's a lot of what drives Mark to
not only create the company, men of any
private access, but also to keep coming
every day and doing it.
It's a ton of fun for us,
and the gala really allowed
us to see you enjoying
it as much as we do, too.
So with that said, Mark?
Yep, same.
I share those sentiments as well,
guys.
And again, thanks for all the handshakes
and hugs and everything.
It was overwhelming on a much lesser scale
than Mark's, but a really great time.
Yeah.
So I'll wrap it up here for today.
We'll let you know.
Post it on the platform.
Stay tuned to the live
stream for real-time alerts
throughout the week and
about the Thursday Q&A session.
And we'll be back at it soon.
All right.
Take care, guys.