Hello, everyone.
Welcome to this week's Minervini on the
Market Weekly Report, January 12, 2025.
We're coming up on the 2025 Gala in Myrtle
Beach.
We're looking forward to seeing all of you
there, all of you that are attending.
Of course, we're going to have an
incredible day of education, fun,
and a special guest.
And we're also releasing or debuting the
Minervini Markets 360 platform.
We're very excited about that.
We're going to demonstrate that.
Lots of special guests, including Stan
Weinstein.
My good friend, Dr. Eric Wish,
will be there presenting.
Who else do we have?
We have a panel of nine U.S.
investing champion winners and top
finishers, those that were up over 100%,
a nice roundtable discussion, our staff,
of course.
So it's going to be a great time,
and we're looking forward to it.
Of course, the next day or the next
evening is my birthday bash.
That's turning out to be something that we
know is going to be incredible.
I think there's about 1,100
people now coming to
that, so it's going to be
a heck of a birthday party.
So I'm looking forward to that,
and we'll see you all there, too.
So let's start off by taking a look at key
components of market health.
Not that pretty right now.
Market is definitely under pressure.
Market index is negative, up, down,
volume, neutral.
New highs, new lows, and individual stock
participation, both negative.
And, of course, we've had
the STEM model negative for
some time now, going all
the way back to November 4th.
Keep in mind, if you're new, the STEM
model is purely stock-based.
We don't put any or take into account
anything of the general market.
Excuse me.
On the general market, on the longer term,
our SPY models follow the long-term trend,
and they're designed to keep you in gear
with that long-term trend.
And they're actually still bullish and
holding on to buy signals.
Now, of course, remember, these are very
long-term oriented, so it's going to take
some decline to put them onto a sell
signal.
And the same thing, coming off of a low,
you'll need some rally.
So you'll never pick the low or get the
high, as sometimes we get very close to
when I short the S&P, like I just did
recently.
That's not going to happen with this type
of model.
But this will keep you in gear,
and there's very few switch signals.
Also, it is an allocator, so there is some
laddering of allocation.
So you can use it either directly,
or I should say, specifically going from
0% to 100% on buy and sell signals, or you
can ladder with it and move the exposure.
Either work quite well, you know, based
on the past performance of this indicator.
Again, this is looking at the individual
components.
I think, as I said last week, that we are
at risk of maybe raising 25% or 50% cash.
If the market falls much from here,
or continues to fall from here,
I think, and again, I'm just sort of
forecasting here, the mechanics of the
models are going to have to switch to get
these signals.
But it looks like we'll
probably raise 25% or
even 50% cash if we go
have another leg down.
Taking a look, making sort of heads or
tails, you know, the whys of the market,
hopes that the Federal
Reserve would keep their interest
rates or keep cutting interest
rates are dwindling now.
And that's definitely putting pressure on
stocks.
December job growth was strong,
but good productivity is helping.
And unit labor costs, things like that,
productivity, unit labor costs correlates
to 90% with the economy's rate of
inflation.
So that's something that, of course,
we'd like to see and check.
The economy's doing okay.
And that's really key
with that Goldilocks
scenario, which I'll talk
about in just a second.
There's no signs of a recession, but
there are areas of concern for inflation.
The Trump tax cuts, tariffs, deportations,
things that Trump is talking about that a
lot of analysts have speculated that it
will be inflationary.
The Fed's been put on pause and that
raises concern for a recession.
So we're kind of stuck in the middle.
To me, it's a balancing act that turns out
to be still pretty good for the long-term,
short-term under pressure.
But I think it will create
a buying opportunity
because we're still in
that Goldilocks economy.
We have not really moved
out of that range as far as
real GDP or some of the
other metrics that I look at.
Interest rates, when you look at the one
year, the one year has been pretty stable.
And I think that's good
for something, for a catalyst
that would cause a major
problem in the market.
But the 10-year has backed up here.
It's going from 360 all up to 477 and all
the way up to those highs of almost 502.
And that's put pressure on the market.
And that's come at a time where you have
sentiment.
It was very bullish.
It's come off now, but not still to levels
that I would consider to be bullish.
I still think we're at levels that are
complacent, if you will.
If you take a look, we're looking at just
the bull side of it.
If you divide it by the bulls and the
bears and get the total picture versus all
the advisors in the Investor's Intelligence
Survey, we're still in nosebleed areas.
So we need to come down with sentiment
there.
And the real...
We could make or try to make heads or
tails of the whys of the market,
but the what's are what are very important
or what most important.
And looking at that, we can see that we
have a tape, if you will.
Of course, saying tape dates me.
I'm sure Stan Weinstein used to be called
the professional tape reader.
The tape is the tale of the market here.
Looking at the price and volume,
we're still under distribution here.
So we have to be very careful.
And we just recently had
an accumulation day or a
follow-through day attempt on
this gap right here on the NASDAQ.
And once you get some accumulation, you get
a follow-through day coming off the lows.
Now, this wasn't even an official
follow-through day, even if it held,
it came on just a couple days after it
made that low.
So it wouldn't even be an official
follow-through day.
You'd have to have a few days,
another day or two go by before we would
consider that as an official
follow-through day.
It has to be on the fourth day or later.
But that accumulation met immediate
distribution.
And that's what we look for after you have
any accumulation or a follow-through day.
Can the accumulation hold
without getting distribution,
particularly massive distribution
or immediate distribution?
So this was pretty big distribution right
off the hop the very next day.
And that just negates any type of
accumulation.
So we would still consider this a
distribution-dominant tape.
This has been building.
We had some churning days and then a big
decline here.
And now you can see we're continuing that
distribution.
If you look at the NYSE,
two indexes that I follow for
this particular analysis are
the NASDAQ and the NYSE.
Similar where you had distribution off the
highs.
And now you're almost all the way down to
the 200-day moving average.
You've been living below the 50.
That same rally attempt here just failed.
It was actually... This would be
looked at as a distribution day.
Even though we're up a little bit,
it came well off the highs.
Looking at the S&P 500, of course,
this is the index that I shorted on 12.9.
It was just one day off the high.
And again, a great entry for the short.
And right now, we're in an excellent
position.
I mean, if you want to
move your stop to break
even and completely
de-risk it, that's up to you.
But the stop is less than a percent above
the short price.
So there's really very little risk here.
Right now, of course, with a 1% or less
stop being up 4% or so, certainly,
you know, that's a 4R.
So it's already a really good winning
trade based on risk versus reward.
Dow, of course, has come off more.
The more narrower index would have been
the one that's short.
That's the only mistake
I made is I went into
the wrong index as far
as looking in hindsight.
But also, the Dow, you can see,
is closing in on that 200-day.
And I wouldn't be
surprised if we come down
to that 200-day on the
Dow and maybe the NYSE.
And some of that pressure
that I'm seeing is coming
underneath the surface in
the IBD Mutual Fund Index.
So this is looking at some
of the better funds and
they're already under the
200-day moving average.
And that was a pretty big weekly decline
that closed right on the lows.
And you can see there's really no bounce.
You know, very dead cat bounce.
Almost no bounce at all.
So really showing signs
that we've got, we're
in a market that we
would call an egg here.
There's no tennis ball action.
Now, looking at the IBD 50, it looks a
little bit better.
And I think there's like two scenarios
that we can be considering here.
One is where...
And okay, where did I put that?
Here it is.
One is where we pull back a bit more
maybe, but we maintain this uptrend and we
spend some time maybe
basing and then you'll see
more stocks will start
to show up setting up.
And maybe it's not such a large decline
and it holds up relative to the market.
Or maybe the market pulls back a bit more
and we see a bit more pressure and you've
got to take out that low
and temporarily it looks like
that longer-term trend might
be turning to a downtrend.
And then we see some type of low when we
get some real bearishness there.
So again, one is a shorter-term scenario.
One would take a little bit longer
probably to correct itself.
But I think both scenarios
are a correction within
an ongoing bull market
here and that we're still...
We've still got to give the market the
benefit of the doubt even though there's
some pretty negative things right now that
we see.
However, we have pulled back some so far
and the longer-term trend is still up and
the underlying economic conditions are
still not unfavorable by any great amounts.
The real problem is the volatility.
And again, that's
what we have to watch
carefully in the individual
stocks in particular.
We can look at the VIX and see that we've
gotten an increase in volatility there.
And that right in itself is an environment
that we want to be cautious with.
But when it's translating into volatility
in the individual names and you're not
able to get clean breakouts and you're
getting volatility around those pivots or
just where we are now where we don't
really have a whole lot of stock ideas
that are setting up in a crisp fashion
that we have really good clear buyable
low-risk buy points,
then that's a market that
we need to wait until
the volatility calms down.
Until volatility calms down, particularly
on the individual stock level,
you've got to play it definitely small
ball if not just stay in cash.
Also, we talked about sentiment.
I like to look at what people say, but I
also like to look at what people are doing.
And when the two agree, that's when you get
the best sentiment signals, if you will.
So when you get a lot of bearish sentiment
and you got a lot of put buying,
people are saying bearish things and
they're doing bearish things, that's where
you get the best signals from the
sentiment.
And we have not gotten to those points on
either.
So we're sort of now getting into that
middle road where, yeah, you could bottom
here, but I think we need to get the
complaints since he's still rung out of
the market and there's still some,
at the very least, some basing or some
backing and filling sideways action to
come.
And most likely, we're going to see more
downside in the market.
It's anybody's guess how much,
of course.
But, you know, again, we
treat every 5% pullback as a
potential 20% and every 20%
as a potential major bear market.
In summary, market is under pressure
without a doubt.
We had a failed follow-through.
Again, it wasn't an official
follow-through even if it held and we got
no distribution, we would still be looking
to see an additional follow-through day.
The tape, because of that, the tape is
still distribution dominant.
Volatility, as I said, is the problem
here.
And the S&P 500 model is, I think,
at risk here of raising some cash.
So, as I pointed out earlier, I didn't
think it was a bad idea maybe to raise
some cash around the highs several weeks
back when I was starting to get bearish,
especially when I start talking about
shorting the market, right?
You know, we short the market.
That's usually a good time to take some
chips off the table.
It means that, you know, the landscape is
definitely getting risky.
Sentiment, want to see that also.
Volatility and sentiment should both start
to spike together.
Volatility, if it goes up from
here, want to see bearish
sentiment go up with it,
that could help make a low.
And bottom line is, we got to look for
setups.
And when the setups
are there, I mean, there's
a few stocks that are
setting up right now.
A couple have broken out and tried to make
some moves here.
NVIDIA is a perfect example, though.
If you remember last week, we were talking
about NVIDIA.
I can't remember if it was here,
if it was in the Q&A.
But I said, you know, this isn't a
successful trade yet.
It could still fail, even though
just because we're up, I
don't even know we're up
six, seven percent or whatever.
You know, it's a
successful short-term trade,
but still, it only broke
out for a day or two.
And sure enough, that
came in really hard with a big,
you know, big distribution
there with the market.
And so I think, you know, we still have a
market that we've got to be careful.
It's very, very selective.
So if you're going to trade, you're going
to trade these few stocks here and there
that set up, you know, do it with tighter
stops, maybe smaller position sizing,
or if you're having big position sizing,
going with very limited risk as far as the
stops are concerned, and just make an
adjustment, make an adjustment for the
period that right now
the weight of evidence is,
you know, is leaning
more to the bearish side.
All right.
So we'll see you tomorrow at 1130 a.m.
for live Q&A with myself,
Bob Weissman, moderating,
and Mark Ritchie
answering questions with me.
And we'll see you then.
Have a good rest of the day.
And today is my wedding anniversary.
So I'm going to go out with my wife to
dinner tonight.
So I'll talk to you guys tomorrow.
Bye-bye.